["Daydreamer" by Aurora playing]
Good morning. And welcome to WWDC.
WWDC is an incredibly important event
to Apple, our developers and our users.
It's here that we bring
some of our biggest innovations to life.
And we have not stopped innovating,
doing the work that will enrich
people's lives for years to come.
Because we're all looking forward
to a more hopeful tomorrow.
That's why we believe it's so important
to have WWDC this year.
And while it cannot possibly
feel the same in here without you,
I can assure you
that we have a great show ahead of us.
This year we're delivering the conference
in a whole new way
to all of you around the world,
directly to your home.
And we want to welcome you
to our home here at Apple Park.
I'd like to first talk to you
about two big things
that are happening in the world right now.
To start, I want to address the topic
of racism, inequality and injustice
and to recognize the pain being felt
throughout our nation,
especially in
our Black and Brown communities,
after the senseless killing
of George Floyd.
And while the events of this past month
are sadly not new,
they have caused us to face
long-standing institutional inequalities
and social injustices.
This country was founded on the principles
of freedom and equality for all.
For too many people and for too long,
we haven't lived up to those ideals.
We're inspired and moved
by the passionate people around our nation
and around the world
who have stood up to demand change.
We must all aim far higher to build
a future that lives up to our ideals.
This means taking action.
Two weeks ago, we announced Apple's
Racial Equity and Justice Initiative
with a commitment
of one hundred million dollars.
Starting in the United States,
and expanding over time,
this initiative will challenge
systemic barriers
that limit opportunity
for communities of color
in the critical areas of education,
economic equality and criminal justice.
We also announced something important
for this community,
the new Developer Entrepreneur Camp
for Black developers.
We want to do everything we can to foster
the brightest lights and best ideas.
At Apple, our mission has always been
to make the world a better place,
and we're committed
to being a force for change.
Right now our world is
also battling a virus
that is affecting
the daily lives of billions of people.
We want to thank the dedicated people
everywhere,
especially our health-care workers,
who have made tremendous sacrifices
to take care of those in need.
We've also seen the profound impact
our products have had.
People are relying on them more than ever
to remain connected to family and friends,
to do their work,
to express their creativity,
to be entertained
as well as to entertain others.
Today the world is counting on all of us,
and on the products and experiences
that we create, to move forward.
Because throughout history,
great challenges have been met with great
creativity and important breakthroughs.
That's why we're so excited
about this year's conference.
This is going to be truly a unique week,
delivered unlike any
that we've done before.
There will be more than a hundred
engineering-led video sessions,
one-on-one consultations
with Apple engineers,
developer forums and so much more,
delivered to you from different locations
right here at Apple Park.
And this year,
the conference will be available
to our entire community
of 23 million developers,
as well as anyone who is interested,
for free.
Presenting the conference in this way
allows us to be more inclusive than ever.
Perhaps this will inspire
the next generation of developers.
So even though
we can't be together in person,
in some ways we're going to be
more together than ever.
Today we're going to push
each of our platforms forward
in some exciting and breakthrough ways.
With that, let's get started
by sending it over to Craig.
Good morning. Great to have you here.
As you can see, we've got a lot to cover,
so let's get started with iOS.
Together with iPhone,
iOS is central to how we navigate
our lives and stay connected.
And now we're making it
even more powerful and easier to use.
Our new release is iOS 14.
This year we've spent time rethinking
some of the most iconic elements
of the experience on iPhone.
Now it all started here,
with a carefully considered Home Screen
that has truly stood the test of time.
Of course, over the years, we've kept
the fundamentals largely the same
but carefully added features
like folders for organizing your apps,
widgets for quick information
and personalized experiences
powered by on-device intelligence
that serve up just the right thing
at just the right moment.
It's hard to imagine iPhone
without these features now.
Well, that brings us to this year.
We're doing more on our iPhones today
than ever before,
so we've rethought some of
the core elements of iOS to reflect this.
Let me give you a quick peek.
["Like This Like That" by
BEGINNERS &amp; Night Panda playing]
This is gonna be amazing.
Let's dig in,
starting with the Home Screen.
Today's Home Screen works great,
but as we get more and more apps,
we can end up with this:
lots and lots of pages.
And we tend to forget
what's beyond the first couple.
Wouldn't it be great
if there were a way to organize
all of those apps without doing a thing?
Well, this year we're doing just that
with something called the App Library.
It's a new space
at the end of your Home Screen pages
that automatically organizes all your apps
in one simple and easy-to-navigate view.
Let me show you.
Here's my Home Screen.
Now, like you, I have muscle memory built
for the first page or two,
but when it comes to all of these pages,
well, honestly, I've lost track
of where a lot of things are.
And that's where the App Library comes in.
You can see that all of my apps
are automatically organized here.
In fact, now with the App Library,
I actually don't need all those pages
for all my apps.
So we created an easy way
to hide app pages.
I just go into jiggle mode,
tap the dots at the bottom,
and check this out,
I get a zoomed-out view
of all my app pages.
I can simply tap
to hide the pages I no longer need.
Just like that.
And now with those pages hidden,
App Library is always
just a swipe or two away.
So here in App Library, getting to the app
I'm looking for is really easy.
Up at the top I have the Search field,
and I get all my apps
organized from A to Z.
Now over here on the upper left
I have Suggestions.
It uses on-device intelligence
to show me the apps
that I'm likely to need next.
And on the right is Recently Added,
giving me access to the apps that I've
recently downloaded from the App Store.
And below are
intelligently curated categories.
So I can tap into a category
like Apple Arcade
and see all of my apps in that category.
Now let's go back.
You may notice
that in each of these categories
the apps I use most are right here
at the top level,
so I can launch one of these directly
with just a tap.
So that's App Library.
We think this is gonna make it
easier than ever to get to your apps.
Next, let's turn to Widgets.
Today, widgets help you get information
at a glance.
But a lot has changed
since we first introduced these.
Now we have Apple Watch, where we're able
to surface so much information
on a small screen
that you wear on your wrist.
Well, this year,
we're taking all that we've learned
to create a completely reimagined
experience for widgets.
To start,
they're more beautiful and data rich.
And we're introducing different sizes,
so you can choose one
that best fits your needs.
Let's take a look at them in iOS 14.
So let's swipe over to Today View
and take a look at our new widgets.
They're just beautiful.
And the new designs are
more data rich than ever.
And you can see
they now come in a variety of sizes.
So you can pick just the right level
of information for each one.
Now we like these new widgets so much,
we wanted to make them
even more accessible.
So check this out.
I'm just gonna tap and hold
on the Weather widget,
and I can drag it out of Today View
and onto my Home Screen.
And watch, as I move it around,
the apps just dance out of the way
to make space for my new widget.
Let's add a second one.
Just gonna tap the plus
here in the upper left
and grab on to Podcasts.
I can drop it just like that.
Now I'm gonna swipe over to page 2 here
and bring back up the Widget Gallery.
The gallery is a great place
to explore widgets.
Now when I tap on one,
I can actually page through
all of the different sizes available.
Just like this.
But, you know, right now what I want to do
is grab this widget up top.
It's a really special one.
It's called the Smart Stack.
Just gonna tap it and drop it here.
With the Smart Stack,
I can easily swipe through widgets
to pick just the one I want
for the moment.
But what's really cool
is that the Smart Stack can
actually do this for me automatically.
So in the morning,
I can get my news briefing.
Throughout the day,
find out when I have a meeting coming up.
And in the evening, I might get
a summary of my activity for the day.
So that's widgets on the Home Screen.
We're excited to see how everyone
will customize them in their own way.
Next, we're also bringing
Picture in Picture to iPhone.
So you can access apps on your iPhone
while watching video
or talking on a FaceTime call.
Let me show you.
So here on my Home Screen,
the Smart Stack
is showing me the TV widget.
So I can just tap to start playing a show.
Now check this out.
When I swipe to go Home,
the video automatically goes
into Picture in Picture
right over the Home Screen.
And when I launch another app, like Notes,
I can keep watching.
Now I can drag the picture
to another part of the screen.
If I want to make it bigger,
I can even pinch to zoom.
And as I move between applications
it stays with me.
And what's cool is
I can also swipe it to the side,
and the audio keeps playing
when it's off-screen.
Now here on the Home Screen
I can bring it back out if I want.
And I have controls
to get back to full-screen playback,
or I can just tap the "X" to close it.
And that's Picture in Picture video.
It's a great way
to continue enjoying your video
while tapping into everything else
your iPhone can do for you.
And that's a quick look at the updates
to the core elements of iOS.
We think these new features are gonna
make iOS even more helpful in the moment.
Another iconic experience
that's getting a major update is Siri.
As much as Siri has advanced
over the years,
the visual interface for interacting
with it has remained largely unchanged.
When you use Siri, your iPhone
switches to this full-screen UI,
obscuring your current context.
So this year, we've completely redesigned
the Siri experience
with a new compact design.
It makes tasks like launching apps
incredibly seamless.
For example, if you say, "Open Safari,"
Siri pops up at the bottom of the screen
and instantly launches the app.
Or if you ask for information,
like the weather,
results appear at the top of the screen
just like a notification.
Now this is especially great
when there's information
you want to reference on-screen.
For example, you could ask Siri
to add to your grocery list.
So that's the new Siri design in iOS 14.
But the UI is only part of the story.
To tell you more about
how we're making Siri smarter than ever,
I'll hand it off to Yael Garten.
Thanks, Craig.
Siri's getting smarter
and even more helpful every day,
and I'm really excited to share
the latest updates with you.
Siri helps you in a ton of little ways
every day:
playing the morning news,
ordering a coffee, getting directions,
setting the alarm before going to bed
and so much more.
In fact, Siri's helping so many of you
with a staggering 25 billion requests
each month.
And Siri's getting more helpful every day.
Siri's always been great
for getting information
and now has over 20 times more facts
than just three years ago.
For more complex questions
like "How do hybrid cars work?"
or "What causes seasons?",
we recently introduced answers
from websites across the Internet,
enabling Siri to help you
find even more answers.
Another way Siri helps is
with communication, like sending messages.
This year, you can now ask Siri
to send an audio message,
and Siri will start recording.
This is great when you really want to have
the emotion of your voice come through.
Another popular way to send messages
with your voice is using dictation.
Keyboard Dictation uses
the same speech recognition as Siri.
And leveraging
the power of the Neural Engine,
we are now able
to run dictation on-device.
This provides great accuracy and privacy.
When communicating with someone in another
language, Siri can help with translations.
This year we're expanding
to support many new language pairs.
This is hugely popular,
but we know our users want
more than just translating phrases.
They want to have entire conversations.
And we believe conversations
between languages
should feel natural and easy
and have the ability to stay private.
That's why we're introducing
a new app called Translate.
It is designed to be the best
and easiest-to-use app for conversations.
And it can work completely off-line,
keeping your conversations private.
Using advanced on-device machine learning
and the powerful Neural Engine,
you can translate your text and voice
between any combination
of these 11 languages.
So I could have a conversation
with someone in Mandarin,
and they could have a conversation
with someone in Russian.
Just tap on the microphone and say,
"What are your store hours?"
[Siri reads Spanish translation]
[Yael] You get back
the text and audio right away.
And just turn the phone to landscape
to open conversation mode.
We've designed a side-by-side view
that's easy for two people to know
which side to follow in the conversation.
This mode is incredibly intuitive,
with just a single microphone button
because the app intelligently detects
the language spoken
and shows translation
on the correct side of the screen.
Translate will make communicating
between languages easier than ever before,
connecting people in new ways.
And we can't wait for you to try it.
Thanks, Yael.
Next up, Messages.
Messages is how many of us communicate
with people most important to us.
And now we're using it more than ever.
Compared to just a year ago,
we have a record number of users
sending a record number of messages.
And we've seen people use Messages
more and more
to keep in touch
with their closest groups.
This year, we're introducing
a new way to stay connected
with your most important conversations,
giving you new ways
to express your identity with Memoji
and making big changes
to how we communicate in groups.
To tell you more, here's Stacey Lysik.
Thanks, Craig.
First, let's get started
with Conversations.
From the beginning, Messages was designed
to make it really easy
to get to your newest messages.
But with so many active conversations,
sometimes it can be tough to get to
the ones that are most important to you.
So we are introducing a new way
to let you stay connected
to your most important conversations:
by letting you pin them
at the top of your list
so you can always get to them.
And you can see messages as they come in
with a beautiful animation on the pin.
Next, let's talk about expressing yourself
with Memoji.
There are over one trillion ways
to customize your identity with Memoji.
In iOS 14, we're adding even more ways
to create your look
with over 20 new hair and headwear styles
to let you reflect your hobby, profession
and personality.
We've also added something that's
even more relevant today: face coverings.
And we're adding more age options too.
My favorite way of using Memoji
is with Memoji stickers.
And now we have
three brand-new Memoji stickers
that let you send a hug, a fist bump
or even a blush to your friends.
Last, let's chat about groups.
When you're talking to a group,
sometimes there's so much going on,
it can be hard to keep track
of the conversation.
So this year, we're gonna help you
bring order to the chaos.
First we're adding inline replies
that let you reply
directly to a specific message.
You can view replies
in the full conversation
or you can view them as their own thread
so you can focus in on the specific topic.
To make it even more clear
who a message was meant for,
we're introducing mentions.
With mentions,
you can just type someone's name
to direct a message to them.
And now you have the ability
to only be notified
when you're mentioned
in the group conversation.
And check out
the top of this conversation.
We have an all-new design
for how groups appear.
It lets you see
all the members of your group,
where the most recently active people
are shown largest.
And, for the first time ever,
you can create a unique visual identity
for your group
by setting a group photo
or customizing your group's look
with an emoji.
Inside the conversation
you see group members' photos
around the image.
Of course it looks great as a pin.
You know who's most recently commented
in the group
because their photo will appear
around the outside of the pin.
And that's what's coming to Messages
in iOS 14:
all-new pinned conversations,
fun updates to Memoji
and powerful improvements to groups.
Thanks, Stacey.
Next, let's take a look at features
that help us while we're out and about.
Now we know that life looks very different
for many of us right now,
but it won't always be this way.
And as things start to open up,
we have a new set of features
that will help us explore the world again,
starting with Maps.
Apple Maps is the best way to navigate
and explore the world,
all while protecting your privacy.
Over the past several years,
we've added many great features,
and of course we've been
rebuilding our map from the ground up.
Our new map finished rolling out
across the US earlier this year
and brought with it better navigation
and far richer detail
for roads, pedestrian paths,
landcover and more.
The new map also offers
more accurate information for places
and allows us to build incredible features
like Look Around.
Maps has come a long way,
and people have noticed.
Just look at this quote from Fast Company.
"Apple Maps has improved
by leaps and bounds
and is a formidable rival to Google Maps.
It's also arguably got the better UI,
and by far-- by far--
the better privacy policy."
We're excited to announce
we're bringing our new map
to more countries later this year,
including the UK, Ireland and Canada.
In addition to the rich detail
and improved accuracy,
the new map serves as the foundation
for many great new features.
In iOS 14, we're adding things
that will make it easier
for people to find places they love
and help them get to where they're going
in ways that are better
for the environment.
To tell you more,
I'll hand it off to Meg Frost.
Thanks, Craig.
First, let's talk about
finding great places.
We have millions of people
coming to Maps every day
to discover great new places,
whether they're planning
their next big vacation
or just looking for
something to eat nearby.
In iOS 14,
the Maps team will be working with
some of the world's most trusted brands
to offer amazing Guides.
Guides for great places to eat, shop,
meet friends or explore
in cities around the world.
You can save Guides
so you can easily get back to them later,
and the best part is they automatically
update when new places are added,
so you always have
the latest recommendations.
In addition to helping you
discover great new places,
Maps helps you get there
in a way that's better for the planet.
For years,
Maps has made it easy to navigate
using environmentally-friendly options
like public transit and walking.
With iOS 14,
we're introducing great new features
to help our users
reduce their carbon footprint,
and our first one is
also our most requested:
It's Cycling.
We've built an incredible
cycling experience
that helps you get around town
on your bike.
We're adding a dedicated cycling option
to Maps
which allows users to ride their bike
along bike lanes, paths and roads.
Maps takes elevation into account
to let you know if you're in for
a challenging uphill workout
or a leisurely flat ride.
You can also see if your route
includes quiet or busy roads.
We'll even let you know
if you have a steep passage coming up
or if you'll need to carry your bike
up the stairs.
You can also choose
to avoid stairs altogether.
With iOS 14, we're bringing cycling
to New York City, LA,
the San Francisco Bay Area,
along with a number of cities in China
like Shanghai and Beijing.
And we'll be adding many more cities
in the coming months.
For environmentally conscious drivers,
we're also introducing EV routing.
If you have an electric car,
Maps is going to help eliminate
range anxiety.
With iOS 14,
Maps will track your current charge
and factor in things
like elevation and weather
to automatically add charging stops
along your route.
And Maps will know
which type of charger works for your car,
making sure to only route you
to compatible stations.
We're working with a number
of manufacturers
to support EV routing in their vehicles,
including BMW and Ford,
and we'll be adding many more
in the near future.
Cities around the world are also working
to improve air quality and reduce traffic,
so we're adding
congestion and green zones to Maps
to easily see where they are
along with alternate routing options.
In addition, drivers in China
can securely store their
license plate number on their iPhone,
and Maps will let them know which days
they can enter congested city centers
based on that number.
And those are just some
of the great new features
coming to Apple Maps in iOS 14,
making Maps the best product
to help users explore
and navigate their world.
Thanks, Meg.
And now, on to CarPlay,
which has transformed
the driving experience for iPhone owners
by being the smarter, safer way
to use the apps you love in your car.
CarPlay is everywhere,
and it's incredibly popular.
Here in the US,
it's available on basically every new car.
And worldwide, it's available
on over 80% of new cars sold
and has quickly become the default
in-car experience for so many people.
People love CarPlay, and we get
some really passionate reactions.
Joanna Stern says
it makes her life "infinitely better."
We have some great updates for iOS 14.
First up, we have new wallpaper options
perfect for the car.
And we're adding support
for new categories of CarPlay apps:
parking, EV charging
and quick food ordering.
In addition to this,
we're really excited for the next step
in how we're transforming
your relationship with your car
by rethinking car keys.
They've been around
for over a hundred years,
but they've become big, bulky
and ripe for reimagining.
To tell you more about
what we have planned,
let's go to the garage
with Emily Schubert.
Thanks, Craig.
I'm excited to introduce
a digital version of car keys.
Now you can leave your keys at home
and unlock and start your car
with your iPhone.
And the very first car to support this
will be the new 2021 BMW 5 Series.
Let me show you how it works.
It's super simple.
-It uses NFC, and you just tap to unlock.
-[beeps]
And I place my phone on the charging pad
and then push to start.
[chimes]
But this goes beyond just one less thing
you have to keep in your pocket.
Digital keys have security benefits.
They live in the Secure Element
of your iPhone,
and if it goes missing, you can turn off
your keys remotely via iCloud.
They're even easier to share
than a physical key.
Copies don't involve
trips to the dealership.
And you can share
from wherever you are with iMessage.
Let's give Craig a key so he can
drive home after we're done here.
With each key you share,
you can set options,
like a restricted driving profile,
perfect for teen drivers.
Which is tempting,
but we'll give Craig full access.
[phone chimes]
-[phone chimes]
-Full access? Thanks, Emily.
The new BMW will be available
to customers next month.
In addition to adding this feature
to iOS 14,
we're also enabling it in iOS 13,
so customers can use their car keys
even sooner.
Of course,
we want this to work in any car,
so we've been working on standards
with industry groups.
And this is just the beginning.
We're working on technology
that will leverage our U1 chip,
which uses Ultra Wideband technology
for precise spatial awareness.
So you'll be able to leave your iPhone
in your bag or pocket
and still securely
unlock and start your car.
We expect to see support for this standard
starting in new cars next year.
Now, let's turn to the App Store.
Twelve years ago,
we revolutionized the industry
with the launch of the App Store.
Today we have so many amazing apps
that offer a rich set of experiences,
we can truly say
that for everything we want to do,
"There's an app for that."
So now it's time for us to extend
the success of the App Store
and make apps available and accessible
in whole new ways.
What if you could have the right app
you needed at just the right moment?
Let's look at what it would be like
if you did.
[narrator]
Today, no matter what you want to do,
there's an app for that.
But what if you don't have the app
you need right when you need it?
Like when you need to pay for parking.
Well, now there's an App Clip for that.
[car chirps]
Ooh. Look, a new coffee shop.
There's an App Clip for that.
Or a friend sends you a message
with a print you like.
There's an App Clip for that.
That looks nice.
Looking for somewhere to eat nearby?
App Clip.
Very health conscious of you.
Hey, there's a scooter.
Let's take it for a spin.
Yep. App Clip.
Mmm. Ice cream. Wait.
There isn't one for that yet?
Well, soon there could be
an App Clip for that.
And that.
-And that.
-[martial artist] Hi-yah!
An App Clip is a small part of an app.
It's light and fast and easy to discover,
so you can quickly get what you need
right when you need it.
Everything about App Clips
is designed for speed.
They start with this card
which quickly pops up.
And with just a tap,
you can launch the App Clip.
You don't need to enter
credit card numbers
because App Clips
can use Apple Pay for payments.
And you don't have to manually
log into an account
because it can take advantage
of Sign in with Apple.
App Clips won't clutter your Home Screen
and will only stay along
as long as you need them.
But you can easily launch recently used
App Clips from the new App Library.
It's always easy to download the full app,
and this makes App Clips
an easy way to discover
more of what the App Store has to offer.
And discovery is key.
App Clips are all about getting to a part
of an app at the moment you need it,
so it was critical that we made them
really easy to find.
App Clips can be easily discovered
and launched from the web.
You can launch App Clips from Messages
when friends share them with you.
When you want to order takeout
from a restaurant in Maps,
you can launch an App Clip
right from a place card.
You'll be able to tap on NFC tags out in
the world, on things like parking meters.
Or you can scan QR codes
to launch App Clips
that work with products you purchase.
The best way to discover App Clips will be
with the new Apple-designed App Clip code.
So when you see one, you'll know
that there's an App Clip waiting for you.
They incorporate
both a visual code and NFC,
so you tap on them or scan them with
the camera to bring up an App Clip.
App Clips will be great for businesses
that already have apps.
But we want to be able
to use App Clips everywhere,
including smaller spots
that may not have their own app.
So we made it possible for apps like Yelp,
which support multiple businesses,
to create App Clip experiences
for each of the places they work with.
Developers will create App Clips
from a part of an app,
using Xcode and the full power of the SDK.
To ensure that they launch quickly,
they'll need to be
less than 10 megabytes in size.
And that's App Clips.
Immediately discoverable,
small in size, so they launch fast,
integrated Apple Pay for easy payment,
Sign in with Apple
for quick and privacy-friendly login
and the option to download the full app
from the App Store
when you want to keep it around.
We can't wait to see all the App Clips
developers will create.
And that's iOS 14.
It's a huge release that transforms
the core experience of iPhone,
with redesigned widgets
right on the Home Screen
and a new way to organize your apps
with the App Library.
It adds incredible updates
to some of the most popular apps,
with powerful improvements
to Messages and Maps,
and introduces a whole new way
to tap into apps
with App Clips.
And next up, iPadOS.
["S.S. Luker's Mom" by Oh Sees playing]
Oh, hey, we made it.
All right. Well, let's jump right in.
iPadOS builds on
all the amazing features of iOS
while adding unique capabilities
that deliver a distinct experience
for iPad.
Like using Apple Pencil for taking notes,
markup and illustration.
A reimagined track pad experience
that lets you interact with iPad
in a whole new way.
And unmatched AR experiences with ARKit
and the amazing new LiDAR Scanner
in iPad Pro.
All of this combines to put iPad
into a class of its own.
iPad excels at "every type of input"
and is a "product to do anything
and everything."
Which brings us to this year
and our new release, iPadOS 14.
Let's start with experience.
This year iPadOS delivers
unique made-for-iPad designs
that take great advantage
of the iPad's large, multi-touch display.
Now iPad has always been about the apps.
In the beginning, we focused on
giving the ecosystem of iPhone apps
a larger canvas
to deliver new and unique experiences.
This quickly sparked
an entirely new set of apps,
designed for iPad first,
with immersive experiences
that transform this magical sheet of glass
into whatever you needed it to be.
We're proud of the over one million apps
on the App Store today
designed just for iPad.
With customers continuing to push
their iPads further than ever before,
we're extending
the design language of iPad
to make apps more streamlined
and more powerful.
To give you a live look
at these enhancements,
I'll hand it over to Josh Shaffer.
Thanks, Craig.
Let's take a look at
some of the enhancements to iPadOS.
The first thing that you'll notice
are the same redesigned widgets
that you saw in iOS 14.
They look great on iPad as well,
and they give you information at a glance
whenever you go Home.
But let's see some of the improvements
in the apps, starting with Photos.
iPad is the perfect device
for browsing your photos.
Its large canvas lets you immerse yourself
in all your favorite memories.
And this year, we're making it even easier
to browse and organize your photos
with an all-new sidebar.
With just a tap of this button,
I can reveal the sidebar,
with all the core functionality of the app
in a single location.
My photos remain front and center,
but now I can quickly tap to move
between parts of the app.
The sidebar is a really powerful way
to organize your photos too.
I can easily drag a photo to the sidebar
and then just drop it
to add it to an album.
We've brought this sidebar to many apps
across iPadOS.
Like Notes,
where it provides quick and easy access
to all your folders.
And Files, where we've consolidated
navigation into the sidebar
for a streamlined new design.
We've also streamlined the toolbars,
adding new drop-down menus
that consolidate functions
into a single, easy-to-access button.
I can just tap to change views like this.
And for even quicker access,
I can just tap and drag to change
the sort order, all in a single motion.
You'll find this same approach
across other apps, like Calendar,
where we've brought controls
into a single toolbar at the top,
providing more space for your content
and a single unified place to access
all the app's functionality.
Finally, Music has been updated
to take even better advantage
of iPad's large screen.
The sidebar in Music makes it easy
to move between views.
I can quickly jump between
the new Listen Now and my playlists.
-And once I start playing a song...
-["Caution" by The Killers playing]
...I can bring up the brand-new
full-screen player,
where I can see rich album art,
transport controls and lyrics,
-all in one single view.
-[song fades]
And these are just
some of the enhancements
that are coming to apps in iPadOS.
We're really loving these new app designs.
But there's more,
starting with Siri.
The new compact Siri design
that you heard about in iOS 14
is especially useful on iPad.
Results appear at the bottom right corner,
allowing you to easily reference the app
while using Siri.
And we applied this same approach
to other parts of the experience...
like calls.
Now today when you receive a call
on iPad, you see this.
[beeps]
Whatever you were working on
is suddenly completely covered
with the incoming call screen.
Not cool.
Wouldn't it be nicer
if instead you saw this?
[beeps]
Well, that's much better.
Now an incoming call is presented
with a compact notification
that doesn't take you out of context.
And you can simply tap to answer
or flick it away to dismiss.
And this applies to all calls,
including those from your iPhone
or third-party VoIP apps like Skype.
[rings]
And of course we're bringing this
to iOS as well.
We think our iPhone customers
are going to love it.
Now there's one more key experience
we've redesigned for iPad this year,
and that's Search.
Today Search is a full-screen experience,
and sometimes you can lose track
of your context.
So we've redesigned Search
with a new, compact design.
You can start a search from anywhere,
like the Home Screen
or over any app.
And this makes it easy
to find what you need
without feeling like you've left the app
you're working in.
But we didn't just redesign it.
We've rebuilt Search from the ground up
to be Universal,
becoming a single destination
where you can start all of your searches.
First, we made it better than ever
as an app launcher.
You just start typing a few characters,
and you can instantly get
to where you're going.
It's also great for finding contacts
to message or call
or documents.
You can even search directly into apps
like Keynote, Messages, Mail or Files.
Or look up information
about people or places.
And it's also a great place to start
all of your web searches as well.
As soon as you start typing,
you get relevant suggestions
to complete your search.
And you can get to your web search results
with just a tap.
And Search now makes navigating
to your favorite websites
just as easy as launching an app.
Just type a few letters and the top hit
will take you right to Safari.
So those are some of our updates
to the iPad experience.
And of course,
you also get the new widgets
and all the other great app enhancements
from iOS 14.
Next, we want to push forward your ability
to express yourself creatively
with improvements to Apple Pencil.
Apple Pencil is a game-changing tool
that turns iPad into
a professional drawing canvas,
a great way to mark up and sign documents
and the ultimate note-taking device.
What many people love most
about taking notes with Apple Pencil
is how they can express themselves
in a free-form way.
Mixing handwriting and drawings can be
the best way to capture your thoughts.
Now the challenge is
when you want to change things afterwards.
Here, working with handwriting
just isn't as easy as with typed text.
Now, we sometimes take it for granted,
but with typed text
it's so easy to select,
copy and paste into another document,
or even just make space for more text.
Well, this year, we're going to make
handwriting just as easy
and just as powerful.
But that's not all.
Our customers tell us that once they have
an Apple Pencil in their hand,
they don't want to put it away.
So this year,
we're bringing Scribble to iPad.
So you can handwrite into any text field,
and it will automatically
be converted to text.
To show you all of this in action,
I'd like to welcome Jenny Chen
for a live demo.
Thanks, Craig.
I'm really excited to show you
some great new features we have
for Apple Pencil and iPadOS this year.
One of the great parts about taking notes
with the Apple Pencil
is that it really lets you work
in a free-form way.
I can just start writing anywhere.
And it's not just about text.
I can also express myself
with drawings or shapes.
But sometimes you want that
more professional, cleaned-up look.
So now, when I draw a simple shape
and pause at the end,
it'll automatically convert
to that ideal shape.
And we're smart about it,
retaining the same size
and angle that you drew it at.
In addition to shapes,
we've also made huge improvements
to our handwriting recognition.
So now, when I write,
I can easily make a selection
using the same gestures
that I use for typed text.
I can double tap to select a word
or double tap again to select a line.
Thanks to our advanced,
on-device machine learning,
you'll notice how we can
select the handwriting
while avoiding the drawings nearby.
Now that I have the selection,
I can easily change the color
or move it around the document.
It's also perfectly easy for me
to make space for more room to write.
We think that this will make note-taking
with the Apple Pencil even better.
Now, you don't even have to put it down
when you want to do something else.
Let's say you want to search
for "Edison bulbs" in Safari.
Using Scribble, I can just write
directly into the text field...
and it automatically
gets converted to typed text.
It also works in any text field,
so I can easily add a new Reminder
to my shared Reminders list
with my husband.
I've also been learning Chinese,
so I want to surprise him
with some of my progress and skills.
I'll use Scratch to delete "lights."
And then I can use Scribble to write "new"
and then "light fixture" in Chinese.
You'll notice how Scribble recognizes
both English and Chinese in the same line.
And what's awesome is that
we can build on this technology
to deliver other great features,
like Data Detectors.
We can automatically detect
what you write,
like phone numbers,
so I can make a phone call.
Or addresses, so I can look up directions.
We can use these features together
to do even more with your handwriting.
Let's say I wanted to use my handwriting
in another app.
I can easily select what I want,
tap the new Copy as Text
from the callout bar,
and then paste it into an app like Pages.
And it's automatically converted
to typed text.
We're really excited
about these awesome new features.
And we think it will let you do
even more with the Apple Pencil.
Thanks, Jenny.
So those are the enhancements to Pencil.
Just one part of an amazing release,
with Scribble for handwriting
into any text field,
a whole new way to work
with your handwritten notes,
broad enhancements to the app experience,
and of course, iPad users also benefit
from the great features
you already saw in iOS 14
and much more that
we didn't have time to talk about.
So that's iOS and iPadOS.
Next, let's talk about AirPods.
From the one-click setup
to the automatic pairing
with all your devices
to how they pause your audio
when you take them out,
people love the magical experience
that AirPods deliver.
Now we're bringing even more magic
to AirPods.
To tell you all about it,
here's Mary-Ann Ionascu.
Thanks, Craig.
We have some amazing updates
coming to AirPods,
starting with Automatic Switching.
AirPods will now seamlessly move
between your devices
without you having
to manually switch them.
Let's say you just finished
listening to a podcast
and you pick up your iPad to watch a show.
AirPods will magically switch over.
And later you start a video conference
on your Mac.
AirPods will automatically switch again.
-[ringing]
-And if a phone call comes in,
the audio in your AirPods
will route right back to your phone.
We also have an exciting new feature
coming to AirPods Pro:
spatial audio.
You know the experience
of being in a movie theater
with a state-of-the-art
surround sound system,
one where the sound
not only comes from in front of you...
-[tone pulsing]
-...but also from the left, the right,
behind, and even from above you?
Well, we are thrilled to bring that same
immersive experience to AirPods Pro.
But it turns out it's a lot harder to do
when you only have a single earbud
in each ear.
So our team created advanced
spatial audio algorithms for AirPods Pro
that replicate
the movie theater experience.
By applying directional audio filters
and subtly adjusting the frequencies
each ear receives,
we can place sounds
virtually anywhere in space...
[high-speed vehicles passing]
...creating an immersive
surround sound experience.
But to truly deliver on this promise,
we had to factor in real-life situations.
First, people move their heads.
For an authentic
surround sound experience,
you need the sound field to stay fixed
so the voice feels like
it's coming from the actor
and not some random point in space.
So we use the accelerometer
and gyroscopes in AirPods Pro
to track the motion of your head,
remapping the sound field
so it stays anchored to your device,
even as your head moves.
And it's not only your head that can move,
but you might move
your iPad or iPhone as well.
That's why we constantly compare
the motion data
from your head and your screen
to understand how they are moving
in relation to each other.
So if your bus turns the corner
or your plane banks,
the sound stays in sync.
The result is a surround sound experience
that keeps you
in the middle of the action,
no matter where you go.
Spatial audio for AirPods Pro will work
with content encoded in 5.1, 7.1,
and even Dolby Atmos.
Thanks, Mary-Ann.
I've been using the new spatial audio,
and I think you're all
really gonna love it.
All right. Next let's head
to the Fitness Center
to hear the latest on watchOS from Kevin.
["I'm Getting Tired"
by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
Thanks, Craig.
Since we launched Apple Watch,
it's completely redefined
what a watch can do,
and this has been
incredibly meaningful work.
Apple Watch not only helps you
stay connected and active,
it's become an intelligent guardian
of your health,
enabling you to take an ECG, detect falls
and call emergency services for you.
It's impacting lives in ways
that were inconceivable five years ago.
The power of Apple Watch
is not only its built-in features,
but how developers
have personalized it for you.
We introduced the App Store in watchOS 6,
and there are now over 20,000
watchOS apps available.
These apps bring the information
you care about most
to just a glance at your watch face.
We're taking this even further
in watchOS 7,
starting with complications.
Until today, an app could appear in only
one spot at a time on a watch face.
In watchOS 7 developers can
enable multiple complications,
making even more richly personal
watch faces.
So if you like to use
Dawn Patrol for surfing,
you can create your own surf watch,
including water temperature,
swell and wind speed predictions
for your favorite beach.
Or new parents can use Glow Baby
to see nap, changing and feeding times
all on one face.
While Nike Run Club can display stats
like pace from your last run
and your weekly run goals.
We're also bringing rich complications
to more faces,
including a fresh Chronograph face
with an integrated tachymeter
and an updated Extra Large face
with a huge, rich complication
right in the center.
And Configuring Watch Faces
has been redesigned
so you can easily select
which information you'd like to see.
As developers, with watchOS 7
you can now build your rich complications
with native SwiftUI.
While there are so many ways
to configure watch faces,
you may not have yet gone in
and set these up for yourself yet.
That's okay.
With watchOS 7 we're making it super easy
to share watch faces,
so you can discover a face
that works perfectly for you.
To do this,
we're introducing Face Sharing.
You'll be able to discover curated faces
with third-party apps on the App Store,
or discover a new favorite watch face
right on a website,
or receive watch faces
directly from friends and family.
Let's take a look at how this works.
When you see a watch face you'd like,
you just press "Add Apple Watch Face."
If the watch face uses some apps
that you don't have yet,
you'll be offered each one right here
so you can easily get them if you like.
And the new face appears
right on your watch.
If you'd like to share a face
you've created yourself,
that's also really easy.
Just long press on the face,
tap "Share," pick a contact and send.
Developers can offer preconfigured
watch faces right from their apps.
You can even share watch faces
across social media.
It's a great way for the community
of Apple Watch wearers to connect
and help each other discover all the
amazing things Apple Watch is capable of.
Next, let's talk about Maps.
Maps is great for walking, driving
and transit directions,
and now in watchOS, just like in iOS 14,
you can get cycling directions.
You'll see a variety of routes
with information like time, distance
and whether there are bike lanes.
You can preview travel time
and elevation changes
and navigate with turn-by-turn directions
that are large and easy to read.
Maps can direct you to dismount
and walk your bike
or even take the stairs to save time.
You can also search for and add places
optimized for cyclists,
like bike repair shops.
[chimes]
Now to tell you about
how we're advancing Workouts,
please welcome Julz Arney.
Thanks, Kevin.
The Workout app uses algorithms
that are smartly tuned
to track all aspects of your training.
It's one of the most used apps
on Apple Watch,
and we've continued to add support
for new workout types every year.
-And in watchOS 7 we're adding Dance.
-[dance music playing]
Dance is a total body workout
that's great for your heart.
It makes you more fit and flexible,
and you're guaranteed to have fun.
Whether you're doing Hip Hop, Latin,
Bollywood, or simply Cardio Dance,
the Workout app now tracks
some of the world's most popular
styles of dance for fitness.
Getting the most accurate credit for Dance
presented a unique challenge.
Arm movements aren't always repetitive
or synchronized with leg movements
like in running and walking.
The solution was to use
advanced sensor fusion.
[music continues]
In Dance, we combine data from
the accelerometer and the gyroscope
to detect the difference between
dancing with just your arms...
just your lower body...
or when you put it all together
and dance with your entire body.
Then we add in heart rate data
for the most accurate
calorie burn calculations.
watchOS 7 also tracks accurate calories
for Core Training,
those exercises for your abs and back,
Functional Strength Training,
a workout type that helps you get stronger
and move better for everyday activities,
and also Cooldowns
to add on to another workout
when you want to continue
with easy moves and stretches
as you bring your heart rate
and breathing back to normal.
Of course, you can track your progress
for any of these new workouts
inside the Activity app on iPhone,
which is completely redesigned
in watchOS 7.
The app now features a new Summary tab
that gives you an easy way
to see your activity history,
workouts and trends,
all in one seamless view.
With a new focus on easy navigation
and summary metrics,
the app is getting a new name as well:
[music continues]
Fitness.
Back to you, Kevin.
-[record scratches]
-[music ends]
Thanks, Julz.
Apple Watch helps you meet
not only your fitness goals,
but also helps support your health
with features such as Cycle Tracking,
the Breathe app, and Noise notifications.
And we're going to be adding even more
capabilities this year in watchOS 7.
We'd like to share a couple of them
with you today,
starting with one of the most-requested
features for Apple Watch:
tracking your sleep.
To tell you about this, over to Vera Carr.
Thanks, Kevin.
There are many ways to look at sleep:
scores, advanced monitoring,
or sleep cycle analysis.
We are taking
a more holistic approach to sleep
by leveraging the devices you use
every day
to not only track your sleep
but to support you in actually meeting
your sleep duration goal.
That starts with choosing not only when
you would like to wake up in the morning,
but also when you'd like to go to bed.
For most of us, setting a goal is easy.
But getting to bed on time,
that's the hard part.
Experts say that establishing
a bedtime routine
helps the body transition
from wakefulness to sleep.
So we are offering Wind Down.
It can help you get to bed on time
by minimizing distractions
and creating a personalized routine.
Let's look at how this works.
In the evening, ahead of your bedtime,
your phone can display
the Wind Down screen
to help you transition mentally
before you go to bed.
It creates a calm lock screen experience
and turns on Do Not Disturb for you.
You can also set up shortcuts
for simple things you may like to do
to help you prepare for bed.
These might include
using your favorite meditation app
or playing relaxing music.
Once it's time for bed,
your screen will dim and your watch
will go into Sleep Mode,
which looks like this.
The screen will be off during time in bed
so it won't bother you,
and a tap displays this simple face.
When it's time to wake up,
you have a selection of gentle
and effective alarm sounds,
or a silent Taptic-only wake-up alarm
so you don't disturb your partner.
Once you're up, you'll see a friendly
greeting easing you into the day.
It also shows your battery level
so you can remember to charge
in the morning.
Apple Watch tracks your sleep
using a machine-learning model
that senses your motion
and even interprets the micro-movements
caused by the rise and fall
of your breath,
providing signals for when you're awake
and when you're asleep.
There's an updated Sleep section
in the Health app,
including a view of your trends over time.
Sleep Schedules, Wind Down, and Sleep Mode
are also available on iPhone,
without a watch, in iOS 14.
We know you'll enjoy using
your watch throughout the day
and now throughout the night.
Thanks, Vera.
In addition to sleep keeping you healthy,
there's another preventative-care item
that's so important, particularly now:
handwashing.
In watchOS 7,
Apple Watch is the first watch
to deliver automatic detection
when you start washing your hands
and sensing of how long you actually wash.
Our approach here is using
machine-learning models
to determine motion
which appears to be handwashing
and then use audio
to confirm the sound of running water
or squishing soap on your hands.
During this, you'll get a little coaching
to do a good job.
You'll see a countdown,
along with haptics and sounds,
to make sure you wash
as long as you're supposed to.
If you pause early,
there's a polite note to keep washing.
And when you're done,
you'll see, hear and feel it.
That's just some of what's coming
this year in watchOS 7,
including discovering and sharing faces,
new workout types,
sleep and handwashing detection,
and other new capabilities
like Siri language translation.
And that's Apple Watch.
It's time for you to join Craig again
to talk about something
that's important to all of us.
Here we go!
["I'm Getting Tired"
by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
At Apple, we believe
privacy is a fundamental human right.
So we build it into our products
from the beginning of the design process.
Privacy matters now more than ever.
And because our devices contain
our most sensitive information,
all of our product work is grounded
in a set of privacy principles.
First, data minimization.
We use innovative technologies
and techniques
to minimize the personal data
we or anyone else can access.
Second, on-device intelligence.
We avoid data collection
by processing as much of your information
on your device as we can
rather than sending it to a server.
Third, security.
Security protections are foundational
to everything we do in privacy.
And finally, transparency and control.
It helps you better understand
the data being collected
so that you can make your own choices
about how that data is used.
These principles come together
across our products,
in our hardware,
our software and our services.
At the end of the day, they result
in great privacy and great ease of use.
A powerful example of this
is Sign in with Apple,
which is designed for simplicity,
security and privacy.
And since we launched it last year,
users have created
over 200 million accounts
across a wide variety of apps
and websites.
And developers are seeing great usage
when they adopt it.
For example,
Kayak has integrated Sign in with Apple
and found that their users are now
two times more likely to use it
than any other sign-in provider.
Now, one thing we hear a lot
with Sign in with Apple
is that people wish they could convert
their existing accounts to use it.
So this year we're going to enable
developers to let you do just that.
When you upgrade, you get the ease of use
and built-in security
of Sign in with Apple
while keeping the account
that you already have.
This is another big year
of privacy improvements in our products.
And to tell you more, here's Katie Skinner
and Erik Neuenschwander.
Thanks, Craig.
First let's talk about location.
This year we're continuing to give you
even more control.
In addition to the option
of sharing your precise location,
you will have the option to only share
your approximate location with apps.
We're also making changes
for mic and camera
so you always know when you're recording.
In addition to requiring your permission,
this year we're adding more visibility
for current or recent mic or camera use.
So if an app uses either one,
we'll indicate that in the status bar.
[Katie] Next, let's talk about tracking.
Safari's Intelligent Tracking Prevention
has been really successful on the web.
And this year, we wanted to help you
with tracking in apps.
We believe tracking should always be
transparent and under your control.
So moving forward,
App Store policy will require apps to ask
before tracking you
across apps and websites
owned by other companies.
[Erik] Last, let's talk about app privacy.
Today we require that apps
have a privacy policy.
Wouldn't it be great to even more quickly
and easily see
a summary of an app's privacy practices
before you download it?
Now, where have we seen
something like that before?
For food, you have nutrition labels.
You can see if it's packed with protein
or loaded with sugar, or maybe both,
all before you buy it.
So we thought it would be great
to have something similar for apps.
We're going to require each developer
to self-report their practices.
[Katie] We'll show you what they tell us.
You can see if the developer is collecting
a little bit of data on you
or a lot of data,
or if they're sharing data
with other companies to track you,
and much more.
[Erik] We're going to put this information
on product pages in the App Store.
So for each app, you can see
highlights of their privacy information
before you download it.
And we're going to include this
in all of our App Stores.
Back over to you, Craig.
Thanks, Katie and Erik.
These are some of the ways we're
strengthening the privacy of our platforms
and bringing new features
to give users even more control.
And one of the places where
privacy matters most is your home.
Like most of you,
in the past few months I've spent
more time at home than I ever imagined.
It's more clear than ever
just how important it is
to live in a home
where the technology just works.
That brings us to some great new features
we're bringing to the home this year.
All of these features share
a few key attributes.
First, anything we develop for the home
should be easy,
from initial setup to everyday use,
just like how a tap of your iPhone
can automatically configure an Apple TV.
Second, home products should never
compromise your privacy.
That's why your Siri requests use
a random identifier, not your Apple ID.
And finally, your devices should
all work better together,
like how AirPlay lets you share
from your iPhone straight to the TV.
And when things are easy, private
and work together seamlessly,
your home is more enjoyable,
whether you're watching TV,
listening to music
or getting the most
out of your smart devices.
To tell you more
about what we have in store for the home,
let me pass it to Yah Cason.
Thanks, Craig.
Let's start by talking about
the smart home.
With HomeKit,
we've given developers a robust framework
to create smart home accessories
that are remarkably easy to set up
all while being end-to-end encrypted
to your Apple devices.
Already there's a rich ecosystem
of devices available.
But we want to make it even easier
to build products
that work across more homes.
So we formed an alliance
and partnered with Amazon, Google
and other industry leaders
to define a new interoperability
standard for the smart home.
We open-sourced HomeKit
to ensure its ease of use and privacy
are core to this effort.
And any accessory using HomeKit
or this new standard
will work incredibly well
across all your Apple devices.
And you control it all in the Home app,
the most secure way
to manage your smart home.
Adding new devices to your home
has never been easier.
Simply tap or scan to set up an accessory.
And in iOS 14, after you add an accessory,
the Home app will now suggest
useful automations
so you can immediately
put your new device to work for you.
Automations are rules
that set your home to autopilot,
like automatically turning on
your porch lights when motion is detected
or having the garage door open
as you arrive home.
And now when you open the Home app,
you'll see a new visual status
right up top
that prioritizes the accessories
which most need your attention.
You can easily see if you've left
a door unlocked or the lights on
and quickly control them.
Let's take a closer look
at one of the most popular categories
of HomeKit accessories:
Lights.
Millions of us have already added
smart bulbs to our homes,
many of which can change color on demand.
In iOS 14,
we're introducing a feature to help you
get the most out of those bulbs:
Adaptive lighting.
Adaptive lighting automatically adjusts
the color temperature of your lights
throughout the day.
Turn it on to ease into the morning
with warm colors,
stay focused and alert midday
with cooler ones,
and wind down at night
by reducing blue light.
Adaptive lighting ensures
you get the right color at the right time.
Another popular smart home category
is cameras.
With HomeKit Secure Video
your cameras are completely private.
And in iOS 14, we're making your cameras
work even harder for you.
You'll be able to define Activity Zones
that focus on the most important areas.
This is great if you face a busy sidewalk
and only want to be alerted when people
actually walk up to your front door.
Another powerful feature we're bringing
to cameras is face recognition.
HomeKit cameras and video doorbells will
now provide even richer notifications,
telling you who's there
by leveraging the friends and family
you've already tagged in your Photos app.
And face recognition extends to HomePod,
announcing who's at the door.
And with Apple TV, you'll get a live view
whenever someone rings the bell.
In fact, all your HomeKit-enabled cameras
will be directly integrated with tvOS 14
so you can quickly bring them up
in the new home view in Control Center.
Or just ask Siri to pull up any camera
at any time.
You can even take any camera full-screen,
giving you a great view
of what's going on.
And we have even more coming to tvOS 14.
Now let me pass it to Cindy Lin
to tell you about it.
Thanks, Yah.
Apple TV is my favorite way to unwind
and enjoy entertainment with the family.
With 4K, HDR,
Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos,
you get a theater-like experience
right in your living room,
making all your movies and shows
look and sound amazing.
But Apple TV goes beyond video.
You can access
the entire Apple Music collection
and even sing along with timed lyrics.
You can play
an incredible selection of games,
including all the games in Apple Arcade.
And we're making gaming on Apple TV
even more personal
by expanding multiuser support.
Now you can instantly resume your games
exactly where you left off.
Just open Control Center
to switch between users,
and you can now see your game progress,
achievements and friends.
And for even more fun,
we're adding support
for Xbox Elite 2
and Xbox Adaptive Controllers.
Apple TV
also helps you keep active at home
with a great selection of fitness apps.
And with tvOS 14,
we're gonna make your workouts,
and everything you do on Apple TV,
even more productive
by extending Picture in Picture
across the entire Apple TV experience.
So you can keep up with the news
or not miss a second of the big game.
You can even have an AirPlay session
show up in a Picture in Picture window.
And AirPlay is getting even better.
Now the whole family can share
their stunning videos captured on iPhone
in their full 4K resolution.
With videos, music, games and more,
Apple TV truly offers something
for everyone.
Of course, nothing compares
to being captivated by a good story.
And we've built a service for just that:
Apple TV+.
We've already created
an incredible lineup of Apple Originals.
And you can watch them all
in the Apple TV app,
which is available
on your favorite Apple devices,
on all major streaming boxes
and many popular smart TVs.
It's already reaching
over a billion screens.
And it's coming to Sony and Vizio
smart TVs later this summer.
Today, we're really excited
to tell you about a new Apple TV+ Original
that we're working on.
Almost 70 years ago,
Isaac Asimov introduced the world
to a series of epic novels
that spanned hundreds of worlds
and thousands of years.
Many consider it to be the best
science-fiction series of all time.
I'd like to share a sneak peek
with you now.
This is Foundation.
[dramatic music playing]
They're going to arrest me tomorrow.
And you. It's almost a certainty.
You're familiar with my work,
psychohistory?
Yes, in theory.
But I don't know what it has to do with--
It's not a theory.
[Salvor] They're worried
you can predict the future.
[whirring]
[Hari]
They're worried people believe I can.
[whirring]
And they don't like the future I predict.
The empire will fall.
Order will vanish.
There's massive events rushing to meet us.
[Salvor] Only we can shorten the darkness.
[music fades]
Wow. I'm super excited to watch Foundation
when it comes to Apple TV+ next year.
With Apple TV, your home
has never been more entertaining.
And with adaptive lighting,
face recognition for cameras
and these other great features,
your time at home
has never been more enjoyable.
Now let me hand it back to Craig.
Welcome back.
Now let's talk about some big changes
coming to macOS.
Since its introduction,
macOS has revolutionized the experience
of using a computer
by combining incredible power
with incredible ease of use.
And it's loved
by all different types of users,
from families and students
to creative pros,
businesspeople
and, of course, software developers.
And this year, we're taking
the macOS experience you love
even further.
But what should we call it?
Well, if you're a student of macOS,
you know this question
can only be answered by Apple's
legendary crack marketing team.
Their drug-fueled,
minibus-driven vision quests
have yielded some great names
and, sadly, spawned a host of imitators.
The truth is,
we can't responsibly continue
to inadvertently lead our competition
to copy these methods
when they clearly can't handle the trip.
So this year, we're leaving our process
shrouded in mystery
and taking you straight
to the glorious destination.
Our next release of macOS
is macOS Big Sur.
macOS Big Sur introduces
an entirely new design
and major updates to some of
the most essential apps on the platform.
And just like its name,
Big Sur brings you unmatched levels
of power and beauty.
Let's start with design,
where we're making the biggest change
since the introduction of Mac OS X.
To tell you more about the philosophy
and incredible craftsmanship
behind the new design,
here's a short video with Alan Dye.
[piano playing]
At Apple, design has always been
about great ideas.
Those ideas then are developed
with this obsessive dedication to detail.
If we care enough about all the details
that make up a product,
then in the end
we will have designed an experience
that really feels like
there's no other way it could be.
And the best example of this
is macOS Big Sur.
Our goal was to bring even more clarity
to the design of the software
while retaining the Mac's
powerful capability and ease of use.
We started with the simplest of elements,
from the shape of a corner radius
to refinements in buttons and controls.
And we brought our unified language
of symbols to the Mac,
making them more consistent
and easier to recognize.
Depth, shading and translucency
are used to create hierarchy.
These new materials are rich,
and they're vibrant.
They bridge light and dark.
We've reduced visual complexity
to keep the focus on users' content.
Buttons and controls appear
when you need them,
and they recede when you don't.
There's a new way
to access system-level controls
and a unified space
for notifications and widgets.
We've also created a new suite of sounds.
They're familiar to the Mac,
but remastered and more refined.
[pulses]
[alert notifications chiming]
We wanted consistency
throughout the ecosystem,
so users can move fluidly
between their Apple devices.
But we also love that Mac icons
have a deep history
and a distinct look and feel.
So we've retained
many of the highly crafted details
and the playful elements
that make Mac icons unique.
This OS reflects an important history.
It's familiar, but it's also
entirely new in every detail.
We love the Mac.
It's the tool we use to make all the
products that we put out into the world.
And macOS Big Sur is where it starts.
[Craig] So that's the thinking
behind our new design.
Now let me show it to you
in action with a demo.
As Alan said,
we've refined some of the most iconic
elements of the Mac experience.
Let's start with the Dock.
It has an elegant new design that floats
along the bottom of your desktop.
And you'll notice that we've created
gorgeous new app icons
for all of your favorite apps.
Speaking of apps,
let's take a look at the Finder.
You notice it has a gorgeous new
top-to-bottom design for the sidebar,
and it has a compact,
space-efficient toolbar.
Makes it really easy
to get to all of your controls.
Next, let's take a look at Mail.
You can see that Mail has
all-new glyphs in the sidebar,
and you may have noticed
that we've brought color back as well.
Now, each app uses its own key color.
That same color is used for the elegant
new rounded row selection style
here in the message list.
Now, the toolbar makes it really easy
to get to all your controls.
Check out how the search bar expands
as I click on it.
And, of course,
other operations like filtering,
they're just a click away.
Next, let's take a look at Photos.
It's just stunning.
You can get to all your albums
and media types from the sidebar,
and the photo grid is backed by Metal,
so animations are super smooth
whether I'm scrolling, transitioning
or zooming all the way in
or all the way out.
It's beautiful.
Now we've refreshed the design
for all the apps on the system,
from apps like Calendar and Notes
to Podcasts and Music,
with its new Listen Now pane.
And an all-new version of iWork
that features a simplified toolbar.
You may have noticed
we've also updated the menu bar.
It's now translucent and elegantly takes
on the color of your desktop picture.
And we've updated the layout
of menus as well.
We've given all the items
just a little bit more room to breathe.
Now, on the Mac, we love our ability
to get directly at controls,
like Wi-Fi or Sound.
And you can see that we've reworked these
to be even more useful.
But we've gone even further this year
by giving you one place
to get at all your controls.
We've brought Control Center to the Mac.
All of my controls are here,
and it's really easy to make adjustments.
For instance,
I can change display brightness here
or I can click to dive in for more,
like turning on Dark Mode
or activating Night Shift.
And what's really cool is
that I can customize the menu bar
with any of these controls.
So, say I want one-click access
to Do Not Disturb.
I can just click and drag it
right into my menu bar
and customize just like that.
Now we've also reinvented
Notification Center.
You can access it by clicking on the time
in the upper right.
And as you see, we now have a single view
that brings your notifications and widgets
together all in one place.
And we now group
related notifications together.
You can easily expand them
to take a closer look
or clear them all out in one step.
And we're bringing our redesigned widgets
to the Mac.
They're really beautiful.
And you have all-new ways
to customize them.
I'm just gonna click "Edit Widgets"
down here at the bottom.
And you can see
I have a gallery of all my widgets,
and they come in a variety of sizes.
I can select between them just like this.
And developers can bring
their own widgets as well,
like this one here from Day One.
Now adding widgets is easy.
Let's start by adding,
say, the World Clock.
Maybe I'll add Notes in.
And it'd be kind of cool
to add my Reminders list as well.
So that's a look at Widgets,
Notification Center
and our all-new design in Big Sur.
Next, there are exciting updates
for some of the most-used apps on the Mac.
First, let's talk about Messages.
Messages on the Mac is designed to work
seamlessly with all of your devices,
so your SMS and iMessage conversations
are in sync
no matter what device you're using.
Now this year we're taking Messages
to the next level
with a ton of great new features.
We're introducing powerful search
to help you find what you're looking for.
We have a redesigned photo picker
to make sharing photos and videos easier.
And Memoji. You can now create
and edit your Memoji right on your Mac.
And Memoji stickers
bring personality to messages,
giving you fun ways to express yourself
in all of your conversations.
Messages effects helps you
celebrate special moments
and get your point across.
And you're also getting
pinned conversations
that are synced across devices
so you can always get to them,
along with new Groups enhancements.
So that's what's coming
to Messages on Mac:
powerful tools
to manage your conversations
and new ways to express yourself.
Next up, Maps.
Apple Maps is the best way
to explore and navigate the world,
whether you're planning a trip on the Mac
or using turn-by-turn directions
on your iPhone.
Today I'm excited to announce
an all-new version of Maps for the Mac.
To start,
Maps features a stunning new design
that makes it easy to find your way around
using Apple's detailed new map.
And for the first time on the Mac,
Favorites like home, work
or that great coffee shop on the corner
are now just a click away.
You can now create your own Guides
of all the places you want to visit
right on your Mac.
And before leaving for the airport,
you can check where your gate is located
with indoor maps
or explore your destination city
with Look Around,
which is incredible on the big screen.
We've even brought
other useful features to the Mac,
like the ability to see
the progress of friends
who have shared their ETA with you.
And the Mac gets
all the other new Maps features
we just introduced in iOS 14.
And that's just a taste of what's coming
in the all-new Apple Maps on the Mac.
Next let's talk about Mac Catalyst.
Catalyst gives developers a big head start
in creating a Mac app from an iPad app.
Take, for instance, our recent release
of Swift Playgrounds for Mac.
Catalyst gave us a big head start
creating the app,
and we were able
to spend our development time
crafting a great Mac experience.
Today we have some improvements
to Mac Catalyst I'd like to share.
This year, developers will be able
to optimize their apps
to fully utilize the native resolution
of the Mac screen,
providing total control of every pixel.
We've also given developers
new capabilities,
including powerful new menu
and keyboard APIs
and updated controls
like checkboxes and date pickers.
They look great
with the new design of macOS.
In fact, we used Catalyst
with the new version of Maps.
And just as you'd expect,
it's a full-fledged Mac app
that runs natively
and is designed
in a way that's true to the Mac.
So you get multiple resizable windows,
keyboard shortcuts
and everything else you'd expect
from a native Mac app.
And we did the same thing for Messages.
Maps and Messages join
the great set of apps from Apple
that already use
the Mac Catalyst technology.
And there's a growing list
of third-party Catalyst apps available
on the Mac App Store.
Next... Safari.
Our users love Safari
for its speedy performance,
power efficiency
and state-of-the-art privacy protections.
And it delivers all of that
while making it easy to get to your
bookmarks, tabs and browsing history
across all of your devices.
This year, we're building
on Safari's amazing performance,
elegant design
and pioneering privacy protections
to deliver the biggest update to Safari
since it was first introduced.
As you know, Safari has long been
the world's fastest desktop browser.
This year, Safari's performance
running JavaScript is better than ever
and continues to significantly outpace
all other major browsers.
And now, when it comes to page loading,
we're even faster there too.
In fact, when loading
frequently visited websites,
Safari is now on average
more than 50% faster than Chrome.
And Safari delivers
this amazing performance
while continuing to deliver
industry-leading battery life.
And of course,
Safari is continuing to build
on its pioneering track record
of protecting user privacy.
Safari was the first browser to introduce
private browsing, cookie blocking,
and most recently,
Intelligent Tracking Prevention.
This year, we want to give our users
even more visibility
into how each site they visit
tries to track them
and the ways that Safari protects them.
So now users can click on
the Privacy Report button in the toolbar
when they visit a site
to better understand
how that site is treating their privacy.
In addition to monitoring
unwanted tracking,
Safari now also securely monitors
your saved passwords
to ensure that they haven't been
compromised in a data breach.
And this is also a big year
for extensions in Safari.
We're adding support
for the WebExtensions API
so developers can easily
bring over extensions
that they built for other browsers.
And we're building an all-new category
in the Mac App Store
to showcase Safari extensions
so users can easily find them.
Now extensions are very powerful
but can introduce privacy challenges.
In other browsers, extensions can access
every page you visit,
every tab you open,
even everything you type.
So we're doing even more here.
In Safari, you choose
which sites each extension can work with,
and you can even give them access
just for the day,
just for the website or all the time.
But improved performance,
power efficiency and privacy protections
are only the start.
We have a whole slew
of new features this year.
From a customizable start page
to redesigned tabs
that are more elegant and powerful,
and native translation capabilities
built right into Safari.
To tell you more,
I'll hand it off to Beth Dakin.
Thanks, Craig.
I'm so excited to give you
a tour of the brand-new Safari.
When you open Safari,
right away you'll notice the new look.
It's clean and fresh.
I want to show you
one of my favorite new features:
the customizable start page.
I love it because I can make it my own.
It's easy to get to
the customization controls
here in the bottom corner.
We think a lot of people are gonna want
to set a background image,
and there's a beautiful gallery
of curated wallpapers to choose from.
You can use one of your own photos, too,
and I know I want a photo of my son.
I have a few really cute ones
here in the downloads.
I can just drag and drop to set it.
That is so perfect.
You can add new sections
to the start page too.
Let's add iCloud Tabs and Reading List.
Let's take a look.
There. This is perfect.
I use Reading List all the time,
and now it's so easy to get to.
Another way that you can dial in Safari
to suit your specific needs
is with extensions.
I can't wait for you developers
to bring your web extensions to Safari.
I've gone ahead and downloaded
a few web extensions to take a peek.
So let's go here to the Safari preferences
to enable them.
And I'll enable Power Thesaurus
and Recipe Filter.
So each of the extensions
that I just enabled
now has its own button
here in the toolbar.
Let me show you Recipe Filter.
I love this one.
So this extension will search
the web page for a recipe,
and if it finds one,
it will pop it up in a little card.
It's been a great accelerator for me
when I'm building a grocery list.
So the extension hasn't done anything yet
because I haven't granted permission.
So let me click on the toolbar button,
and I'm going to allow this extension
for one day.
And when I click here, it'll do its thing.
So here we go. And there it is. So useful.
Okay, so I have my personality
pretty thoroughly stamped
over Safari at this point.
And you know,
I use Safari for a lot of personal things,
and Apple makes sure
my private life stays private.
Privacy is essential to everything we do
at Apple, and it's critical on the web.
And now you can see
what Safari is doing to protect you.
If I click on the
Intelligent Tracking Prevention button,
I can see the number of known trackers
that Safari protected me from
on this web page.
I can click here
to see a list of the known trackers
right here in this popover.
And the full privacy report
is just one click away.
And that's what we have for privacy
in the new Safari.
Next I'd like to talk about tabs.
If you love tabs,
you're going to love the new Safari.
It's easier and more efficient than ever
to work with lots of tabs.
So I have another window here,
and right away you'll notice
that there are icons and tabs,
which makes it so easy
to spot what you're looking for.
And if I open more tabs,
then you'll see more of them at once
because the tabs get smaller
and use the space more efficiently.
If it's a little hard to find what
you're looking for with this many tabs,
that's no problem.
You can just hover over tabs
and see a nice preview of the page.
I'm ready to clean up now,
and that's easy too.
I can just bring up the context menu here
and close all tabs to the right.
Just like that.
We are so excited that
the new Safari has built-in translation.
Let me show you.
So here on this website, on El Mundo,
Safari has detected
that this is not in my primary language,
and it's added the translation icon
to the smart search field.
I can click here,
and let's translate this page to English.
It'll happen inline.
And as more content is added,
that gets translated dynamically too.
Those are some highlights, but there is
so much more to the new Safari.
Back to you, Craig.
Thanks, Beth.
So that's Safari.
It's a huge release,
with new ways to customize,
big improvements
to your browsing experience
like tabs and translation,
and even stronger privacy protection
to keep your browsing your business.
And that's macOS Big Sur,
the biggest update to design since
the original introduction of Mac OS X,
significant updates to Messages and Maps
and the biggest update to Safari ever.
But these changes are only the beginning.
For years now,
down deep, below the surface,
we've been working
on something truly profound.
To tell you more,
I'll hand it back to Tim.
Thanks, Craig.
Big Sur is going to be
a great release of macOS.
But that's only part of the story,
because today is going to be
a truly historic day for the Mac.
Today we're going to tell you
about some really big changes,
how we're going to take the Mac
to a whole new level.
From the very beginning,
the Mac redefined
the entire computer industry.
The Mac has always been about innovation
and boldly pushing things forward,
embracing big changes to stay
at the forefront of personal computing.
The Mac has had
three major transitions in its history.
The move to PowerPC,
the transition to Mac OS X
and the move to Intel.
And now it's time
for a huge leap forward for the Mac,
because today is the day we're announcing
that the Mac is transitioning...
to our own Apple Silicon.
When we make bold changes,
it's for one simple yet powerful reason:
so we can make much better products.
When we look ahead,
we envision some amazing new products,
and transitioning
to our own custom silicon
is what will enable us
to bring them to life.
At Apple,
integrating hardware and software
is fundamental to everything we do.
That's what makes our products so great.
And silicon is at the heart
of our hardware.
So having a world-class
silicon design team
is a game changer.
To tell you more about Apple Silicon
and how it will take Mac
to the next level,
I'd like to send you over to Johny Srouji
at one of our labs
in an undisclosed location.
["I'm Getting Tired"
by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
Welcome to our lab.
We've been building and refining
our Apple Silicon for over a decade.
The result is a scalable architecture
that is custom-designed
for Apple products,
and it leads the industry in features
and performance per watt.
So I'd like to tell you how we got here
and what it means for the Mac
moving forward.
It all started with the iPhone.
The iPhone demanded
performance and capabilities
that were seen as impossible
in a device that small.
This is where we developed our relentless
focus on performance per watt.
Generation after generation,
we pushed the boundaries of technology,
which enabled us to improve
performance and energy efficiency,
while building advanced
and industry-leading features.
Our team delivered ten generations
of increasingly complex and rich designs,
always improving performance.
In fact, CPU performance in the iPhone
has improved by over a hundred times,
keeping the iPhone's performance ahead
of every other phone in the industry.
Another opportunity for the team
was the iPad.
While iPhone chips
could drive our mainstream iPads,
we wanted to push the iPad even further.
It began with the iPad's Retina display,
which demanded a custom chip.
So the team scaled our architecture
and designed the most-optimized
and highest-performance chip
possible for the iPad.
Starting with the A5X,
we built a line of SoCs
specifically designed for the iPad.
We doubled the iPhone's
graphics performance through a larger GPU
and a wider memory subsystem.
This put the iPad in a class by itself.
Compared to the very first iPad,
the latest iPad Pro delivers
over 1,000 times faster
graphics performance
in just ten years.
This is part of the reason
why the iPad Pro is faster
than the vast majority of PC laptops.
And this foreshadows how well
our architecture will scale into the Mac.
Another place where we applied our focus
was the Watch.
We scaled our SoC architecture
to optimize performance
for the device's unique
low-power requirements,
and we built a chip
perfectly suited for Apple Watch.
Our SoCs enable each of these products
with unique features
and industry-leading performance per watt,
and it makes each of them best in class.
And we do this at an enormous scale.
In fact, adding all of the processors
across these three products,
we've shipped over two billion
in just ten years.
And we've designed and shipped
billions of additional chips
that work together with our SoCs
to enable our amazing products.
And now we're bringing
all of that expertise
and that same focused
and disciplined approach
to the Mac.
The first thing this will do is give
the Mac a whole new level of performance.
Now, when we talk about performance,
we have to talk about power,
because all systems built today
are constrained by power consumption,
thermals, or both.
Among today's consumer systems,
desktops deliver the highest performance
but consume the most power.
Notebooks trade off performance
for lower power,
making them portable.
As you can see,
normally to get more performance
you have to consume more power.
When you take a closer look at this chart,
you realize you want to operate
in the upper-left corner.
You want to deliver
the highest performance
at the lowest power consumption.
And that's exactly
where we want to take the Mac.
Building up on our years of experience
designing the world's
most energy-efficient chips,
our plan is to give the Mac
a much higher level of performance
while at the same time
consuming less power.
So, much better performance
is reason enough
to transition the Mac to Apple SoCs.
But that's just part of the story.
Our scalable architecture includes
many custom technologies
that when integrated with our software
will bring even more innovation
to the Mac.
With our advanced power management,
we will maximize performance
and battery life
better than ever before.
Our Secure Enclave will bring
best-in-class security,
and our high-performance GPU
is going to bring a whole new level
of graphics performance to every Mac,
making them even better
for Pro Applications
and really great for games.
And combined with our neural engines,
our chips will make the Mac
an amazing platform for machine learning.
And we're bringing
many other custom technologies,
such as our video-display
and image-processing engines,
that will help make the Mac
better than ever before.
So, what does all of this mean
for the Mac?
First, we're designing a family of SoCs
specifically for the Mac product line.
Second, just like we did
with the iPhone, iPad and Watch,
we're going to bring
great technologies to the Mac.
This will give the Mac
a unique set of features
and incredible performance.
And third, we'll have
a common architecture
across all of our product lines,
making it far easier for developers
to write and optimize software
for the entire Apple ecosystem.
Ultimately we know
that bringing our SoCs to the Mac
will allow us to build
much better products,
and the Mac will take
another huge leap forward.
Now, a key advantage we have
is the tight integration
of our silicon with our software.
To tell you more about
how macOS will run on Apple SoCs,
here is my colleague, Craig.
Thanks, Johny.
Now let's talk about the technologies
that we've built into macOS Big Sur
that will make the transition
to Apple Silicon smooth and seamless
for both consumers and developers.
These new Mac systems will be incredible,
and users will want their favorite apps
to take full advantage of the capabilities
of our custom silicon.
And the best way to do that
is with native apps.
So of course when we updated
our apps for Big Sur,
we built everything as native
for Apple Silicon.
And I'm happy to say we have
all of our own Apple apps,
including our most demanding Pro Apps
like Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro,
up and running as native now,
and they'll be ready for customers
on day one.
So, how did we do this?
We're using Xcode,
just like all our developers will.
Everything developers need
to build apps for these new chips
is built into the new version of Xcode.
To get started, developers just open
their app projects and recompile.
The vast majority of developers
can get their apps up and running
in just a matter of days.
And to deliver these apps,
we've created Universal 2.
It's a new type of Universal binary
that works on both Intel-based Macs
and Macs built on Apple Silicon.
So developers can tap into the native
power and performance of our new Macs
and still support Intel-based Macs,
all with a single binary
for all of their users.
Some of the biggest Mac developers
have already gotten started.
Microsoft is hard at work
on Office for the Mac.
And we've been working with Adobe
on their flagship Creative Cloud,
and many of their apps
are already up and running great.
So let's take a look at macOS
running on Apple Silicon.
So here we are on the desktop
that we know and love.
And I'm just gonna open up About This Mac.
And what you see here is that we are
running on our Apple Development Platform.
This is a system built
to support early development
using the same A12Z processor
currently shipping in iPad Pro.
Now, I have a confession to make.
This isn't the first time
you've seen macOS running here.
In fact, this is the same Mac
that Beth and I used to demo
all the new Big Sur features earlier.
And as you saw earlier,
we've updated all of our Apple apps
and they're running great.
Of course, a big part
of the Mac experience is third-party apps,
and we've been working
with our friends at Microsoft,
and they already have Office
up and running natively on our new Macs.
Let's take a look at Word.
It runs great.
Scrolling is super smooth.
Everything you do
is just super responsive.
Next let's check out Excel.
Just as you'd expect,
complex sheets and elements like this map
all update instantly.
And next let's take a look at PowerPoint.
It's using Metal for rendering,
and it performs great.
For instance, check out how I can see
all the layers of my slide in 3D.
The animation is perfectly fluid.
Now, we've also been working closely
with our friends at Adobe
to bring Creative Cloud to our new Macs.
Here's Lightroom
running native on Apple Silicon.
Navigating large libraries of DNG images
is super fast,
and all of Lightroom's editing controls
are available right here.
Let's apply an adjustment to this image.
Well, that's much better.
And we can apply that same edit
to all of these images in a single step.
Looks great.
Next, let me show you the app
I know many of you wanna see:
Photoshop.
Here is a five-gigabyte Photoshop file
by photographer Stephen Wilkes.
Now this is a heavy-duty document
with lots of layers.
Now let's add one more bird in there.
Not totally comfortable with the level of
social distancing, but let's keep going.
And let's check out
how smooth the animation is as I zoom out.
Wow. Beautiful.
Finally, let's turn to
one of our most sophisticated apps:
Final Cut Pro.
Here it is running on Apple Silicon
for the first time.
Let's play back some 4K video.
As you can see, playback is super smooth.
And all your filters are here,
and you can apply them in real time.
Let's try some color correction.
And I can even add
animated titles and lens flare...
all during live playback.
And Final Cut takes advantage
of the unique capabilities
of the Apple Neural Engine
with a new feature that analyzes video
and intelligently crops it
to keep the most important action
in the frame.
But that's not all.
Final Cut fully exploits
the system's multicore architecture
to let us play back not just one or two,
but three streams
of full-resolution 4K ProRes,
all on an A12Z processor.
Amazing.
So that's a first look
at Universal apps on Apple Silicon.
We're really excited to see
so much great work on native apps.
These apps even get more amazing
when they're built to take advantage of
the Silicon's powerful capabilities.
Like its incredible
CPU and graphics performance,
a unified memory architecture
and the Neural Engine
which accelerates
advanced machine-learning tasks.
The transition to Apple Silicon
is also great for developers
who've already optimized their apps
for other Apple platforms.
The shared architecture
across our products
means that their code
will absolutely sing on our new Macs.
And there's even more to the story.
We're doing some really important things
to make this transition
seamless for our users.
Now, while we expect most developers
will go native immediately,
we wanna make sure that users
can run all of their apps on day one,
even if some apps
haven't yet been updated.
Now, we've been down this road before.
When we transitioned
from PowerPC to Intel processors,
a cornerstone of that transition
was Rosetta,
a technology that makes it possible
to run PowerPC apps on Intel-based Macs.
macOS Big Sur will include
a new version of Rosetta, Rosetta 2.
Rosetta 2 automatically
translates your existing Mac apps
so they work on new Macs
with Apple Silicon.
And this time Rosetta is even faster,
more powerful and more compatible.
It translates the apps
when you install them,
so they can launch immediately
and be instantly responsive.
And Rosetta 2 can also
translate code on the fly when needed,
like for web browsers with just-in-time
JavaScript compilers or for Java code.
It even handles the most complex
Pro Apps and their plug-ins.
Rosetta 2 is transparent to users,
and the performance is amazing.
We're also introducing new Virtualization
technologies in macOS Big Sur.
So, for developers who wanna run
other environments like Linux
or tools like Docker, we have you covered.
When you put
all of these technologies together,
Universal, Rosetta and Virtualization,
you have a system that can run
an amazing diversity of apps.
To show you how this all comes together,
I'll hand it over to Andreas Wendker.
Thanks, Craig.
Let's take a look at some existing apps
running under Rosetta.
Rosetta, of course, works great with
all sorts of apps you use every day.
But for our first demo, I'd like to
show you something a bit more challenging.
This is Maya, the powerful animation
and modeling software
running great here on Apple Silicon.
I already have a model open that consists
of over six million polygons
and, as you can see,
I can fluidly move around in this scene.
So let's make it more challenging
and bring in textures and shaders as well.
And still, everything is incredibly fluid.
So Rosetta works great,
and the performance is simply fantastic.
But Rosetta isn't just for apps.
It also works amazingly well with games.
I can even use a game controller.
This is Shadow of the Tomb Raider,
a high-end AAA game
that's using our Metal APIs.
I downloaded it directly from
the Mac App Store,
so it's completely unmodified,
and it is absolutely beautiful.
Let me jump into the water.
You can see
some of the lighting effects here.
And as I follow the path,
you can see the game is responsive,
it's smooth,
and the best part is, you're running
the 1080p as a translated app
and an emulation.
So these new Macs, they are fast.
You can see
some more of the lighting effects here.
It's awesome what Rosetta can do
with existing games.
Now, as Craig mentioned, many of our users
rely on apps from other environments.
So let me bring up a Linux VM
in Parallels Desktop.
You can see the graphical user interface
designed for Linux here.
But, of course, many developers
like to use Linux for hosting servers.
So let me dive down to the command line
and launch in Apache Web Server.
And now I can simply bring up Safari
and browse the website of the server
I just launched in the Linux VM.
Here it is.
Now I want to show you one more
type of app to run on these new Macs
that we haven't even told you about yet,
and that is iPhone and iPad apps.
Since they've been built
to run on the same Apple Silicon
that we're using on our new Macs,
they will run natively,
completely unmodified,
on the new Macs as well.
Let me show you a few.
This here is one of my favorite games,
Monument Valley 2.
It's fun to play here on the new Mac.
And if I want to catch up on my
guitar lessons, I can use Fender Play.
[guitar plays]
Or if I want to relax
at the end of the day a little bit,
I can bring up the Calm app.
And that was just a quick look
at Rosetta, Virtualization
and support for iPhone and iPad apps,
giving users amazing versatility
for running apps and other environments
with macOS on Apple Silicon.
Back to you, Craig.
Thanks, Andreas.
As you saw,
Macs built with Apple Silicon will be able
to run iPhone and iPad apps directly.
Starting day one, users can download
these apps right from the Mac App Store,
and most apps will just work
with no changes from the developer.
With everything we're doing,
the range of apps that users
will be able to run on these new Macs
is truly unprecedented.
Together, we have all the technologies in
place to make this an amazing transition.
The vast majority of Mac apps
can be recompiled as Universal
in a few days,
so users can have fast, native apps.
Rosetta 2 runs existing Mac apps,
our Virtualization technology
makes it easier than ever
to bring other environments,
like Linux, to the Mac,
and Mac users can, for the first time,
run iOS and iPadOS apps directly,
tapping into
the world's most vital app ecosystem.
Now, we know our Mac developers will be
eager to get started on this new platform.
So to get them going right away,
we're launching a Quick Start Program.
The focus of the Quick Start Program
is to enable developers
to make their apps Universal
and take advantage
of all the capabilities of Apple Silicon.
Developers will have access to
documentation and sample code,
forums on developer.apple.com,
priority DTS support incidents,
and access to labs around the world.
This program also includes
new Developer Transition Kit hardware
so developers can get going
even before we ship production systems.
The DTK hardware
takes the form of a Mac mini,
but one with an A12Z SoC inside.
It has desktop specs,
including 16 gigabytes of memory,
a 512-gig SSD,
and a complement of Mac I/O ports.
Most significantly, it will include
the macOS Big Sur developer beta
and Xcode tools.
Developers will be able to apply
to the program
at developer.apple.com today.
We will be shipping units out
starting this week
so you can get to work.
So that's how macOS Big Sur
is paving the way
for a smooth transition to Apple Silicon.
This year, we're elevating the Mac
to a whole new level.
And it's an incredible opportunity
for developers.
I can't wait to see what you all create,
and I can't wait until
we can all be together in person again.
And now, back to Tim.
Thank you, Craig, and thank you, Johny.
It truly is a historic day for the Mac.
Our vision for the Mac
has always been about
embracing breakthrough innovation
and having the courage
to make bold changes.
Every time we've done this, the Mac
has come out stronger and more capable.
And I have never been more confident
about the future of the Mac
than I am today.
So, what's the timeline
for this transition?
Well, for developers,
it begins this week with
the valuable information
delivered at this conference as well as
applying for the Quick Start Program.
And for the customers,
we expect to ship our first Mac with
Apple Silicon by the end of this year,
and we expect the transition
to take about two years.
We plan to continue to support and release
new versions of macOS
for Intel-based Macs for years to come.
In fact, we have some new Intel-based Macs
in the pipeline
that we're really excited about.
What a huge leap forward for the Mac
and for Apple.
Apple Silicon will bring
amazing technologies,
industry-leading performance,
and a common architecture
across all of our products.
What an incredible day of announcements.
As you've seen,
we haven't stopped innovating.
We pushed all of our platforms forward
in some amazing new ways.
Our OS releases will be available
as developer betas today.
And each of them will have a public beta,
including watchOS for the very first time,
starting next month.
And all of this great software will be
available to our customers this fall.
We hope you've enjoyed
this very special keynote
and that you're ready
for the big week ahead,
with over 100
engineering-led video sessions,
one-on-one consultations
with Apple engineers,
and so much more.
We can't wait
to start working with all of you
and watch you do
the best work of your lives.
At Apple, we've always drawn strength
from the diversity of our global community
because we truly believe
when we all work together,
we can change the world for the better.
Thanks to you all for joining us.
This has been such a big day,
and it's only the beginning
of a huge week to come.
So let's have a great WWDC.
["Daydreamer" by Aurora playing]
[song fades]