DUFF: 12 of America's
best young bakers
are proving that age
is just a number.
-VALERIE: It smells like heaven.
-Absolutely stunning.
This just looks like
a taste adventure.
Yay!
Oh.
-Nailed it.
-Who will go from bake sales...
*
It looks exactly like
a baloney sandwich.
Dude, you're messing
with my head!
-[ Giggles ]
-VALERIE: To baking champion.
GIRL: Awesome.
No laughing.
[ Laughter ]
DUFF:
And take home 25,000 bucks.
-Whoa.
-Yes!
This is...
BOTH:
"Kids Baking Championship."
**
-[ Squeals ]
-Oh, my gosh.
Oh, this is so cool.
-This is crazy.
Duff and Valerie
are gonna be here.
-I know.
-Wow.
Listen to them.
They are so excited.
Uh-huh.
They cannot wait for all this
to start.
-You want to do this?
-Yes. Okay?
-Let's go in.
-I have, like, goose bumps.
I'm gonna cry. [ Gasps ]
Oh, my gosh!
When I see Duff,
I was about to, like, happy cry,
but then I thought to myself
this is national television.
-No crying.
-Hey, guys.
Welcome to
the "Kids Baking Championship."
[ Cheers and laughter ]
Are you guys ready to flex
your baking muscles?
-Yeah.
-Let's see 'em. Let's see 'em.
Oh, yeah. Look at these guns.
[ Laughter ]
This is Duff Goldman.
-I am Valerie Bertinelli.
-Hi.
We are here for you.
And you're here
to win $25,000.
[ Cheering ]
You know how much
you can do with that?
You can buy like...
I don't know.
Something really expensive.
DUFF: And the title of...
BOTH: Kids Baking Champion!
[ Cheering ]
I need your help
solving a puzzle.
Oh, my gosh. No.
What? What?
I can see all your brains
working.
Thought I smelled
something burning.
[ Laughter ]
I love cookies,
and I love cake.
Put 'em together, it's like
one extraordinary dessert.
-Cookie plus cake equals?
-KIDS: Cookie cake!
-Good job.
-I like that algebra.
[ Laughter ]
Me too.
So, for this challenge,
you guys
have two hours to bake
and decorate
a layer cookie cake.
You know, Val,
I feel like we gotta
throw something else at 'em.
-KIDS: No.
Or maybe they gotta
throw something.
-Better.
-I knew it. I knew it.
GIRL: Oh, wow.
KIDS: Ohh!
All right, guys.
If your cookie disc
lands in the cake,
you receive an advantage.
All right.
Grady, first up.
-Ooh!
-All right.
-Come on, Grady.
GIRL: Come on. You can do it!
**
-KIDS: Oh!
-VALERIE: Close, Grady. Close.
Super close.
-Come on up, Julia.
-DUFF: Let's see it.
Yeah! Nice.
[ Cheering ]
Right in the middle.
All right.
There's one.
-You got this.
-Come on. You got it.
-Got to do this.
-Do it.
-Let's do this.
Have to be precise, eh?
Here we go.
Hey, those are
expensive shoes.
These are brand-new shoes, man.
[ Laughter ]
**
-Right into the camera crew.
-You guys all right?
[ Laughter ]
Looks good.
Oh!
ALL: Oh!
Oh! Oh!
-Sorry.
-[ Laughs ] All right.
So, we have
one advantage winner.
That's Julia.
Good job, Julia.
[ Applause ]
You get to choose
which type of cookie
you're gonna make
for your cookie cake.
There's 12 of you guys,
but only 6 options --
sugar, peanut butter,
chocolate, chocolate chip,
oatmeal raisin,
or snickerdoodle.
You can add so much
to chocolate chip,
so I'll go with that.
-Right on.
BOTH: Okay.
-Chocolate chip. It's yours.
-It's all yours.
Now, for the rest of you,
when time starts, it's a
random grab to pick your cookie.
All right, bakers.
2 hours,
layer cookie cakes,
and your baking time
starts...
**
BOTH: Now!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
[ Laughter,
all shouting at once ]
DUFF: Savages!
[ Laughter ]
Two hours is not enough time
to make cookie cake.
You need like 700 hours,
and those take forever.
Um, maybe I should
do a double batch.
Cookies cakes aren't
like regular cookies,
because cookie cakes
have to be sturdy,
so that you can
structurally pile them up,
and that kind of makes it hard,
'cause the ratios are
a little bit different,
but nothing that
I can't pull off.
I'm a cookie cake pro.
[ Giggles ]
**
My name is Abby.
I'm 13 years old,
and I'm
from Franklin, Wisconsin.
I gotta support
the cheese state.
Hello, Wisconsinites.
[ Bell dings ]
I also want to prove that great
things come in small packages,
because I'm short,
but I'm great.
I love baking because it lets me
be a perfectionist,
'cause I am quite
the perfectionist
and it just makes me so happy.
[ Giggles ]
Perfect. Get 'er going.
I'm making
a chocolate cookie cake
with a cookies and cream
buttercream.
I gotta get one of these.
I decided to do this
because my baked goods
are usually inspired
by different ice cream flavors
'cause I know that
those combinations work well.
That'll be good.
And chocolate, of course,
goes with cookies and cream.
Cookie dough is my favorite.
Awesome.
-Hey, Val.
-What?
What kind of keys do kids
like to carry around?
-Yeah.
-I don't know. What kind?
Cookies.
[ Laughter ]
Don't run away, eggs.
My name is Luke, and I'm
13 years old and I'm from
Rancho San Margarita,
California.
Other than baking,
I like to play baseball
and I like making short films
in my neighborhood
with my neighbors.
And like now I'm here.
It's like all the camera gear
and stuff --
it just looks so cool.
That was a lot of butter.
Today I'm going to make
a chocolate chip cookie cake
with Neapolitan frosting.
A chocolate chip cookie cake
is pretty bland on itself,
like super plain,
so adding all the three flavors
from the Neapolitan
will add a lot more spice to it.
-Aah!
-Nice, Luke.
Oh, yeah.
So, after I put my cookies
in the oven
I'm starting on my frosting.
I mix my butter, powdered sugar,
and a little bit
of vanilla extract
and then I separate
the buttercream
into three different bowls,
so one I left plain
as the vanilla.
The other one I add cocoa powder
to make it chocolate
and then the third one
I add strawberry puree
to make it strawberry.
-Time, please?
-15 minutes gone.
-1 hour and 45 minutes left.
-Oh, my gosh.
[ Clatter ]
Aah!
Oopsies.
I never made a batch this big.
[ Grunts ] Ah, here we go.
My name is Linsey Lam.
I am 13 years old and I am
from Closter, New Jersey.
I'm obsessed with baking
and competitive gymnastics.
If I won and got
the prize money,
I'm going to...well, taxes.
My dad told me about taxes.
Those aren't good.
Anyway, if unicorns did exist,
I would get a unicorn.
Yes.
That was messy.
-Chocolate.
-Yeah.
If you're not making a mess,
you're not doing it right.
[ Laughs ]
I'm making a dark chocolate
cookie cake
with strawberry buttercream
and a chocolate
hazelnut ganache.
Okay, we're good.
Oh, my God.
I'm already covered in flour.
Typical me.
Hi. I'm Beverly.
I am 10 years old and I
live in Foster City, California.
I have a baking business
called Baked by Beverly
and, I mean, it's just
amazing being here.
I am so excited!
#soexcited.
[ Screams, grunts ]
Ahh.
This is typical
Beverly behavior, so no worries.
I'm just cuckoo. [ Laughs ]
Shakeity, shake, shake,
shake, shake, shake, shake.
#shakeit.
Whoo, now I'm dizzy.
I'm making
a snickerdoodle cookie cake
with maple cream cheese
frosting.
Yummy cookie dough.
Now I just need to add
all my cinnamon sugar.
It is a snickerdoodle,
after all.
Otherwise it would just be
an ordinary cookie.
#imgoingintheoven. [ Giggles ]
-How is everybody doing?
-Good.
Looks light, looks fluffy,
looks delicious.
Hello. My name's Alex.
I'm 12 years old, and I
live in Edmonton, Alberta.
I'm so happy that I'm
the first Canadian
on "Kids Baking Championship"
because first, like, wow!
And also I want to prove
that people from Canada
can bake just as well
as Americans can.
I have done some fine things
in my day.
I've done soufflé, crème brûlée.
I've actually done
sacher tortes before,
some extraordinary things, and
when I win, I'm gonna get a dog,
if my dad lets me.
I'm not making just
a sugar cookie.
I'm making a lemon raspberry
sugar cookie cake.
Valerie loves lemons,
and I love raspberries,
and why not put those
two inspirations together
and make a delicious
lemon raspberry sugar cookie?
Perfect.
I think putting 'em
on a sheet tray
will make them bake faster
than in a cake pan,
so it can cook in time to cool.
Going in.
-How much time do we have left?
90 minutes left, guys.
-Oh, God.
-Ooh.
Time went by pretty fast.
-Is that the cinnamon?
-Yeah.
-Can I have it?
-Sure.
Thank you.
My name is Aditya.
I'm 12 years old, and I
live in North Carolina.
I taught myself to bake
by watching videos online
and I am a vegetarian,
but I'm not a vegan,
so I can use, like,
dairy products in my baking.
Can I take these both from you?
-Um, yeah, you can borrow them.
-Okay.
I'm making a spiced
oatmeal raisin cookie cake
with spiced buttercream.
Look at all those
spices Aditya is using --
nutmeg, allspice, cinnamon.
Num.
Yeah, I just hope he has
an even hand in using 'em.
Yeah.
I love all those spices.
I do, too, but sometimes these
kids like to go a little...
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-"If I put more, I'll win."
-Yeah. [ Laughs ]
-[ Laughs ]
Usually I would bake
a cookie cake in a cake pan,
but all the other kids
have them,
so I just get
a parchment-lined baking sheet
and I, like, press
the dough onto it
and use one of those
cake circles as a guideline
and I try to be as
even as possible, too.
-Hey, Alex.
-Yeah?
-How'd your cookie turn out?
-Ah.
Ow. That's hot.
-Ouch.
-You okay?
I burned myself.
Ow, my hand.
Ah, I don't know
if I can continue.
Ah.
**
You okay?
-Oh, God, my hand hurts.
-GIRL: You okay, Alex?
Ouch. I just burned myself.
I'm feeling like I'm about
to give up. Um...
Okay.
**
-I have to make sure that...
-Hurts.
Yeah.
Yeah. I can do it.
[ Exhales deeply ]
Yeah.
After talking to my dad,
I'm feeling so much better.
I cannot give up.
I have to finish.
I have to finish,
or else I will be going home.
Alex, hang in there, man.
-You're tough.
-No big deal.
I have learned the importance
of oven mitts,
to always have them in my hands
whenever I'm grabbing a tray.
Well, let's continue, eh?
-Hour and 15 left.
-Oh, my gosh.
Cookie cakes we can't
wait to taste.
Let's hope so.
Oh, oops.
-I saw that.
-[ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
I'm Bryn. I'm 11 years old,
and I live
in South Hill, Virginia.
[ Club hits ball ]
I like to golf,
and I like to bake.
My baking business
is called These Sweets,
and I specialize in, like,
desserts for celebrations,
birthday parties, graduations,
all that kind of fun stuff.
I'm making
a snickerdoodle cookie cake
with vanilla frosting,
and I'm going to use my Mimi's
famous sugar cookie recipe
and just add the cinnamon sugar
and brown sugar coating.
How's everybody doing?
Good.
Careful, careful, careful.
**
Let's go.
My name is Michael.
I'm 11 years old, and I
live in Bowie, Maryland.
Other than baking,
I like music and photography.
I like experimenting with new
flavors and combinations,
and that's what's gonna make me
stand out from all the rest.
I don't want to make
a traditional
peanut butter cookie.
I want to make something
different, unique,
so I'm gonna make
the same thing I use
for a chocolate chip cookie,
but instead of using
chocolate chips,
I'm using peanut butter chips.
Mise en place.
The first thing I get started on
is the mise en place,
which just means
I measure out everything
and put them in little cups
and then when I want
to start assembling everything,
all I have to do
is reach over and grab the cup,
put it in there, reach over,
grab the cup, put it in there.
But it's taking a really
long time,
and I feel like
I'm never gonna get this done.
Come on, Michael.
Let's do this thing.
I'm making
a chocolate chip cookie
with pecans in it and
a salted caramel buttercream.
I heard that Valerie likes
pecans in chocolate chip cookies
and so, even though
this is a cookie challenge,
I hope my pecans win me
brownie points with Valerie.
That's something
my dad would say.
He's really cheesy.
[ Laughs ]
I'm Julia Betz.
I'm 12 years old, and I
live on an island near Miami
called Key Biscayne.
I have a photographic memory,
and it helps me a lot in baking.
I love how baking lets me
put my art, design,
and math skills to use.
That's a workout.
It's so thick.
Now I need to get started on
my salted caramel buttercream.
I slowly add in the heavy cream
to the sugar mixture as soon
as it turns golden brown
and then, after that,
it cools a little bit,
so I start to slowly add
that into my buttercream.
Good.
DUFF:
1 hour for cookie cake!
Oh, boy.
[ Whirring ]
Oh, where's that peanuts?
This is!
[ Rattles ]
Yes.
My name is Grady Holloway.
I'm 11 years old, and I live
in St. Louis, Missouri.
[ Drums beating ]
I play drums and ukulele,
but baking is my jam.
I'm sort of addicted to baking.
I'm not like actually
addicted to it,
but I like doing it,
like, all the time.
I want to win
"Kids Baking Championship"
so bad.
I really want chickens, but
my dad says I can't have 'em,
but maybe winning this,
maybe he'll let me have 'em.
Right now I'm thinking
about what goes good
with peanut butter.
I'm making a peanut butter
cookie cake with vanilla
and chocolate frosting
and smoked peanuts.
So I add in my little wood
pieces, and I light it.
Put your tube inside
of your plastic wrap
and smoke goes like...
[ Imitates flame whooshing ]
Smoking stuff is kind of fun.
I really wanted to make
my chocolate chip cookie,
but I didn't end up getting it,
so I'm going to take a normal
chocolate chip cookie recipe,
but then just add
in peanut butter.
How's everyone doing?
-Good.
-You're making a double batch?
I'm not yet,
'cause it's a lot,
but I might have to
make more.
My name is Soleil,
and I am 12 years old
from Livingston, New Jersey.
I'm a competitive dancer,
and I also do pageants.
I love baking so much,
and I can't wait to add
"Kids Baking Championship"
to my wall of trophies.
So, what I'm making is
an oatmeal raisin cookie cake
and cinnamon frosting,
because I know that cinnamon
goes really well
with both of those flavors
and I want it to be
nice and cinnamon-y.
So, after I mix in the raisins,
I start to spread out my batter
onto one of my sheet trays.
And then I realize I really
don't have enough batter at all
to make my whole
entire cookie cake,
so I have to do that
whole process over again.
Is Soleil just starting
on her cookie batter?
-That's her second batch, right?
-I think so.
That really might eat
into her time,
but cookies don't take
a long time to cook.
Yeah, cookies don't take
Yeah, but these are...
You're right.
-Cookies.
-Yeah.
I'm a little bit worried
for the time,
but I think I'll be able
to pull it off.
DUFF: Bakers, can we have
your attention, please?
Oh, no. [ Laughs ]
-I forgot about this.
-Uh-oh.
You think they know
what's coming?
I think they do.
Oh, forgot about the twist.
DUFF: Okay, bakers, because
there's so many of you,
I can't keep
your names straight.
VALERIE:
So, for this twist,
you must put your name
on your cookie cake
in an edible way.
-Oh, no.
I'm looking around,
and everyone is way ahead of me
and I really don't have
time for any twists.
I don't have enough time.
I have my mise en place done,
but I don't have a dough.
Oh, Michael -- is he ever gonna
get a cookie in the oven?
I have no idea what I'm doing.
I have no idea.
You know what?
I want to go talk to him.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-How you feeling?
-I'm good.
What's going on?
Why are you crying?
Tell me. Tell me.
It's okay. We have time.
You have time, so tell me
what's going on.
I didn't get my dough in
and everyone else is already...
You know what?
That doesn't matter.
You're making cookies.
Cookies do not take
a long time in the oven.
-Yes.
-Okay, remember that.
-You got this. You got this.
-Mm.
I-I don't know.
He seems a little lost, like he
doesn't know what to do next.
-Right, right.
-Time!
45 minutes left.
[ Whirring ]
Oh, totally should
have gone off.
This timer isn't working? Huh.
Okay, they're still
on the jigglier side.
Hello, my name
is Gareth Bennett.
I'm 11 years old, and I'm
from Gaithersburg, Maryland.
[ Hockey stick whacks puck ]
Other than baking,
I play hockey and soccer
and I ran four triathlons,
and I've won two.
So you could say
I'm a little competitive.
I've only baked from scratch,
and all my stuff tastes great.
Okay, these are done.
My sugar cookie recipe
is a little bit softer
and moister
than most sugar cookies.
I take my first cookie cake
out of the pan.
No, no.
Shoot.
As I put it on the cake platter,
it just split in half.
No, no, no, no, no. Oh!
What is Gareth doing?
What? Oh.
The cake's crumbling.
Oh, no.
Gosh.
-30 minutes!
-What?!
No, no, no.
I look ridiculous.
**
-Oh, gosh.
-30 minutes!
-What?!
-We want our cookie cakes.
Oh, no. I look ridiculous.
Gareth, you got this, man.
You can do this.
I hope he can do this.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay, I can do this.
I can do this.
I don't have time to go back
and redo things.
I just have to keep on
moving forward with my cake.
Well, Gareth's making
a chocolate ganache.
-It's a good glue.
-Yeah. [ Laughs ]
-He's gonna need it.
-[ Laughs ]
I put a layer of chocolate
ganache,
and I tried to smoosh it
all into a remotely looking
cake form.
I just have to work.
It looks like he's going
with it, and he kinda has to.
Well, it's too late
to make another one.
Cracks, stick 'em
back together.
-Mm-hmm.
-Little frosting.
I know that my cookie
and my ganache taste good,
so I'm just gonna try to make
as many good decorations
as I can in this
amount of time.
"Gareth." "Gareth."
This isn't my best, but okay.
25 minutes!
Darn it.
I have my dough in my pans,
and I'm finally ready
to put them in the oven.
Come on. Bake.
Mm.
Okay, a couple more minutes.
It feels really moist --
moist and absolutely delicious.
Okay.
My hand is really bothering me,
so it's pretty hard
to do this piping.
Oh, it's crumbling.
So, I came in strong, confident,
and when this burnt hand came,
everything just went
into the drain.
I'm trying to piece it together.
I still need to write my name.
Oh, jeez.
Yet I don't have enough room
for the "X,"
so I just go with it.
It looks a little messy,
but I know it's gonna taste
really, really,
really, really good.
[ Gasps ] Perfect.
To decorate my cake,
I put a layer of my cookies
and cream buttercream
and I put a layer of
chocolate ganache in between.
Abby is putting her cookie
layers together with ganache.
A lot of ganache today.
-Why ga-not?
-[ Laughs ]
-Oh, ganache, I don't know.
I write in chocolate ganache
my name, Abby,
and it looks just perfect.
Good thing my name's short.
[ Gasps ]
A little piece of my cookie cake
broke off,
but it's not
that big of a deal.
Mmm!
Whoops. I had to taste it.
I hope Duff and Valerie
like the flavor
of my Neapolitan frostings.
Nice.
That looks good.
* 'Cause it's maple,
maple's yummy *
* I'm singing
and I don't know why *
-I love cream cheese frosting.
-Me too.
I'll put it on everything.
Steak.
Well, except that.
-Roast chicken?
-No, not that.
-Lasagna?
-[ Laughs ]
-So, I guess I lied. [ Laughs ]
Perfect.
Oh, no.
Oh, no. Not today.
Okay.
I'm going to decorate
my cookie cake
by adding a lot of sprinkles,
like a birthday cake,
just because birthday cakes
are fun and colorful.
For the twist, I melt down some
light pink coating chocolates
and write my name.
The reason that I wanted
to use coating chocolate
because I knew it dries really
fast and coating chocolate
will hold its shape.
I don't think
I cooked it enough.
Shoot.
Linsey's trying to
put her cake together
and her cookies
are falling apart.
Yeah, she looks
really worried.
[ Sighs ] It's a mess.
Ganache is spilling over
the edge and I'm trying
to soak it up with paper towels
and it's overflowing
and it's just a mess.
So, I'm gonna try and fix it
by just piping
on more frosting as a barrier
and taking more cake pieces
and placing it on top
and just covering
the entire cake in frosting
and hoping that nothing
leaks out anymore.
-It doesn't look that bad.
-Thanks.
Oh! Soleil almost
dropped her cookies.
**
[ Sighs ] Whew.
Thankfully, my cookies are done
and I didn't drop them.
For the twist,
it'll be really simple,
and I can just get it over with.
-Time?
-10 minutes left, everyone.
10 minutes for your first bake
and your cookie cake.
I put the first cookie
on the cake stand,
put on my salted caramel
buttercream,
then I take cookie,
buttercream, cookie,
and the last layer
of buttercream
and then I pipe my name
with the pink chocolate,
'cause I love pink.
You can never add
too many sprinkles.
Hee, hee, hee.
My cakes are cooled
and my buttercream's done,
so then I start
to frost my cakes,
and I feel like
I'm missing something,
and the cake seems
a little bit plain,
so I look in the pantry,
and I decide to add
crystallized ginger and raisins
in between the layers.
Yes.
Decorating my cookie cake, I put
a layer of vanilla frosting
and then I put a layer
of chocolate frosting.
Then I just stack like a bunch
of smoked peanuts on it.
It's perfect.
-Michael, you good?
-Uh...
I'm really worried
about Michael.
Do you want me to put
your icing in a piping bag?
-Yes, please.
-Michael, do you need any help?
Cavalry to the rescue.
VALERIE: Oh, I love it when
the bakers help each other.
-Is there a spatula?
-90 seconds!
Yeah!
Quick, help me.
90 seconds. A minute and a half.
-Oh, my God.
-I don't think I've ever seen
that many bakers
at one station before.
Yes.
I don't think that there's
gonna be enough room.
Do you want to try
your initials, maybe?
Come on, Michael!
Get it done.
-You can do this!
-You got it.
DUFF AND VALERIE:
9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1.
Hands up! Hands up!
I've always wanted to do that.
Good job.
[ Applause ]
Yay! Thank the Lord.
VALERIE:
Congratulations, bakers.
You just finished
your first bake.
-Oh, yeah.
-I believe to never give up
'cause you can never succeed
if you were to give up, right?
**
-So, Val, cookie cakes...
-Mm-hmm.
And they had to put
their name on top.
I think we're geniuses.
That makes one of us.
[ Laughter ]
Beverly, come on in.
What's up, kid?
Nothing much,
except for the ceiling.
[ Laughter ]
So, explain to us
what you made for us.
Well, it's a giant
snickerdoodle cookie
with maple cream
cheese frosting.
Mm.
That sounds delicious.
Maple.
I tell you, man, it is
super straight, super clean.
The thing I like about it
is that, even though we know
it's made of cookies,
it looks exactly like a cake.
Yeah.
And if you didn't know there
were cookies in there...
That's true.
...you'd be like look
at this cool cake
and then you go to slice it,
you'd be what?
[ Imitates explosion ]
What? It's cookies?
[ Laughter ]
You need to be more animated.
I'm not quite getting the drift.
Mind blown.
[ Laughter ]
I love that you added a little
heart there with your name.
Wow, look at that.
It looks like a cookie.
-You know what's missing?
-What?
Bacon.
[ Laughter ]
Mmm. Mmm.
That cream cheese frosting
is delicious.
-Mm-hmm.
-Thank you.
I don't taste
a lot of the maple,
but the cream cheese
tastes so yummy
and the snickerdoodle tastes
just like snickerdoodle.
-Thank you so much.
-Thanks, Beverly.
-Bye.
-Bye!
She's skipping.
Oh, my God!
[ Laughter ]
I love it.
**
-DUFF: Hi, Linsey.
-Hi.
Tell us what you made
for us today.
I made a dark chocolate
cookie cake
with a strawberry buttercream
and a hazelnut
chocolate ganache filling.
Let's talk about the
presentation of this beautiful
chocolate strawberry
cookie cake.
It's kinda beautiful.
Yeah, it looks like
it's a little...
-[ Makes squeaking sound]
-Squashed.
Yeah, it's like
somebody sat on it.
What happened?
It fell apart.
Gotcha.
And then I tried to like
piece it all back
together with the buttercream,
but you know.
And you know what?
Can I just say thank you
for not making excuses.
Thank you for just
telling us the truth.
-I love when kids are honest.
-I wouldn't have been.
[ Laughter ]
I love it.
Cut it.
I want to taste it.
Okay, okay, okay.
**
Oh, yeah.
-There you go.
-Mmm.
-I like when chocolate drips."
-[ Laughs ] Me too.
-Boy, do I love this frosting.
-Oh, thank you.
It's really tasty.
It's not overly sweet.
It's spongy like cake,
but it's crumbly like a cookie.
Yeah.
You know, it's really
interesting,
and it's really good.
-Thank you.
-DUFF: See you later.
All right, Luke.
Come on in.
-What's up, dude?
-Hi.
Tell us what you made for us.
Today I've made for you
a chocolate chip cookie cake
with Neapolitan frosting.
All right.
Well, this is gorgeous.
-Thank you.
-So, Chef,
tell me about what
happened right here.
Hoped we wouldn't notice?
I was taking it out of the pan
and just a little bit fell off.
-Oh, gotcha.
-Did you eat it?
[ Laughs ]
Maybe instead of eating it...
I should put it back.
Exactly. [ Laughs ]
It looked good.
I was hungry.
[ Laughter ]
Wow.
Look at all those
chocolate chips in there.
Nothing is more disappointing
when you think oh,
chocolate chip cookie
and you bite into it
and there's like three.
-Yeah.
-Come on.
I like a lot
of chocolate chips.
Me, too.
Oh, I love that vanilla
frosting and the strawberry.
Not too sweet.
Okay, here's
what's awesome -- you.
Because as a cookie cake,
with a cookie and a cake
and you stuck 'em together,
it's like you achieved
I think the perfect texture
for what this is.
-Thank you.
-But my problem
is I just wish the cookies
were half the size,
because it's so thick.
-Delicious cake.
Thank you. Thank you.
-Aditya, come on in.
-Hi.
Tell us what's
in your cake.
So, it's a oatmeal raisin
cookie cake
and I put some like cinnamon,
nutmeg, and all that.
That is one
killer cookie cake.
You know what?
I love how big it is.
Yeah.
You know, it's like...
It's a real cake.
And you didn't use a mold.
I mean, these are
free-form-baked, huge cookies.
Yeah.
Oh, it cuts good.
Oh, boy.
-Wow, look at that.
-Wow.
Oh, and I put candied ginger
in the middle and raisins.
What? You were just gonna
leave that out?
Not tell us?
I love a spicy cookie,
and when I mean spicy,
I mean all those great,
warm spices like
your cinnamon, your nutmeg.
-Jalapeños.
-[ Laughs ] No. No.
And I get the heat
from the ginger,
which is really, really nice.
The flavors in here
are perfection.
-Yeah. Thank you.
-Thank you.
Hey, Alex.
How's it going, buddy?
Good.
How's it going with you?
I'm pretty good.
So, let's see it.
Let's see the injury. Yeah.
-Now you're a real chef.
-Yeah.
You're not a chef
without scars.
-[ Laughs ]
-Thattaboy.
There you go.
So, tell us about
your cookie cake.
Okay, so I made
a lemon sugar cookie cake
with a raspberry frosting
and hope you enjoy.
It looks like you ran out
of room
when you were writing your name.
Yeah, I did.
So, the X is kind of over here
and then you covered it up
with a strawberry.
-Yeah.
-I don't know that I love
all the fruit all over it,
even though I love fruit.
Oh, okay.
I hope that it tastes
a lot better than it looks.
I think
the raspberry buttercream,
it's almost like a mousse.
-Ooh.
-And it's really good.
I'm not getting any lemon
in the cookie.
Oh.
Don't say the L word
unless you're gonna deliver,
because she's gonna be
all over you for it.
I think you might have
over-mixed your cookie
dough a little bit.
Oh?
Because it's not as tender
as I want a sugar cookie to be.
-Oh, okay.
-You know?
-All right. Ice it up.
-Thanks, Alex.
-Okay. Bye.
-See you, buddy.
How's it going, Michael?
Good.
So, tell us what you made
for us today.
I made a peanut butter
cookie cake...
Mmm.
and I used
a peanut butter buttercream.
So, you had to put your name
on it, an edible name.
Yes.
-I see a "Muh..."
-Muh?
-Yeah. [ Laughs ]
-Just here you go.
I got three-quarters of an "M:
and just here you go.
-Just get it on there.
-What happened, Michael?
I was trying to do
the "P" in my name.
Like I was trying
to do my initials
'cause I didn't have any time
to do my whole name
and it
just scattered everywhere.
Okay. So, you did not fulfill
that particular challenge,
but how does it taste?
Oh, yeah.
Wait a minute.
What's going on in here?
What's going on?
Hold on.
How'd you make this
peanut butter cookie dough?
I made just like a chocolate
chip cookie cake,
but instead of using
chocolate chips
I used peanut butter chips.
It's like a peanut butter
blondie cookie.
Perfect consistency, but --
but I just wish there was more
of a punch
of peanut butter, you know?
The frosting's very,
very sweet.
As soon as you put it
in your mouth,
it's like woo, that's sweet.
There's a lot of sugar in here.
Thanks a lot, Michael.
Thank you.
It's too sweet.
Aren't cakes supposed
to be sweet?
Wow.
I could have put up with
the sweetness of the cookie
had he pulled back
the sugar in the frosting.
-Or vice versa.
-No, the cookie needed to be.
-All right, Chef.
-[ Laughs ]
-[ Chuckles ]
-I was adamant, too. No.
**
You know, Duff, cookie cakes --
I think we're starting a trend.
Yeah, I think I'm gonna make
a million bucks off it, too.
Hey, Bryn.
How'd you do today?
It was crazy,
and it was surreal.
[ Laughs ]
How old are you?
-11.
-11?
I don't think I used the word
"surreal" when I was 11.
-No. [ Laughs ]
-[ Giggles ]
So, explain to us
what you made for us.
Well, today I made
a snickerdoodle cookie cake
and it's just regular vanilla
frosting with sprinkles inside.
-It's magical.
-It is. It's magical.
-I love it.
-I want a unicorn to pop out.
I want a unicorn
to pop out of it. Yes.
[ Laughter ]
I love the way you did
your name up there.
Thank you.
You know, you didn't, like,
just lay it down on the top.
You know, it's nice 'cause it's
almost like a rainbow, you know?
Well done.
It looks like
a festive birthday cake.
Thank you.
Will you make
my next birthday cake?
Totally.
I mean, I would do that.
I thought I was making
your next birthday cake.
[ Laughs ]
Are you trying
to take my job?
Um...maybe.
It's got that perfect
snickerdoodle consistency.
Maybe you could have put it up
a little notch on the cinnamon,
so you really know
it's a snickerdoodle.
It's delicious.
It's just not really
a snickerdoodle.
-It's more of just a cookie.
-Okay.
But man, it's cute.
-Thank you.
-Just like you.
-Thank you so much.
-Bye.
-How's it going, Grady?
-Good.
Going good?
So, tell us
what you made us today.
So, what you have here is
a peanut butter cookie cake
with a vanilla frosting
on the first layer
and a chocolate frosting
on the second layer,
with smoked peanuts.
-Did you say smoked peanuts?
-Uh-huh.
-How'd you smoke a peanut?
-I used a smoke gun.
-Really?
-You can smell it.
I don't know
that you taste it, though.
The thing about peanuts
is that peanuts
are really dense, right?
They're really hard,
really dense, so for something
that dense you kind of need
to smoke it for a little longer.
So, you made your name
out of coating chocolate?
Yes.
Cool. I like that it's 3D.
**
I'm kind of scared. You guys
are chewing it like "hmm."
-Hmm.
-Hmm. [ Giggles ]
It's delicious. But because
of the vanilla frosting
and the chocolate frosting,
it's kind of hiding a bit
of the peanut butter.
But this chocolate
peanut butter drizzle,
whatever you did here,
put it in a jar and sell it.
This is delicious.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Grady.
-See ya.
**
-What is that?
-Where?
-Oh, it looks like a nut.
-That was a nut.
-You look like a nut.
-We're very excited.
-[ Laughs ]
-Julia!
Hi.
So, tell us about
your cookie cake.
I made a chocolate chip
cookie cake with pecans
and a salted caramel
buttercream.
BOTH: What?
That sounds amazing.
-Thank you.
-VALERIE: Yum-mo.
Now, Julia, correct me
if I'm wrong.
You were the only one
that won the advantage, right?
Yes.
-And you picked chocolate chip.
-Yeah.
But then you got
a little creative with it.
Yeah, I thought pecans
would be good,
'cause I saw on one episode
that you like pecans
or something crunchy,
so I tried doing that.
-Are you trying to buy me?
-Yes.
[ Laughter ]
Well, listen, Julia.
I gotta tell you, man.
Your icing is on point.
Your rosettes are clean,
and they're even.
You know, it's got your name,
Julia, in pink.
It kind of matches
your apron.
Oh, it feels nice and dense
like a cookie.
Oh, yeah.
-Mmm.
-Get it in there.
Get it in there.
[ Taps table ]
I love that little crunch
of pecans in there.
The perfect amount
of chocolate chips in there.
I was really looking forward
to salted caramel, though,
and I don't taste
a lot of that.
You never have to worry about
another
chocolate chip cookie recipe
for the rest of your life.
[ Laughter ]
This is perfect.
Thank you so much.
-Thank you.
-VALERIE: Thank you.
Abby.
-How's it going, Abby?
-Awesome.
-Really?
-Tell us about your cake.
My cake
is a chocolate cookie cake
with a cookies and cream
buttercream.
You know, I saw that,
and I was like,
that looks like
cookies and cream.
Yes.
And that is so "Inception"
if you think about it.
Yeah.
Cookie cake,
cookies and cream buttercream.
[ Makes whooshing sound ]
Is your mind blown again?
-[ Imitates explosion ]
-[ Laughs ]
Blown. [ Laughs ]
**
That chocolate flavor
is so intense.
-Is it too much?
-No, no.
The cookie for me is a just
a tiny bit on the dry side.
But the cookies and cream
buttercream...
Yeah, yeah.
I like it.
I want to eat it all.
Yeah.
It's delicious.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-Bye.
See ya.
I love it.
Her hair is...
**
So, Soleil,
tell me about your cake.
So, I made
an oatmeal raisin cookie cake
with cinnamon buttercream.
You know what I like?
I think it looks like
a sand castle.
-Oh, I didn't see that.
-Doesn't it?
And "Soleil" is French
for sun, right?
Mm-hmm.
-Yeah.
-And the beach.
It's even sparkling
like the sand.
Yeah.
It's very, very pretty.
Mmm.
-Lots of raisins.
-Yeah, it looks good.
You know, Soleil,
tell me something.
What is in the buttercream?
Cinnamon and vanilla.
The cinnamon is the only
brown thing you put in there?
-Yeah.
-It's dark.
You didn't put coffee in there?
-No.
-Hmm.
**
-[ Whispers ] It's really good.
-Is it?
-Don't ruin it for me.
-Mm.
But...it builds.
-Uh-oh.
-It definitely builds.
Your cookie is delicious.
There is just a lot
of cinnamon in there.
-Thank you.
[ Coughs ] My breath is
super-fresh, though.
[ Exhales deeply ]
-[ Exhales deeply ] Hi.
-[ Laughs ]
-Hi.
-What's up, Gareth?
I'm okay.
[ Laughter ]
What happened?
[ Laughs ] It kind of
crumbled a little bit,
so I tried
to push it back together
with my chocolate ganache.
Yeah.
So, what are
the flavors in here?
Well, it's a sugar cookie.
There's chocolate ganache,
toasted almonds, and bananas.
Well, it kinda looks like
a banana kinda threw up.
[ Laughter ]
Look, when you
get right on top of it,
you can actually read "Gareth."
-Oh, good.
Right?
You can totally read it.
-All right.
-Thank you.
-Nice.
-You got that. You did it.
Yeah, I'm really hoping
that it tastes
a lot better than it looks.
Oh, okay. Yeah, me, too.
It's just as much of a quilt
on the inside.
Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
**
Wow, it's a very
tasty sugar cookie.
There's something going on
with that ganache.
I cannot figure it out.
-It's like soapy.
-I don't know.
-I'm not sure.
-What?
How many times did you
wash your hands
while you were making it?
[ Laughter ]
-What?
-Your hands are super-clean.
But that sugar cookie
is really good.
-Thanks, Gareth.
-Thank you.
-Huh. Okay.
-It's not bitter.
-No. It's --
-But it's soapy. It's weird.
**
Bakers, your cookie cakes
were imaginative and fun,
but three of you
really aced your cakes.
I said it.
[ Laughter ]
Julia, you used the advantage
to your advantage.
Your chocolate chip cookie cake
was right on point,
and the chocolate chip cookie
itself was really yummy.
Beverly, your snickerdoodle
cookie cake
looked and tasted the most
like a cookie
and your cream cheese frosting?
Utterly delicious.
Aditya, we really liked
the boldness of the ginger
and the spice
in your oatmeal cookie
and the layers looked really
cool, like giant cookies.
But one cookie cake
stacked up best.
That baker is...
Hey, what time you got?
[ Music warps down ]
-What?
-Oh. Let's see.
I don't know.
Do you wanna grab a coffee?
-Yeah, let's do it.
-Okay.
[ Laughter ]
That baker is Aditya.
-Congratulations.
-[ Laughs ]
[ Applause ]
This is really awesome,
but this is just week one.
I don't want to, like,
think, like,
oh, I won the first challenge.
I'm so great.
Because there's still
so much more to do.
Now, a few other smart cookies
did well enough
to keep you here
for another week.
[ Whispers ]
I'm shaking right now.
-Bryn.
-[ Whispers ] Good job, Bryn.
-Abby.
-[ Exhales deeply ]
Soleil...Luke.
[ Sighs ]
-Grady.
-[ Whispers ] Yes!
And...
**
-Linsey.
-[ Whispers ] Good job, Linsey.
-GIRL: Good job, Linsey.
-Unfortunately,
that leaves Alex,
Michael, and Gareth.
Please step forward, boys.
**
Alex, your lemon sugar
cookie cake fell short today.
The texture of your cookie
was off,
and you ran out room
writing your name.
Michael, your name wasn't
legible
on your peanut butter cookie
cake,
and your frosting and cookie
were both overly sweet.
Gareth, your sugar
cookie cake crumbled,
and the large chunks of banana
did not help your presentation.
[ Sighs ] Bakers,
it is always so hard
to lose one of you
this early in the competition.
You are each so talented,
or you wouldn't even be here.
Unfortunately, the baker
leaving us today is...
Michael.
-[ Gasps ]
-So sorry, man.
You're a cool kid.
You're an awesome baker.
We're sorry, Michael.
The best part of this
competition was finding
new friends who bake
just like me,
and I'm gonna miss everyone,
but I'm excited
to see my family.
DUFF" Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Ready to flex
your baking muscles?
KIDS: Yeah!
VALERIE: Bake and decorate
a layer cookie cake.
You must put your name
in an edible way.
I don't think that there's
going to be enough room.
Do you want to try
your initials maybe?
VALERIE: The flavors in here
are perfection.
DUFF: One cookie cake
stacked up best.
Aditya, congratulations.
[ Applause ]
[ Laughs ]
Like it fell out of a plane.
I'm not getting any lemon
in the cookie.
Oh.
-I got three-quarters...
-A half an "M."
...of a M and then just...
Here we go.
The baker leaving us today
is Michael.
**
Wow.
What the heck?
[ "La Donna è mobile" playing ]
BOY:
What is happening here?
I am thinking that it's going
to be a savory challenge.
BOY:
I'm confused. What is this?
-Welcome back, bakers.
-KIDS: Hi!
It is pizza day here on
"Kids Baking Championship."
I love pizza.
Wait a minute.
You know
what this pizza needs?
Sprinkles.
-What?
Has Duff lost his mind?
Why would you put sprinkles
on a pepperoni pizza?
-Are you crazy?
-It's going to be delicious.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, my God.
No way.
More?
-No!
-Ew!
Don't eat it! [ Giggles ]
**
You know what?
You're right.
This is going to be
kind of gross.
[ Laughter ]
You know what I think
you're looking for?
-What?
-Dessert pizza.
Yeah! Dessert pizza!
-[ Cheering ]
-No!
Dessert pizza is sweet pizza,
so it has to have a sweet crust
with sweet filling,
then sweet toppings,
and all the flavors have
to combine in perfect harmony.
You had 90 minutes to turn
pizza into a sweet treat.
And remember, you're baking
to stay in the competition.
Your baking time starts...
BOTH: Now!
**
They are going to love
this challenge!
It's going to be great,
man.
To make my pizza dough,
I'm going to make
a shortbread cookie
because, first of all,
it's super fast.
It's literally
three ingredients --
butter, flour, and sugar.
And second of all, it's good
at holding everything together.
And once this is in the oven,
I'm going to make
a raspberry coulis
and then
a cream-cheese frosting.
I feel like all the components
will balance out together.
This is a Grady bake shake.
**
You need to know
the exact amount of butter.
You have to have it perfect
for it to turn out well.
[ Sighs ]
Julia, how many ounces
is 12 tablespoons?
12 tablespoons? 6 ounces.
Okay. Thank you.
I am making a dessert pizza
with chocolate hazelnut spread
for the sauce,
strawberries and bananas
for the topping.
Now I've used those flavors
a lot in crepes
'cause they go
really well together,
and I've learned
after eating them.
I'm making a tar crust.
So in a food processor,
I put butter, flour, and sugar
and just pulse that
until it forms kind of,
like, a sticky dough.
I feel like a tar crust
is perfect for a pizza dough
because it's pretty thin and
crispy just like pizza crust.
**
In my town, there is
a pizza restaurant.
The slices are, like,
this big, like, that big.
Probably can't see my arms.
**
I'm sorry.
I love pizza, and I really,
really like apple pie.
Why not just make a pie
as my dessert pizza?
[ Whirring ]
Okay. We're done. We're done.
For my crust, I am making
a classic pie crust.
I'm using an actual,
like, pizza pan,
and I put that into the oven.
**
-Hey, Val.
-Hmm?
What did the boss say
to his pizza during the meeting?
I don't know.
There's mushroom
for improvement.
[ Laughs ]
Time?
15 minutes gone, bakers.
An hour and 15 minutes left.
Okay.
Today is all about
pizza sweetza.
I was in the top last week,
so I think that I kind of need
to live up to my name
doing this.
I can pull this off,
but I shouldn't get cocky.
No cockiness allowed.
Ooh, the chocolate's
starting to melt, too.
For my dessert pizza, I'm making
a brownie with melted chocolate.
I'm using unsweetened chocolate
for my brownie
'cause I don't like
super sweet brownies.
I melt my chocolate,
and then I combine it
with my sugar,
eggs, and vanilla,
then add my flour and salt.
It is taking a risk
by doing mostly all chocolate.
Chocolate, chocolate, chocolate!
No talking, chocolate!
Now I just need to start
on my ganache,
To represent pizza sauce,
I'm making two ganaches.
So I set up two double boilers
and pour milk chocolate into one
and white chocolate
into the other,
and I melt that down until
it's smooth like a ganache.
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm.
Stir, stir, stir.
DUFF:
One hour left, bakers!
Dessert pizza day!
-Can't wait.
-Yum.
[ Whirring ]
I do not want to mess up and be
in the bottom three again,
so I'm going to show
the world that I can bake
and to try to win the $25,000.
I'd probably buy stocks
to increase
the amount of the money,
and I'd save the rest for
college and buy a go-kart
so I can drive something around
in my driveway.
I'm making a dessert pizza
with pie crust,
raspberry buttercream,
and fresh raspberries.
I'm also going to zest lemons
and put the lemon zest
into my pie crust.
Lemon and raspberry
work well together.
**
You want to have cold butter
whenever you're
making pie crust,
so I'm just cutting
it into tubes
so it's easier
to incorporate it.
I get started on my extra
flaky pie crust.
At home, I always do it by hand,
and I don't really use
a food processor.
It's confusing to use,
so why would I use one?
I would break my pie dough.
Water.
My pie crust is going to be,
like, the crust
on my dessert pizza,
and then, on top,
I'm going to put some
dark-chocolate ganache,
marshmallows and graham cracker.
I want to do a s'mores
because I love s'mores,
so it's definitely
going to be amazing.
I was on the bottom last week.
I cannot afford to be
on the bottom again this week.
Going in the oven!
I have some stuff to prove.
I'm representing Canada,
and I really want to
win it for my country.
For my chocolate ganache,
I want to use dark chocolate
because I don't want all
the other s'mores components
to be overly sweet,
so I got 55% dark chocolate.
Look at how silky smooth
that is.
It's so tempting.
I could crush
an 18-inch pizza.
-You know what I mean?
-Oh, my God.
I could, too, but I'm not
going to tell anybody that.
[ Laughs ]
-I think you just did.
-Oops!
[ Laughter ]
**
I'm making
a caramel apple pie pizza.
You got this.
For the base of my pizza,
I'm going to use
a flaky pie-dough crust.
I've put down aluminum foil
and put some pie weights
in the middle.
I'm using pie weights
so when it bakes,
it'll only rise around the edges
like an actual pizza crust.
For my apple-pie filling...
Okay.
...I start cutting up
my apples,
and then I take a piping tip
and cut out the core.
A piping tip does the same thing
as a apple core,
so I put my apples
in the apple pie spice.
An apple pie spice
is just a mixture
of cinnamon, nutmeg, cloves.
There's chocolate, and I put it
in the cinnamon stuff.
**
Linsey, how'd your
pie crust turn out?
-Pretty good.
-That's good.
I feel like a lot of kids
are going to be making cookies
'cause that's really easy,
and a lot of them are going
to be doing pie crusts,
and I want to take
a harder way out,
so I decide to
a blondie pizza crust.
I want to use my great-grandma's
blondie recipe
'cause it's the best.
My great-grandma taught me
quite a bit about baking.
She was always trying to get us
to eat baked goods,
and she'd be like,
"Oh, just have one more cookie.
It'll be fine."
Going in the oven!
To represent the sauce
on the pizza,
I am making
a lemon cream cheese frosting.
-Aditya, what are you making?
-A snickerdoodle crust.
With cinnamon?
Um, no.
Oh.
I just feel like that would be
kind of weird without cinnamon.
It's just a sugar cookie.
I don't put cinnamon
'cause I was going
to be putting fruit on top.
I'm making a snickerdoodle
without the cinnamon
for the crust of the pizza.
I'm kind of experimenting
in the kitchen.
My favorite subject
in school is science.
I guess baking is science
because you're putting
different elements together
so that they turn
into a different thing.
I don't know. It's interesting.
I put my cookie crust
into the oven,
but since I'm making
a giant snickerdoodle,
I'm not sure
how long it'll take.
**
And for the toppings,
I'm making a salted caramel.
For the sauce of the pizza,
I'm making
a vanilla pastry cream
that'll impress the judges.
Next, pick it up!
Chef, can I have
a barbecue chicken pizza?
No!
Barbecue chicken?
Get outta here!
Chef, somebody wants
pineapple on their pizza.
-What should I do?
-Give it to 'em.
-I love pineapple.
-I love pineapple on my pizza.
-Pineapple's all right.
-Yeah.
How's everyone doing?
-Good. How are you?
-I'm good.
S'mores are one of
my favorite desserts,
so I really want to make
an interpretation of s'mores
on my dessert pizza.
I am making a sugar cookie
graham cracker crust
with chocolate ganache,
a marshmallow sauce,
raspberry coulis,
and toasted marshmallows on top.
**
I hope I can do as well
as I did last week.
I'm making a blondie crust
filled with lemon curd
and a raspberry frosting.
My inspiration behind
this dessert pizza is blondies
because Duff likes them,
lemons because
Valerie likes them,
and raspberry because I know it
goes with both of those things,
and I love pink.
Everything is pink.
I have a pink bike, pink mixer.
Look, even the bands
of my braces are pink.
Pink bedsheets, pink walls.
The only kind of sprinkles
I have in my house
are pink and only pink.
Normally, I would use cornstarch
in my lemon curd to thicken it,
but I decided not to because,
if I put it in the blast chiller
with the cornstarch,
it'd get too thick too quickly.
I hope that my lemon curd
will set up properly.
I'm concerned about Julia.
I mean, she's making
lemon curd, which I love.
-Mm-hmm.
-But it's very liquid-y-y.
I think it's too much butter,
not enough yolks.
Mm.
She's making a
lemon-butter sauce.
Yum. [ Laughs ]
Put a trout in there.
It'd be delicious. [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ]
**
45 minutes, guys!
The crust is kind of breaking
and just, like, crumbling,
and I see that
it needs more butter.
This is terrible.
**
What's going on?
Luke's having trouble.
**
LUKE: I just have to throw it
away and start over.
Oh, man. Luke just threw away
his whole crust.
**
DUFF: 40 minutes, guys,
4-0.
**
I've made this crust, like,
a million times,
and, of course, this one time,
it just completely fails.
**
Hi, Luke. Hey, buddy.
Okay.
What's going on?
Talk to me. Talk to me.
The first one that I put in
just completely cracked in half.
Okay. That's fine.
Start new.
You got plenty of dough.
You're going to
top this pizza.
If it cracks again,
leave it.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Calm down, Luke. Deep breaths.
You got this.
I'm just going to make a new
crust and fix it this time.
I'm doing my second crust by
hand so I can have a feel
of does it need more butter?
Does it need more flour?
Add more butter because
that's my problem last time.
The crust was too crumbly.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Gasps ]
My pie crust stuck
to the aluminum foil.
What can I do?
I'm trying really hard
not to cry right now.
[ Exhaling deeply ]
Oh, no Oh, no.
I'm in trouble.
There's no saving
this pie crust.
I'm just going to have
to start over.
You cannot have a pizza
without the crust,
so I make a whole new batch.
Bryn,
are you doing all right?
Eh.
-They're not going to like this.
-No. They are not.
I can't wait to see
their faces. Uh-oh.
**
[ Chuckles ]
--Oh, they see us coming.
Oh, no.
No, no, no. What?
Bakers, can I have
your attention, please?
KIDS: No.
No, no, no, no.
Dessert pizzas are great,
but you must also incorporate
something that belongs
on a real pizza.
What?
-Ugh.
-Ugh!
We have hot peppers,
basil, bacon...
Oh.
The bacon has my name on it.
...tomatoes,
or fresh ricotta.
VALERIE: First come,
first serve. Come on up.
I bolted straight for the basil.
Bacon. Bacon.
Ooh, ooh!
Remember, you guys
can sweeten...
-Bacon!
-...any of these things up.
DUFF: Yeah, yeah. Relax. Relax.
Chill. Chill.
I grabbed, like,
one entire bunch of basil.
Can I have the basil?
-All right.
-Here you go.
But then Bryn needed some,
so I just gave, you know,
some to her.
I was going to take it all,
but you know.
Basil is kind of a savory thing,
so if I candy it,
I might be able to turn it
into a sweet thing.
I decide to incorporate
the basil into my pecan crunch.
I'm going to sprinkle the crunch
on top of the pizza.
Linsey, what are you
doing with the basil?
I need an idea.
You can candy it
and just sprinkle it on top.
How do you candy it?
You just, like, put, like,
butter and sugar,
and then you cook it
and then it kind of, like,
caramelizes it.
Okay. Cool. Thanks.
I can just do that and get
the twist over with,
and I can sprinkle it
on top of my pizza.
Is that caramel sauce?
It's, like, candied basil.
I didn't know what
to do with it.
-It looks delicious.
-So Linsey helped me, so...
Hey, bakers. 30 minutes.
Dessert pizzas, 30 minutes,
or it's free.
**
It's hard having to add
something savory
into our dessert pizza,
but I did apple pie because
you can add so much stuff to it,
and it'll still taste great.
I grab the basil,
and I chop it up
and put it into
my apple mixture.
SOLEIL:
What did you grab?
I got basil!
So did I.
I think basil and raspberry
go pretty good together.
Since my raspberry coulis
is almost done,
I've add some basil right in...
That tastes good.
...and let it go over low heat
so it infuses a bit,
and I think it should be fine.
-What ingredient did you get?
-Basil.
I did basil, and I'm adding in
cream cheese frosting.
So I take the basil.
I chop it up, and I add that
into my frosting
and set that aside.
The basil in this is
actually pretty good.
Do you love this twist?
KIDS: No!
And there's a bacon
up here left over.
And somebody left a bacon.
You guys picked a vegetable
over bacon?
What kind of kids are you?
**
Time to make Duff proud.
I take a sheet pan,
lay my bacon pieces on it
and sprinkle some
brown sugar on top.
Bacon.
You know what my favorite food
in the world is, right?
-Bacon!
[ Laughs ]
Bacon's going in, 400.
Crispy bacon.
Totally taking a different turn.
Bacon and lemon don't
really go good together,
so now to represent
the sauce on my pizza,
I am making
maple cream cheese frosting
because maple goes
very well with bacon.
**
-Mmm.
-How you doing?
-Good.
I think I may
change my game plan.
Chocolate...
This twist is
a big setback for me.
Savory and sweet don't always
go together in some ways,
so I'll try to make this work.
So I'll scrap s'mores pizza.
I think maybe
a chocolate cream pizza.
For my twist,
I grab hot peppers.
I take out the seeds.
I kind of chop 'em up
so they're smaller,
so it's not, like, a big bite
of, like -- ah -- hot spice
and then put them into
my chocolate ganache.
I think it will go good
with chocolate
because spice and chocolate
go good together,
I think.
Okay. I need to get this spice
into my chocolate.
You need all of those
hot peppers?
-Because I ran out.
-Oh, you can grab one. Here.
Thank you.
I'm going to need some.
I'm just going to make
a spicy whipped cream.
I'm going to whip it with this,
and hopefully,
it will flavor it.
To make my spicy whipped cream,
I pour in heavy cream,
cinnamon, and nutmeg.
I'm only going to put a little
bit of these spices in because,
you know, I want that
hot pepper to be the star.
And I know that the seeds
are always
the hottest part of a pepper,
so I scrape those in
so to give it
a little heat and smokiness
and make it spicy.
I hate hot pepper.
Ah. I hate hot pepper.
**
The ricotta will make a really
nice addition to my buttercream,
and it'll make it
a lot creamier.
It won't really make me need to
start over or change my plans.
I taste my buttercream to see
if I can taste the ricotta.
More ricotta.
Oopsie-daisies. Okay.
**
My plan for using the twist
is to incorporate basil
into my frosting.
I'm going to do this by
cooking raspberry puree
and basil leaves together.
Then I'm going to sift them,
so I get out the basil leaves
and add that to
vanilla buttercream.
I have not used
this technique before,
but I have seen it
in some places in a cookbook,
so I'm hoping that it'll work.
I have everything almost ready.
I just have to grab...
I have to assemble mine.
Yeah. I'm assembling mine
right now.
Yeah.
Wait.
What item did you pick?
-Ricotta cheese.
-I picked basil.
Ricotta?
For my strawberries.
Oh, that's a good idea.
I know ricotta and strawberries
go well together
because I've seen it
in a commercial. [ Laughs ]
I'm putting my ricotta cheese
in a bowl,
and I'm just adding in
a little bit of sugar at a time.
I want the cheese to be sweet so
it'll go better with my fruit.
15 minutes, bakers!
-Whoo!
-Timer!
Ooh, bacon time.
I going to win this because
bacon will make me stand out,
but then I see this black mess.
That's going to
taste disgusting.
Hot.
I think that when I put
the brown sugar on the bacon,
it caramelized,
and then it burned.
Now I'm going to have
to start over.
**
I think
I'm going to remake it.
Bacon is the twist ingredient
that I have.
I can't serve it burned.
I can do this.
Go, Abby. Go, Abby.
Who's cooking bacon?
I smell it.
Yeah. I kind of burned it
a little bit.
Good thing I saved some.
This time, put the bacon on
with nothing on it.
VALERIE:
10 minutes, bakers!
There's 10 more minutes
left to your sweet pizza!
We're going to eatza
your pizza in 10 minutes!
**
Okay.
Try that again.
Somethin' smells good.
[ Sniffing ]
-Did you have the bacon?
-Yeah.
Where's all that bacon now?
**
It burned.
Ooh.
So you just threw away
perfectly good bacon?
**
I don't know if you ever
throw away bacon.
Someone call the cops,
the pork police.
-Yes.
-They're coming.
-[ Laughs ]
-They're going to get me.
All right. Good job, Abby.
Keep it up.
Thank you.
**
It's not sticking.
My crust looks great.
I put my apple mixture in,
and I put it back in the oven.
-What's up, Bryn?
-It's stressful.
It's stressful?
When I made my first crust,
the foil stuck to the pie crust,
so I had to remake it.
-It's all in the oven.
-Okay.
-You like pizza?
-Um...
I like pizza, but I don't know
if I will after this.
[ Laughs ]
**
Take my cookie out.
It's really, like,
puffy and stuff.
I'm adding my
vanilla pastry cream to my pizza
just like a pizza sauce,
and it's a lot thicker
than I want it to be.
I drizzle the whole thing
with salted caramel sauce.
There's no technique
to my decoration.
I'm just making sure that
everything gets on there.
I'm nervous.
I slowly pour on my lemon curd.
My lemon curd's too thin.
I thought the blast chiller
would've thickened it up.
I want to go all out
for presentation.
I start to pipe my
raspberry basil buttercream
in rings around the pizza.
I go to the pantry and grab
my signature pink sprinkles.
Julia's grabbing pink
from the pantry.
Big surprise.
I think she likes pink.
Last week,
I used pink sprinkles.
This week, I'm using
pink sprinkles,
and so that's
my new signature item.
The signature touch.
Time!
Five minutes!
-5 minutes!
What else can you do
to make your pizza amazing?
I spread my raspberry ricotta
buttercream out on my pie crust,
and then I make a raspberry "G"
because my name starts
with a "G"! [ Giggles ]
I don't want to make the same
mistake that I made last week,
so I'm not going to add anything
else onto the dessert pizza.
**
I spread out
my chocolate ganache,
and then,
after that's all spread out,
I put my crushed graham crackers
on top,
and then I start piping my
whipped cream on my pizza.
Look at how pretty that is.
Those strawberries just give
an extra pop of fruit.
Presentation is definitely
redemption from last week.
Some red sprinkles.
And then those red sprinkles
give it, like,
a nice little party to it.
This is pretty nice.
And I'm spilling everything
everywhere, typical me.
I pour
the white-chocolate ganache
and the milk-chocolate ganache
in little strips,
and then I keep going and
going and going and going,
and then I use a toothpick
and go wee, wee, wee, wee.
Then I put dollops
of the whipped cream.
Wish that these dollops
were a little neater.
SOLEIL: It's time to start
assembling my pizza.
My ganache is thinner
than I would like it to be,
and it looks so messy.
I'm going to put it
in the blast chiller
so that it firms up.
3 minutes, guys.
**
Ooh, beautiful.
VALERIE: And make your pizza
the best pizza.
Does it have enough bacon
on it?
[ Laughs ]
Bacon.
My bacon comes out perfect.
So I put a little row
of candied pecans.
I put a little row
of chopped bacon bits
and some pretzels because it
will add a nice texture
and saltiness to my dish.
Sweet and salty.
Luke, that's how you
slice bananas, man.
-Thank you.
-Nice.
I add on my little banana slices
on the chocolate hazelnut
spread.
Then I add strawberries,
so I do one plain strawberry,
one with the ricotta cheese.
That's good.
I decide to put the rest of my
ricotta cheese into a piping bag
and just pipe on
little rosettes all over
to add more cheese flavor.
I'm really happy about how
my dessert pizza looks.
I've placed down
raspberry coulis
and then
my basil cream cheese frosting.
Then I cut up some raspberries
and place them on top.
DUFF: 1 minute, bakers.
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Whispers ] Smells so good.
I start assembling
my apple pie pizza
with a candied pecan,
almond, and basil crunch.
I just take a handful of the
crunch and sprinkle that on top,
and I chop up whatever
left of the basil I have
and just sprinkle that
in the center.
I want to make sure that
it looks pretty at the end.
I'm rushing to get
my whipped cream on.
I start sprinkling on
some walnuts and dulce de leche
on top of the whipped cream.
15 seconds.
SOLEIL:
I'm not feeling so great.
My ganache is running off
the sides and super liquid-y.
This did not turn out
the way I wanted to.
DUFF: 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
-Hands up!
-Yay!
All right!
Yours looks so good.
Mine looks horrible.
-Wow.
-Who did this?
* Julia *
That's stunning.
Julia!
Got to go.
[ Laughs ]
'Cause they're not
nervous enough.
Right. [ Laughs ]
That was just for fun.
Tell us about your pizza.
What'd you make?
I made a blondie crust
filled with lemon curd,
and on top is
a raspberry-basil buttercream.
-Wow.
-Is pink your thing?
-Yes.
-Yeah?
-I love it.
-I get it.
It's understated.
It's clean.
It's really nice.
**
I wish the lemon curd
stayed in there more.
-It's a little loose.
-Yeah. It's a little loose.
Yeah.
It almost looks
like an egg yolk.
It's cooked.
It's chewy, which is good.
Such a beautiful dessert.
I'm a little disappointed...
Mm-hmm.
...because the lemon curd
is so runny,
and the buttercream
is too buttery.
Mm-hmm.
But I love
the raspberry flavor.
I got to tell you, too.
I didn't get any basil.
Okay.
And I think that it would've
been delicious on this pizza.
It just needs to be
tweaked a bit more,
but you are obviously
very talented.
Thank you.
Thanks, Julia.
**
-That's too bad.
-It's a shame.
I know.
Because it was so beautiful.
You're like, "Oh, please, like,
let this work. Let this work."
-Yeah. And then it didn't.
-That's a shame.
**
Grady, it looks exactly
like a pizza.
-It really does.
-Exactly.
What you have here is
a shortbread pizza crust
with a raspberry coulis
and a cream cheese frosting
with basil on it
and then raspberries on the top.
-Oh, nice.
-Wow.
Good slice. Yeah.
That's good.
That's good. [ Laughs ]
I really, really love
that cream cheese frosting.
When you get a piece of basil,
you can taste it.
Yes.
When you don't get a piece
of basil, you can't.
Yeah.
It's just the tiniest bit
underbaked.
I agree. I think maybe just
a few more minutes in the oven.
Man, I can't get over how much
like a pizza it looks.
Thank you.
**
-Hi.
-Hey, Linsey.
Tell us what you made.
I made an apple pie dessert
pizza with a candied pecan,
almond and basil crunch
on top.
This is a beautiful pizza.
You made a great crust.
I love the crunch on top.
-Mm-hmm.
-I don't taste any basil.
-[ Mouth full ] You're crazy.
-I don't.
Okay.
I think you got way
too much spices.
It needs some acid to break up
the cinnamon flavor in there.
**
Thanks, Linsey.
I've actually got a little
cinnamon tongue burn.
**
-Hello.
-How's it going, Abby?
-Good.
-Tell us about your pizza.
My pizza is a blondie crust with
maple cream cheese frosting,
candied pecans,
pretzels, and bacon,
and a homemade caramel sauce.
That sounds terrible.
[ Laughter ]
-Ugh.
You are killing me.
I got the bacon piece.
[ Laughter ]
Mmm.
[ Mouth full ] I got to get as
much bacon as I can.
The maple is the very
first thing I taste,
and I love it.
Tell me how you got the maple
into the cream cheese.
A maple extract.
-Oh, that's why it's so strong.
-[ Singsongy ] Thought so.
I think you used
a little too much.
It's a little extract-y.
I think it's baked absolutely
perfect for a blondie.
The crunch of the bacon...
The caramel is beautifully done.
I'm incredibly impressed.
Thank you very much,
Abby.
-Thanks, Abby.
-Thank you.
I think that I made
my great-grandma proud.
**
-How's it going, Bryn?
-Good.
Today, I made
an apple pie pizza
with dulce de leche
with walnuts,
and then with
a twist of basil.
Okay.
I can see the basil.
Where else did you put it?
-Into the apple mixture.
-Oh.
Well, I gotta tell you
this really looks beautiful.
Thank you.
I think you probably didn't bake
this pie crust long enough.
It looks a little blonde.
It looks a little like you,
a little blonde.
-[ Giggles ]
-I think Duffy is right.
Okay.
It is very underbaked.
My mom calls me Duffy.
Sorry.
**
Um...
Let's start with the pie crust.
There's, like, nothing going on.
-It's got zero flavor.
-Okay.
And it's not baked long enough.
That being said, everything
on top is really good.
Your apples are delicious.
The basil's nice and big,
and I love dulce de leche.
-Good job.
-Thank you.
Whipped cream is so luscious.
And with the dulce de leche,
the sugar in there
is really yummy.
And I do taste the basil.
-Thanks, Bryn.
-Thank you.
Well, how about that?
-Wow.
-Isn't that pretty?
It looks like little
Bufala mozzarella.
-Alex.
-Tell us what you made for us.
So I did, like,
a pie crust pizza
topped with chocolate ganache,
which I incorporated
those cayenne peppers,
and then topped it
with some whipped creme
for, like, to settle down
your palate
a little bit after you have,
like, the hot ganache,
and then I topped it
with some fresh strawberries
and some sprinkles
'cause I love sprinkles.
And did you make
your whipped cream?
Yes. Of course.
By hand.
-Of course.
-[ Scoffs ]
Bakers don't use
canned whipped cream.
Right?
Hey, I like that stuff.
[ Laughs ]
It looks beautiful.
Love how the strawberries
match the sprinkles,
and the crumbles on top
match the pie crust.
Yeah.
Really thought about that,
didn't you?
-Yeah.
-Look at that nice slice.
-Ooh!
-Look at that.
Alex, man, you did a 180
from last week.
I want to go for
redemption this week.
You're on your way.
We'll see.
Goodness gracious.
The way that your pie crust
is nice and salty.
Yeah.
And it's not too sweet,
blends perfectly
with that nice,
thick ganache.
-Thank you.
-Really good.
So delicious.
Unfortunately, there's
no chili flavor.
I got zero chilies.
See...I got nothing.
-Thank you, Alex.
-Nice pizza.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
I was expecting them to be like,
"Whew, that's spicy."
-There's just no heat.
-There's no heat.
But I guess not.
**
This looks like the side
of a waffle.
It looks like a giant waffle.
Hey, Aditya.
-Hello.
-Hey.
Tell us what you made
for us here today.
I made a dessert pizza
with a snickerdoodle crust
without the cinnamon, and I also
made vanilla pastry cream,
and it's topped
with strawberries,
candied basil
and caramel sauce.
A snickerdoodle
without the cinnamon --
is that really
a snickerdoodle, then?
No.
-Or is it just a doodle?
-It's an Aditya-doodle.
It's an Aditya-doodle.
[ Laughs ]
I love that you went
for it, man.
I love all this color.
I love how wild it is.
This is weird.
What's going on here?
That's candied basil.
[ Crunching ]
[ Mouth full ] Mmm,
but the basil got overheated,
so it's a little bitter.
-Wow.
-Okay.
-That's a lot underbaked.
Yeah.
Oh, you knew it.
That part here where
it's actually baked,
it's really good cookie.
You've got a lot
of interesting techniques.
And you're the only person
that's made pastry cream so far.
Pastry cream is a little thick.
This is
a really sweet dessert.
It's that caramel
that's so sweet,
and then it goes into
the pastry cream,
and then the underbaked cookie,
which is super, super sweet.
Something could have
been pulled back.
Rough day.
**
Hey, Luke.
-Hi.
-How you feeling?
-Good.
-Yeah?
You had a little bit
of a meltdown earlier.
Uh-huh.
How do you think
you came through that?
I think I did
pretty well with it
because I still
finished in time.
And it looks like you got
an awesome pizza.
Today, I made for you
a dessert pizza
with chocolate hazelnut
spread,
strawberries, bananas,
and ricotta cheese.
My twist item
was ricotta cheese.
I love how you, like,
fish-scaled the bananas,
you know...tsch-tsch-tsch,
and then you continued it
with the strawberries
in the middle.
And I really love how you
made the little rosettes.
Your crust looks
a little blonde.
Yeah.
When you're baking,
you always want to make sure
that you get things
nice and brown
because when things
are this color,
you can almost
taste that flour.
Okay.
Oh, boy.
Wow.
I thought it was going to
completely fall apart.
Same.
**
Ooh.
That ricotta is
perfectly sweetened.
Oh, man. Really good.
It's got great textures.
It's got great flavors.
I taste the ricotta.
You used your twist ingredient
really well.
I'm so happy to see you
come through
that little mini-breakdown...
-Yeah.
...and come through
with something so flavorful.
-Great job today, man.
-Thank you, Luke.
-Thank you.
-DUFF: Awesome.
Beverly?
Shalom.
Hi. It is a pan pizza.
Wow.
I made a thin brownie crust,
and two ganaches,
a white chocolate ganache
and a milk chocolate ganache,
and then I swirled them
together like a sauce.
Sometimes,
pizza has two sauces.
What was your twist ingredient,
and how did you use it?
Hot peppers,
so I made hot pepper
cinnamon nutmeg
whipped cream.
Whoa.
Your whipped cream has got
these, kind of chunks.
I couldn't find any piping bags.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, come on.
In this
big, old huge kitchen?
Piping bags everywhere.
I know.
If you can't find a piping bag,
just get two spoons.
You can make a little quenelle.
-Oh, sure. Why not?
-Um...
You know how long it takes
to learn how to make a quenelle?
They're here 'cause
they're the best.
-All right?
-Oh, okay.
-[ Laughs ]
-Let's try it.
All right.
I love your swirling.
I love that you chose chocolate
and white chocolate ganache.
It makes for
a very beautiful dish.
Yay.
**
Not bad.
I'm going to try a little bit
of your spicy whipped cream.
Comes in after a bit.
It doesn't taste spicy-hot
to me at all.
Remember, there's a lot of fat
in whipped cream,
so you can afford to pump in
some more spice in there.
Having said that,
this is really delicious.
Yay.
I love the creaminess
of the ganache on top,
and it goes really well
with your brownie,
which is super-duper
moist and dense.
It's real chocolaty.
You know, I've got
white chocolate,
milk chocolate,
brownie chocolate,
whipped cream on top, a little
tiny bit of smokiness...
-At least you got a little.
-It's a good job, kid.
-Yeah.
-Bye!
Hi, Gareth.
-Hi.
-So what'd you make us?
I made a pie crust with
a little bit of lemon zest,
raspberry buttercream
with ricotta,
and then I made
a fresh raspberry "G."
All right.
Who made this again?
I'm not sure.
Gareth.
[ Laughter ]
I think that your crust
could have been a lot neater.
Yeah.
And I think your buttercream
could have been a lot neater.
-Yeah.
-Here's the deal, Gareth.
This is a championship
to win $25,000.
I want to see something
that blows me away.
-Oh, okay.
-So I expect a lot from you.
All right.
The ricotta really salted
down the buttercream,
so it's not super sweet.
I can taste the raspberry.
There's a lot of
good flavors in there.
I would've liked to have seen
what I'm tasting
to be as appealing
to my eyes.
-Yeah. Okay.
-I think everything tastes good.
-It's not blowing me away.
-Oh, okay.
I think it's actually
undersweet.
I think it needs more sugar.
[ Sighs heavily ]
**
-How's it going, Soleil?
-Hi.
What the...
That looks like
a super melty pizza.
-It also looks delicious.
-Yeah. [ Laughs ]
It's a sugar cookie crust
with chocolate ganache,
marshmallow sauce,
and some raspberry coulis,
which is infused
with the basil.
And then,
toasted marshmallows
and graham cracker crumbs
on top.
'Cause it looks
a little overdone.
Okay.
It looks like it burnt
a little bit in the oven.
This pizza kind of gooed
everywhere.
Yeah, I don't think I left
my chocolate ganache
in the blast chiller
for long enough.
We could have maybe
used a lighter hand.
Can you tell me what
your twist ingredient was?
It was basil.
I like everything
on top of the pizza.
The chocolate's delicious.
-Thank you.
-It's really good.
The coulis is really good.
I think you could get a little
bit more body in there.
I think maybe you strained
too much out of it.
And I got no basil.
The inside of the cookie
is a little undercooked
'cause you really
taste the flour,
but yet, the outside
is overcooked.
-Thanks, Soleil.
-Bye.
I am starting to get worried.
-I know I didn't do my best.
-Yeah.
I don't think this is
an appropriate pizza for basil.
Mnh-mnh.
**
DUFF: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a feature story
in "Food Network Magazine"...
[ Whispers ] Yes!
...and $25,000.
[ Cheering ]
**
Bakers, your dessert pizzas
were all over the place,
but three of you
couldn't be topped.
-Luke...
-[ Whispers ] Yes.
...your chocolate hazelnut pizza
was beautiful.
-Thank you.
-Abby.
You made a blondie dessert pizza
with maple and bacon,
and I don't know
what else to say.
[ Laughter ]
-Alex.
-What? Really?
[ Laughter ]
Let's work on that
self-confidence, man.
You made
a salty, buttery pie crust
with smooth chocolate.
Mmm!
But any way you slice it,
one dessert pizza was the best.
And that baker is...
**
Abby.
KIDS: Good job.
Winner, winner, chicken dinner.
[ Valerie laughs ]
Feels spectacular.
Congratulations, Abby.
Good job, Abby.
A few dessert pizzas
were not slices of heaven,
but they were good enough
to keep you safe.
And those bakers are...
Julia...
-[ Whispers ] Good job.
-Beverly...
-[ Whispers ] Nice. Good job.
-Grady...
-[ Whispers ] Yes!
-[ Whispers ] Good job.
Bryn...and...
**
Linsey.
-[ Exhales deeply ]
-GIRL: Good job.
Unfortunately, that leaves
Gareth, Soleil, and Aditya.
Please step forward.
**
Gareth, your raspberry
ricotta buttercream pizza --
it was bland and too simple.
Soleil,
your s'mores-inspired pizza --
the ganache was runny.
Aditya, your Aditya-doodle
pizza was very underbaked.
All three of you
are talented bakers,
or you wouldn't be standing
in front of us today.
We are sad to say,
but the baker leaving us today
is...
**
Gareth. Sorry, man.
I'm sorry, Gareth.
I'm disappointed that I'm
going to have to go home,
but I'm still happy
I had this experience.
GIRL:
You're an amazing baker.
I'm going to have to wait
a little bit longer
to get my go-kart.
-Bye.
-KIDS: Bye, Gareth.
DUFF: Previously on "Kids
Baking Championship"...
VALERIE: You have 90 minutes
to turn pizza
into dessert pizza.
[ All cheering ]
ABBY: Sweet and salty.
VALERIE: One dessert pizza
was the best.
Abby.
-Good job, Abby.
Gareth, I think
it's actually undersweet.
Aditya, now, that's
a lot underbaked.
Yeah, that's a lot
of underbake.
Soleil, this pizza
gooed everywhere.
The baker leaving us
today is...Gareth.
**
-Oh, lemons.
-Oh, my gosh!
-A lemon tree?
-I do not like lemons.
I bet Valerie really
likes this challenge.
-Hi.
-Hello, bakers.
Now, we all know that
Valerie loves lemon, right?
-Yeah.
Duh!
So, today's Big Bake
is for her.
Oh, my God, you're so sweet,
Duff, thank you.
And, you know, one of my
favorite things about lemon
is that goes with
so many other flavors.
I like to call them BFFs --
Best Flavor Friends.
-Oh.
-Flavor friends.
So, let's celebrate lemon
and its BFFs
in the form of...
**
Lemon bars!
[ All cheering ]
Bakers, you have two hours
to create a lemon bar
that combines lemon
and a best flavor friend.
Lemon bars look like
they're pretty easy to make,
but actually, they are not,
because so many things
can go wrong.
To find out which lemon BFF
you'll be working with,
when time starts,
you're gonna grab
a lemon off the tree,
and inside,
you will find the flavor
you must combine with lemon.
Oh, no.
-Oh, one more thing.
-Sure.
We don't want
normal lemon bars.
Of course.
We want special shapes.
Something cool.
-Yeah!
So you will also find
a lemon-bar shape
that you must create
in your lemon.
What?
Your baking time starts...
**
...now!
-Now!
I got triangle ginger!
I got circle blackberry!
I got strawberry rectangle.
Time starts now.
Time -- where are the pans?
A lemon bar is a shortbread
crust with lemon curd filling.
A shortbread is, like,
a butter cookie,
and it's made with only,
usually, three ingredients --
Butter, sugar, and flour.
I add fresh strawberries into my
crust because I want the judges
to taste a real
strawberry flavor.
Going in the oven!
My inspiration behind
my lemon bar today
is my Aunt Claire.
She loves lemon, and since
no one in my family
really likes lemon,
you just give them
all to her family
and they eat them up
within, like, an hour.
Oh, gosh, there's
so many people!
Wahh!
Almond...
I get almond and a...
Ugh!
Let's do diamond.
Well, I'm gonna do, like,
an almond crust kind of thing.
To add the almond flavor
into my lemon bars,
I'm using some almond flour
in the crust
and then take almonds and
put them on the top of my crust
so the crust is baking
and the almonds are toasted.
I prebake my crust so when I put
my lemon filling in,
it won't all mush together
and just be terrible and messy.
My inspiration for these
lemon bars is from my mom
because she loves lemon bars
as much as I do.
15 minutes gone, bakers!
I have raspberry and rectangle.
So, I'm making
a shortbread crust
and a lemon curd
with raspberry in it.
For my crust, I need butter.
Do you know how many ounces
three sticks of butter would be?
One stick is four.
One?
Wait, one cup is four?
-One cup is eight.
-One cup is eight ounces.
GRADY: Oh, okay.
But one stick of butter
is only half a cup.
I'm very confused about
how much butter I need.
Hey.
That is a lot of butter.
GRADY: Whee!
My dough is ready,
so I put that in the oven.
DUFF: Oh, look, lemons.
When will we have
a bacon day?
I want a bacon day.
I want a bacon tree.
**
Hey, what's up, man?
All right,
so you've been having
a little roller-coaster ride,
haven't you?
Um, well, yeah.
You were, like, super awesome
the first week.
Second week, you were...
I definitely want to win
this challenge.
I think -- yeah.
I was in the bottom
three last week
and I definitely don't want
to do that again.
What is your lemon BFF?
It's blueberry.
Lemon blueberry is one
of the most delicious things
on the planet.
-Yeah.
I'm making
a normal lemon bar
with a blueberry coulis
drizzled over it.
To make my shortbread crust,
I'm using powdered sugar
because that gives the crust
a smoother feel to it.
To make my lemon filling,
I whisk together
the sugar and eggs,
add the lemon juice
and lemon zest,
and then I finish it off
with a bit of orange extract,
'cause I think
the orange flavor
complements the flavor
of the lemon.
90 minutes, bakers!
You have 90 minutes left!
Remember, this time
is deceiving, bakers,
because those lemon bars
got to chill
so you can make
the shakes.
You got to chill.
I got to chill.
That's two...
Oh, math.
Geez.
My lemon BFF is ginger, so I
am making a shortbread crust,
which I'm gonna
incorporate ground ginger.
You can smell that
delicious ginger.
Oh, smells like heaven.
I think my inspiration
behind this lemon bar
is the lemon ginger tea
that I love to drink.
Ooh!
Some got in my eye there.
It's a big part of wintertime.
Hi!
-Hi, Alex.
-Hello.
-I love ginger!
Yeah, I put it
in my crust.
Did you use real ginger
or did you use ginger spice?
Uh, ground ginger.
Ground ginger, okay.
I see.
So, you know ground ginger
is a little bit more
mellow than real ginger?
Oh, my God.
What am I gonna do?
I'm scared that they're
gonna get no ginger.
Ginger, ginger, ginger.
Think, think, think.
I decide to make a ginger juice,
ginger beer reduction.
This is probably
the weirdest thing
I've ever done,
but why not try?
**
BOY: Julia,
what are you doing?
Cherries, I don't know.
I'm worried that
since I got cherry,
my filling will be too runny
since I'm gonna add puree.
But I'm also excited because
it's gonna turn out pink!
Pink is my signature color.
Once my crust is cooled, I pour
that into my pan with the crust.
I put that in the oven
and hope that it cooks right.
**
Since my mom is Caribbean,
I've worked with coconut before.
So, what I'm making is
a coconut lemon bar.
My lemon curd has a little
bit of coconut cream in it
with some shredded coconut
in my shortbread crust.
Alex, are you in the top?
Yeah.
Do you mind if I put
mine in there, too?
Yeah, for sure.
I start walking
towards the oven...
Shoot!
You've got to be kidding me.
Since my ganache
sort of overflowed
on my pizza last week,
this cannot happen this week.
So, I just grab, like,
a ginormous sheet try,
and I put it on there.
Thank you.
-Uh-huh, no problem.
Grady, thank you!
Such a gentleman.
BEVERLY: Everyone else is
going in the oven,
and I'm still nowhere
near done with my dough.
My BFF is walnuts.
I decide to toast my walnuts
in the oven
so that I can bring out
the flavor in them.
And then crush them up
in the food processor
and substitute those
for some of the flour.
I definitely get walnut.
This is good.
I realized that everyone
else is, like,
already putting their crust
back in the oven
to bake the second time
with the curd on it,
and I haven't even
gotten mine in the oven.
That's a little scary.
Oh, yeah, oven mitts,
where are you?
There you are.
One hour left, bakers.
One hour.
Oh!
My bad.
My grandma, she really,
really loves my lemon bars.
So, I need to make
these lemon bars like
I'm making them for her.
I got it.
I got it, Linsey,
don't worry about it.
Thanks.
How'd you put the pecans
in the filling?
I just kind of crushed them
and put them on top of my crust,
and then when I poured
in the filling,
they kind of went
all over the place.
Linsey's perfectly dressed
for the challenge today.
She's all in yellow.
What's up
with your shirt?
I got lemons!
Do you think I like them?
-Eh.
Blackberry.
My crust is still kind of warm,
but the clock is ticking down,
so I take the crust,
and I line blackberries
in rows on it
because that was
my lemon bar BFF.
And then I pour the curd over it
so that way, when I cut it out,
every single bar has
one blackberry in them.
Thank you.
I test my crust
with a toothpick...
Yep.
...and it looks done,
so I start to pour my curd on.
**
Come on!
The curd's too heavy,
so it breaks through the crust
and leaks.
The crust is coming up.
I don't have time to start over.
Ugh.
**
BFF lemon bars to keep your
place in the competition!
**
Come on!
I don't have time to start over.
I'm hoping, in the oven,
everything will level out
and that it'll bake fine.
I hope it works out.
I have the best idea.
Bakers, can I have
your attention please?
-No!
Val needs more lemon!
What the heck?
So, you must also create
an edible
lemon decoration.
Edible lemon decoration?
So, it has to look
like a lemon...
What looks like a lemon?
...and be edible.
Julia.
So, what are you doing
for your twist?
Candied lemons.
How are you doing that?
In a pot, you heat together,
like, water, sugar,
and lemon juice,
like, a little bit,
and then you add in
slices of lemon.
As soon as they cool,
it looks like they have, like,
sugar on them.
It's pretty cool.
42 minutes!
-How many?
-42 minutes!
20?!
Wait, how many minutes?
42!
Oh, I thought
you said 20.
-Abby.
-Hi, Duff!
-How's it going over here?
-Good.
[ Gasps ] Look!
Extra strawberries?
Extra strawberries.
You're extra.
I know.
So are you.
What are you
making there?
I'm making
sugar-cookie dough.
For your
edible decoration?
Yeah, I'm gonna try and make
it look like this.
Okay.
Good luck, Chef.
Thank you!
While my sugar cookie is baking,
I make my frosting.
And I add yellow
food coloring...
Perfect.
...and then I pipe on
my frosting
to make it look
like a lemon wedge.
It smells good in here.
For the twist,
I'm making an actual lemon.
My idea is to take
yellow coating chocolate
and put that into a round
silicone bowl, and then...
Don't burn, please.
Oh, no.
...I make
some rice cereal treats.
I take my rice cereal treats and
shove them into my sph-- pheres.
Spheres.
I have problems with shapes
and all that kind of stuff.
Okay.
Then I take some more
melted chocolate
and put it around the edges.
And I have a whole lemon
ready to serve to Duff and Val.
Bryn, have you made
your curd yet?
Yep.
I start late on everything.
I'm doing terrible on time.
And now we need to make
an edible lemon decoration.
This is the last thing I need!
So, I immediately just
throw together lemons
dipped in powdered sugar.
Powdered sugar lemon is amazing.
In my house, we call this candy.
Yum!
I like to lick them.
It looks like a lemon.
It is a lemon.
This counts.
So, I'm like...
Phewf!
Don't spill on me.
Finally, my curd is done.
Mmm!
And then I pour it
over my crust.
This is not enough lemon curd.
Uh-oh.
I can't just serve this much
layer of curd to the judges.
In some places, this much.
None!
I'll have to make it again.
So, I quickly throw together
a lemon curd.
I don't even cool, I just
throw it on my lemon bars
and get it in the oven.
It is what it is.
Edible lemon.
I have no clue
what I'm going to do.
So, I just think, "Fondant."
Fondant, fondant,
yellow, yellow.
Oh, come on!
There's no yellow fondant.
I grab yellow fondant, and then
I roll it out in the sheeter,
and then I cut it into
small little circles,
and then I grab
this little tracing tool,
and then I make those little
designs to represent a lemon.
I think they look awesome.
Edible decoration.
I have the idea to freeze
some buttercream,
and I think
it's gonna work well,
and I think it's
pretty creative,
'cause I don't see
anyone else doing this.
I use my super-quick
batter-making skills,
and I whip up
this lemon buttercream.
Did you have the lemon extract?
Yeah, I do.
Do you want it?
Yeah, can I borrow it?
I grab a mold and start
piping it in.
Hopefully,
they'll freeze in time.
Hmm. Hmm.
So, I'm kind of confused
about the twist at first.
But then I realized, "Oh, I can
just make a rice cereal treat."
Bryn, are you done
with the rice cereal?
Yeah.
I have to grab the rice
cereal from Bryn,
and that's when I realize...
Thank you.
...she's making
the same thing as me.
I have to do this
better than her.
I dip the rice cereal treat in
some yellow coating chocolate,
and then green fondant
so I can make a little leaf.
Are you frying
blueberries?
-No!
-Oh, okay.
ADITYA: I'm washing them.
I'm getting started
on my blueberry coulis,
and now we have a twist.
It just seems kind of...
kind of annoying right now.
To make the coulis,
I throw the blueberries, sugar,
and lemon juice
in a sauce pan,
and then just stir it until all
the blueberries are broken down
and released all their juices.
Luke, what are you
planning to do
for your lemon
decoration thingy?
Rice cereal treats.
I kind of really don't want
to do this twist.
So, I decide to make
candied lemon slices.
I first get started
on the sugar syrup
and I drop a lemon in there.
The sugar syrup is way too thick
and it's sticking to the lemon,
and it's not, like, going well.
I'll probably have to think
of something else
before time runs out,
but I don't know
what to do yet.
Lemon BFF bars,
and I get an edible
lemon decoration.
-I don't.
-'Cause I'm special.
I'm not.
Just work on the garnishes.
I just finished making my
lemon wedges and mint leaves.
Does this count?
I'm a little confused.
What can I do with that?
So, I take yellow and white
coating chocolate
and I pipe out a lemon slice.
Today, I'm really
stepping up my game,
because last two weeks, I've
been in the bottom-middle area,
and I don't want
to be there again.
All right, 30 minutes
left, guys!
Lemon bar BFFs
with a lemon decoration.
So, for the twist, I'm going
with a rice cereal treat.
Once I have it done,
I form it into, like,
a roundish sort of thing,
and then I air-brush it yellow.
Oh, that looks awesome!
BRYN: Hot over here!
I go take out my lemon bars
and it looks done.
I test it with a toothpick...
Oh, no!
No, no, no, no, no!
No, no. No, no.
It is liquidy inside.
This is definitely not what
it's supposed to look like.
I have no idea what to do.
Oh, no!
My filling looks like water.
I have no idea what to do.
What's going on?
Um, in the middle,
it's, like, oily,
and I don't know
what to do now.
Okay, that's not
necessarily a bad thing.
I think it needs to be baked
a little bit longer.
Okay?
So, put your gloves on
and get it back in the oven.
I'm like, "Please just
let everything bake.
Please just let
everything bake."
You'll do great.
I believe in you.
All right, 30 minutes
left, guys!
Lemon bar BFFs
with a lemon decoration.
Come on, sauce, boil, boil!
Reduce, reduce, reduce.
I'm looking at my reduction and
I realize nothing's happening,
it's still pure liquid.
This is not gonna work.
How else can I put ginger
into this dessert?
Whipped cream.
I wonder.
Oh!
I can do a ginger whipped cream.
I whip that up
until stiff peaks.
One of the best whipped creams
I've ever had.
That looks interesting.
Yeah.
This would be, like,
great on the wall.
You know what I mean?
I just thought it looked
burned, but okay.
I like it.
It looks nice.
I have to use coconut
and I'm a little worried
because I know it's not
a very strong flavor,
so I combine powdered sugar
with some coconut cream
and some coconut milk to make
a coconut drizzle for the top.
Aditya, how are you
incorporating your flavor?
ADITYA: I'm making
a blueberry coulis
and drizzling that
on the lemon bars.
Nice.
I mean, you can do
the same thing as me.
Mm.
LUKE: I decide to make
a blackberry coulis
because it's one
of the simpler ways
to add in a blackberry flavor,
but also one of
the best-tasting ways.
Oh, my gosh,
that smells delicious.
All right, Valerie,
we need to get
to the bottom of something.
What is the root
of the lemon obsession?
When I was pregnant
with Wolfie,
the only thing
to take away my nausea
is sucking on lemons.
And I began to really love
to suck on lemons
'cause it made me
feel so much better.
Huh.
So, not barfing
is what led you
to love lemons,
basically?
Yeah, basically.
Good, that's good.
Grady, yours is turning really,
really brown on top.
-Oh, it is?
-Yeah.
GRADY: I immediately put them
in the blast chiller
to cool down.
I have to make sure these lemon
bars are set up just right
so that when I cut them,
they don't, like,
spill everywhere.
SOLEIL: Are you making
anything
for the top
of your lemon bars?
I have a raspberry coulis
that I'm gonna drizzle on top.
That's gonna be good!
13 minutes!
I've chilled my lemon bars
and I'm ready to cut out
my lemon circles
and put everything together.
So, I take a circle
cookie cutter
and start cutting them out.
It's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
Please be done.
Time is almost up and I have
to get these on the plate.
As I'm cutting them,
I'm so nervous
that they are not gonna be set,
but just my luck, they were
ready to be cut into diamonds.
Thank goodness!
I decorate my bars
with some chocolate ganache
and toasted
almonds on the top.
GIRL: Those are amazing,
Julia.
JULIA: I cut my lemon bar
into a square shape.
BEVERLY:
They look so pretty.
I'm really happy because they
did turn out a pretty pink.
**
There's no time left and I
have to get these on the plate.
Like, yesterday.
I cut the rectangles
and put a little bit
of strawberry coulis on top
and then I put one of my
strawberry decorations
that I already had
cut on top of that.
-Five minutes, guys!
-Oh, my goodness.
VALERIE: Who wants to stay
in this competition?
For Canada!
So, it's time to start
plating my lemon bars,
so I start to cut them
into my triangle shape.
I can make them look nice
on the platter.
And I top it with the ginger
whipped cream,
some yellow sprinkles,
strawberries,
and then I put
my fondant lemon.
That's pretty good.
Half my size.
I cut out my triangles,
I get them onto the plate,
I sprinkle on
some powdered sugar,
and then I top it with my
lemon wedges and mint leaves.
Okay.
Then I look around
and a couple people have, like,
full lemons, like,
as a decoration,
and I'm like, "Oh, no.
Did I do the whole twist wrong?"
Oh!
So, I start to freak out.
-How are you doing, Linsey?
-Not good.
-Oh. Do you need help?
-Um, maybe.
But then Alex comes over
and thank God!
I have some extra fondant
at my station.
-Can I use some fondant?
-Okay. Here.
LINSEY: Alex gives me his
leftover yellow fondant,
and as quickly as I can,
I mush it up into a ball in
the most lemon shape as I can.
Two minutes, guys!
Oh, I forgot about the twist.
I'm running out of time and I
still don't have my lemon twist.
So, I'm thinking, at this point,
I just have to use a lemon slice
and hope the judges
will be okay with it.
**
BEVERLY:
It isn't going through.
There's almost no time left
and I try to pull them out,
and this is a disaster.
And it's falling apart.
Oh, dear.
Oh, no.
She's just trying
to take them out.
They're too warm.
This is the only thing
I have at this point,
so I just need to get
this goop into a cup
and call it a lemon bar.
At least it'll taste good.
I can help now,
Beverly, if you need.
Thank you, can you help me
get it into these cups?
BOTH: 9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Hands up!
-Whoo!
-All right.
DUFF: Good job, guys.
Well, when there's nothing left
to do, you eat raspberries.
Oh, boy.
It's lemon time!
I'm so excited.
Don't I know it.
Linsey!
Well,
you're all in yellow.
-Yeah.
-It's lemon day.
So, Linsey,
what was your lemon BFF?
I made you a lemon bar
with a shortbread pecan crust.
I was a bit confused about
what we exactly had to do
for a twist,
so I gave you a few options.
'Cause I was not sure.
Oh, my God.
That's so fabulous.
I got to tell you,
your presentation
is absolutely beautiful.
It's very elegant.
Except for one thing.
-Yeah.
Your lemon bars fell apart.
Mm-hmm.
Now,
you did use fondant.
I'm not fond
of fondant.
But it is edible,
so it's legal.
You could have gotten away
with just these
beautiful decorations
as you're doing here.
Definitely tasting
those pecans.
DUFF: Mmm!
Your curd
is nice and lemony.
The cookie is delicious.
It is a shortbread,
it's falling apart like
a shortbread should.
Mm-hmm.
I'm definitely
tasting pecan.
Pe-can.
-Pe-can.
Yeah.
Definitely tasting pe-can.
-Pecan.
You got good lemon,
you got good pecan.
-Thanks, Linsey.
-Thank you.
-See you.
-She's pretty impressive.
-Pretty impressive.
All right, Grady.
What I made is
a raspberry lemon bar
with raspberry coulis on the
top.
My lemon decoration
is a rice cereal treat
formed into a circle,
and then I air-brushed
it yellow.
Yeah, I thought it was,
like, mac and cheese,
but made with, like, rice.
Like, a risotto
mac and cheese.
And I was about to be
really excited about that,
I got to tell you.
Sounds yummy.
So, I guess the question is,
does it look like a lemon?
And you know what?
I think it absolutely does.
All right,
let's try this guy.
**
It's delicious.
-Thank you.
-This is really good.
-Okay, great!
So, the lemon bars.
Look at that.
Yeah,
that is weird-looking.
It almost looks like
you've got some frozen
cream cheese in there.
I don't see
any lemon curd.
When I took my crust
out of the oven,
I put on my lemon curd...
-Uh-huh.
...but it wasn't done
completely, so it went under.
So, like, it kind of went
through the crust.
Oh.
Let's try it.
I -- ooh.
I taste...
Like, it's a --
it's a mound of butter.
I barely taste any lemon.
And how much butter did you
put in the crust?
3 cups.
3 cups of butter?
-Mm-hmm.
-That's a lot.
I got your raspberry.
It's nice.
Yeah,
totally get raspberry.
And I don't mind butter,
but it tasted like
I literally took
a slice of butter
and put it in my mouth.
Aww, dang it.
That's weird.
I don't know what
went wrong where,
but something went wrong.
-Okay.
-Thanks, Grady.
-Thank you.
I was pretty sure
I had the butter right,
but I guess I didn't.
I put that in my mouth
and I was like...
Yeah.
It -- it's -- only --
I only taste butter.
This is a head-scratcher,
man.
**
Aditya!
Come on in, please.
-Hi.
My BFF was blueberry.
Awesome.
I made a round lemon bar
with blueberry coulis
and oatmeal crumble.
Do I have to --
where is your lemon decoration?
VALERIE: I don't have
a lemon decoration.
I thought it was supposed
to be on there.
-Oh, that's all right.
-That's a lemon.
-Yeah.
-That's your lemon decoration?
So, if I took a big old bite
out of that,
how do you think
I'd feel?
Well, it is edible.
Well, technically,
it looks like a lemon,
and it's edible.
It still meets the guidelines
of the twist
even though it is stupid.
This is an absolutely
gorgeous plate.
I love what you did with
the blueberry coulis,
and I even like
the little bit of crumble
that's on the side.
Yeah, I think the flowers
is a great idea.
You know, it looks really,
really beautiful.
The lemon is
so nice and tart.
It goes so well with
the blueberry coulis,
it kind of adds
that little extra bit
of tartness
and sweetness.
The cookie is fantastic.
See how flaky
the cookie is?
You've got this, like, really
good, strong lemon flavor
that's just
kind of wrapped into
velvety blueberriness
of your sauce.
it's really good, man.
My lemon bars are gonna
have to come
with some blueberry
coulis from now on.
-Mm-hmm.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Aditya.
-Thank you. Bye.
-Wow.
-Very impressive.
Is it in my beard?
No, you're good.
Thanks.
Luke.
Today, I've made for you
a lemon bar with blackberries
and a blackberry coulis.
Please tell me about
your lemon decoration.
That is a rice cereal treat
with yellow coating chocolate
and a little green fondant leaf.
He even made the leaf.
I think your chocolate
was too cold.
You know?
So, if the chocolate
was a little warmer,
it would have leveled
back into itself,
and you probably would
have had a smoother lemon.
Let's taste it --
Ooh!
-I heard that.
-Yeah.
**
Boy, do I love
the lemon flavor in here.
It's nice and bright,
just the perfect amount
of sweetness.
But there's something
interesting happening
in the bar.
It's like the lemon curd
went right into the crust.
So, it's like
a juicy lemon cookie.
-Luke, it's delicious.
-Mm-hmm.
I think what happened was
your crust was
still pretty warm,
it inhaled
the lemon curd.
I did not mean for it
to be like that.
I'll just get a little...
Such a girl.
**
I can't close my mouth.
-It's really delicious.
-Thanks, man.
Thank you.
Yeah,
I wouldn't call it a bar.
I think
juicy lemon cookie.
-Juicy lemon cookie.
That would be
a good band name.
"We're the Juicy
Lemon Cookies!
Good night, Cleveland!"
Julia.
I got cherry
for the ingredient.
It looks like you mixed them in
with your lemon curd?
Yes.
You want to tell me
about your lemon decoration?
I made a candied
lemon decoration.
It's edible
if it's candy.
I like how you used the juice
in the filling
and made it pink.
It's really cool,
it's a great idea.
Let's taste it.
The lemon curd
tastes really good,
but here's the problem
with cherry juice.
Yeah?
It took away all
the tartness of the lemon.
Oh, okay.
So, I don't really taste cherry,
I just taste sugar.
Okay.
Sorry, Valerie.
I know you like lemon.
All right,
I'm going for it.
-That's lemon.
-Yeah.
-Thanks.
-Thanks, Julia.
Thank you.
**
-Hmm.
-Beverly, come on in!
Hey, Beverly, what's up?
The ceiling!
I was supposed to make it
in a square,
and my BFF for my lemon
was walnuts.
Beverly,
what happened today?
When I tried to take
my lemon bars out of the pan,
it kind of went pbht.
It's very upsetting!
I mean, a whole part
of the challenge is missing.
It's not a bar.
**
It's very upsetting!
I mean, a whole part
of the challenge is missing.
It's not a bar.
What did you do
for your lemon decoration?
For the lemon decoration,
I took a slice of lemon
and covered it
in powdered sugar.
Now it's a candy.
-Oh, really?
-Hmm.
**
That's just a raw lemon.
-Well, let's try it.
-Let's try it.
**
It's...
so delicious.
Yay.
It's, like, over-the-top
delicious.
Yay.
That lemon curd is creamy
and bright
and lemony and tart
and just the perfect
amount of sweetness.
I can taste the crunch
of the walnuts.
It's so delicious!
Beverly, you got to work
on your time management.
Your lemon curd is so smooth,
it's so clean,
and you ran out of time,
and then
you have a cup of stuff.
This isn't a bar.
-I know.
-Thank you, though.
-Thanks, Beverly.
-Bye!
-Bye.
See you.
That was hard.
-That was hard.
'Cause this really
does taste delicious.
I know.
But this isn't a bar.
-No.
-It's a cup.
Mm-hmm.
#Time got the best of me today.
**
Abby.
Today, I have made for you
a strawberry lemon bar
topped with a strawberry coulis
and a little strawberry
decoration thing.
Abby, I think your tray
is really cute,
and I think it's
kind of messy.
You spent all this time
on making these beautiful
strawberry fans,
but it would have been nice
to, like, line them up
and show the beautiful
work you did.
Yeah.
So, tell us about
your lemon decoration.
My lemon decoration is a
sugar cookie topped with icing.
You made a sugar cookie?
-Yes.
-Impressive.
-Extra.
-Yeah.
That's a cute
little cookie.
-Take a bite.
-It's your cookie.
It's your cookie.
I'm sure it's my cookie.
**
Oh?
That's a really
good sugar cookie.
Mmm.
Let's eat.
Let's bite into this bar.
Mmm.
Lemony!
-Ooh.
-That curd is fabulous.
But your crust is
really underbaked.
You know, if it was baked
a little bit longer,
it kind of --
you would have had
this nice, soft lemon curd,
and then a nice,
crunchy cookie.
And those two textures
are really good together.
-Thanks, Abby.
Thank you.
**
Alex, come on in.
Hi.
My lemon BFF was ginger.
So, it's a ginger crust,
and then it's just
a regular lemon curd filling,
and then I topped it
with a ginger whipped cream.
For the lemon twist,
I did a fondant lemon.
And it's
a beautiful lemon.
I love that you did
a slice of lemon.
It's actually
quite pretty.
Wow, thank you.
All right, well, Alex,
I think your tray
looks really nice.
-Thank you.
-I like your platter.
I like how there's some red,
and there's some yellow,
and it looks really good.
I'm gonna try and see
if I can taste your ginger
in your whipped cream.
That was a great idea.
Yeah.
It is very gingery.
It's a beautiful,
subtle flavor.
Mmm!
Mmm.
That was a super
mellow lemon bar.
I do like that they're not
too overly sweet.
-Oh, okay.
-I love the consistency.
It's really nice.
You got a nice, clean curd,
it's not all broken up,
and I like your crust.
It's nice when, you know,
you can sort of bite into it,
it's a little chewy.
It's kind of tender,
which is really nice.
-Yes!
-Thank you, Alex.
-Thanks, Alex.
-Thank you. Bye.
-Bye-bye.
-See you.
-The curd.
-It's excellent.
This curd is perfect.
Soleil.
My lemon BFF was coconut.
My lemon decoration
is lemon buttercream.
On our plate, they're
absolutely beautiful.
But you can see where it went
from good to bad to worse.
Now, the buttercream
was an odd choice,
'cause I don't really know
what to do with it.
I don't really want to have
a fork-full of buttercream.
Mmm!
I'm getting the lemon flavor
right off the bat.
Makes me
very, very happy.
Your cookie
is really nice.
It's super chewy,
not underbaked.
It's really good.
And your lemon curd.
-Thank you.
-It is perfect.
It is delicious.
It's really nice.
But I am not getting
any coconut.
I can feel
the coconut texture,
but I can't taste it.
Thank you.
-Thanks, Soleil.
-Thank you, bye.
No coconut?
I thought it was enough.
-Hi, Bryn.
-Hi!
Today I made an almond lemon bar
with chocolate ganache,
then on the side is a rice
cereal crispy treat.
It looks like some of them
are diamonds, not all of them.
I love that you
did a 3D lemon.
I love this
big old baseball.
Now, the seam
is a little rough.
Yeah.
What you could've done here
is taken, like,
a peeler, you know?
For like a carrot,
you know?
And you could've just kind of
shaved that down a little bit.
Here, half for you,
half for me.
All right.
Cheers.
Mmm!
Wow.
It's good.
Delicious.
I'm gonna try
this lemon bar.
**
You know what this is?
It's a really, really
delicious almond bar.
Okay.
I taste
no lemon whatsoever.
Okay.
I did not want this
to happen at all.
I am freaking out.
Bryn, Bryn,
I thought we were tight?
You didn't give me
a lemon bar.
Okay, Bryn,
I think this is delicious.
I think it's -- you can
definitely taste the almonds.
You know, the texture
is really nice,
it's not dry at all.
And it's definitely
not a lemon bar.
-Thanks, Bryn.
Thank you.
I feel so nervous and scared
'cause I have no idea
what's gonna happen next.
This is gonna be tough.
This is gonna be
crazy tough.
**
DUFF: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a featured story
in "Food Network Magazine."
-Yes!
-And...
$25,000!
[ All cheering ]
**
Val, it was
a rough challenge today.
Grady gave us a not-delicious
bar of butter and zero lemon.
-None.
-Where'd it go?
None.
Bryn gave us a bar
that was delicious
and tasted like almonds.
-What a yummy almond bar.
-Yeah.
-Not a bit of lemon.
-Nope.
Beverly gave us a cup,
but it actually
tasted like lemon.
The most delicious
lemon trifle
I have probably ever had.
-Sure.
All three of them didn't
complete the challenge
in different ways.
We have to make a decision,
and for me,
that decision is gonna be
whether I want to eat
any one of those
three bars again.
**
Bakers, I think I am finally
over my lemon obsession,
thank you.
How about no more
lemon desserts?
-Yes.
-Good.
In this challenge,
three of you were the zest --
excuse me -- the best.
-Ha.
Aditya, your lemon
blueberry bars were gorgeous.
The curd was smooth,
the crust was flaky,
and you inspired me
with the way you handled
the blueberry.
-Good job.
-Alex.
Re-- W-w-what?
DUFF: Your lemon ginger bars
were mellow and delicious.
We really liked
the consistency
and subtle flavor
of your lemon curd,
and the ginger in your
whipped cream
was a smart move.
Oh, my God, really, what?
Thank you.
-Linsey.
-Good job!
-What?
-Good job, Lins.
Your lemon bars with pecan
shortbread crust
were presented
elegantly.
We were impressed, especially
with the cookie crust.
Thank you.
I've never been in the top
three before,
and it's such a great feeling.
But only one of you
should pucker up
and kiss success hello.
And that baker is...
Aditya.
-Good job.
-Congratulations.
Thanks.
I really can't believe I won.
That's, like, really
crazy and amazing.
You, Alex,
and Linsey are safe.
We will see you
next week.
Now, a few other offerings
barely passed
the lemon bar,
but they were good enough
to keep you safe.
Julia.
-Good job.
-Abby.
-Good job, Abby.
-Thank you.
-Soleil.
And...
Luke.
Unfortunately, that
leaves Beverly,
Bryn, and Grady.
Please step forward.
What a rough day today,
huh, bakers?
-Yeah.
-Beverly.
There's just
no way around it --
you didn't create
a lemon bar.
You made a lemon trifle.
Bryn, you also didn't
make a lemon bar --
you made an almond bar
with no lemon flavor.
Grady,
you made a butter bar.
-Oops.
-Oops!
This is always
a tough moment,
but the baker
leaving us today is...
**
...Grady.
Sorry, man.
You're an awesome baker,
we're gonna miss you.
We're really gonna
miss you, Grady.
You are awesome.
**
Even though I didn't win,
I'm happy I made it this far.
And I also made a lot of new,
awesome friends,
so I'm gonna keep baking,
no matter what.
Grady-man shake.
All right, that's
three boys in a row.
Boys,
you got to step it up.
Yes, Chef!
DUFF: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Create a lemon bar that combines
lemon and a best flavor friend.
I got triangle ginger!
My lemon bars are gonna have to
come with some blueberry coulis
from now on.
DUFF: Alex, your lemon-ginger
bars were mellow and delicious.
Only one of you should pucker up
and kiss success "hello."
Aditya.
[ Muttering, congratulating ]
Hey.
Ooh. Grady, you made
a butter bar.
DUFF: The baker
leaving us today is...
Grady.
ALEX: There's already been three
boys that went home already,
so us boys, we should really
bring it this challenge.
-It's a drip cake.
-Great.
-Of course it's a drip cake.
-But why are there
ice-cream cones?
Oh, ice cream cakes!
Ice cream!
Oh, there they are.
ALL: Hi.
Val, what do you think we should
have the kids bake today?
Oh, gosh,
I don't know.
There's so many
options.
Hold on a second.
Let me think.
Oh, my gosh.
[ Chatter ]
**
No.
[ Laughter ]
I got it!
Ice-cream cone
drip cakes!
Yum!
Yes!
A drip cake is
a regular cake,
but you take ganache and
drip some of the ganache over
so you get a nice,
dripping effect.
Sometimes, you can have
an ice cream cone,
and sometimes,
you don't have to.
Bakers, we are giving you
2 hours
to make ice-cream cone
drip cakes.
And your cakes will be inspired
by a classic ice-cream flavor,
like mint chocolate chip
or Neapolitan.
-Mmm.
-Okay.
Luke, how you feeling
about this?
I'm thinking.
LUKE: The flavor I wouldn't
want to get is pistachio.
They're just weird
and green and gross.
When time starts,
you guys will come up
and grab the ice cream out of
one of these ice-cream cones.
On the back, you'll find
the ice cream flavor
that will inspire
your cake.
And your baking time
starts...
BOTH: now!
LUKE: Wait.
I got raspberry
vanilla swirl.
I got butter pecan.
I got mint chip.
So, I'm making
a mint-chip cake,
and I'm gonna do a
Swiss meringue buttercream.
My only concern
about this cake is that --
not my only concern, I have
so many concerns, never mind.
There's only
peppermint extract.
Do you think that
would work?
Yeah. Peppermint and mint are
like the same thing, I think.
They both have
the word "mint" in them.
That's a lot of sugar.
To make my cake,
I creamed together my butter,
shortening, and sugar.
Then, I whisked together my
flour, salt, and baking powder.
Then, I added my flour mixture
and milk, alternating as I go.
And then, I add my eggs,
one at a time.
To get the mint flavor
in my cake,
I'm just using peppermint
extract, and then dye it green.
There's a lot of pressure
riding on this drip cake
because last week,
I was in the top three,
and I intend
to keep up with that.
Going in the oven!
How's everybody doing?
-Amazing.
-Perfect.
Cookies and cream is one of
my favorite ice cream flavors,
so I'm making
a cookies-and-cream cake
with a cookies-and-cream
buttercream.
What could be
more perfect?
I'm gonna add some crushed-up,
cream-filled sandwich cookies
into my cake batter.
That is the biggest batch
I've ever made.
The most difficult part
of this challenge will be
being able to get our cakes
in the oven quick enough,
but I'm the queen
of fast batter.
On the dot.
I am good.
I'm nervous
about pistachio
cause I have never had
pistachio, ever.
So, I have no idea
what it tastes like.
I'm making a pistachio cake
with a pistachio buttercream.
These are delicious.
You just ate
a pistachio.
Yeah.
If you had to describe
the flavor of a pistachio,
what would you say?
It's nutty,
and it's kind of sweet.
And sweet. It tastes like
a Mediterranean peanut.
I don't know.
[ Laughs ]
All right.
Good luck.
-Thank you!
-Pistachio palooza.
I substituted 1 cup of flour
for 1 cup of ground pistachios
so that way, there isn't
too many dry ingredients.
Whoa, that is a lot
of batter.
I'm adding in my food coloring,
and it looks perfect.
Well, Duff, they say
you can't buy happiness,
but you can buy
ice cream.
What's your favorite?
My favorite ice cream is
peanut butter and chocolate.
ADITYA: The flavor I get is
chocolate peanut butter.
I like chocolate, but, you know,
I'm not, like,
a choco-holic
or anything.
I'm making a chocolate drip cake
with peanut butter buttercream.
First, I add the dry ingredients
to the wet ingredients.
Then, I add
some peanut butter chips,
just to give it a little bit
of peanut butter flavor.
And lastly, I add the hot water
which blooms or,
like, intensifies
the chocolate.
Some people also do this
with coffee,
but hot water also works.
Going into the oven!
And now, I can finally
get started on my buttercream.
How's it going, bakers?
Good!
I got chocolate chip.
Yay!
Let me put my giant block
of butter.
I like chocolate chip
because it's my nanna's favorite
ice cream flavor.
My nanna, she's awesome!
I'm gonna put in 3/4 of a cup
'cause I don't want too much,
but I don't want
too little.
Yeah,
that's way too little.
I'm making a
chocolate-chip cake
with chocolate-chip
cream cheese frosting
and milk chocolate drips.
I really want to make sure
they taste chocolate chip.
I mean, that's the entire
challenge!
Is anybody in the oven?
-Almost.
ALEX:
I got rainbow sherbet.
This lime
smells delicious.
I think rainbow-sherbet cake
should be key lime cake,
orange curd, and raspberry
buttercream, because those are,
I think, the three main flavors
of rainbow sherbet.
This is a lot of
zesting, eh?
First, I get started on
my key lime cake.
I mix together
my dry ingredients
and my wet ingredients,
and then, I fold in
my whipped egg whites.
Whenever I make
a citrus cake,
I always like to whip
my egg whites until soft peaks
'cause it makes a lighter
and airier cake.
So, the next thing I do is,
I start my curd.
I whisk together sugar,
egg yolks, and orange juice.
All right.
I've accomplished quite a bit,
but I still have a lot to do.
What flavor
did you get?
Neapolitan.
With the Neapolitan ice cream,
I have to make chocolate,
vanilla,
and strawberry.
I'm making a
chocolate-and-vanilla cake
with strawberry-buttercream
icing.
Gosh,
this stuff is strong.
For my chocolate
cake batter,
I saved half of
my vanilla cake batter,
added cocoa powder,
more milk and more eggs,
so it's the same consistency
as the vanilla.
Going in the oven!
Ugh. I forgot
the orange curd.
My curd is on the double-boiler,
and I see that it has scrambled.
I'm thinking, "Oh, my goodness,
what am I gonna do?"
This...this is not
gonna work.
I'm trashing my orange curd
because I do not want to serve
scrambled eggs
to Duff and Valerie.
That would just be
unappetizing.
So, now, I am stressed.
VALERIE:
One hour left, bakers.
We want some cool
ice-cream-cone drip cakes.
Still no.
Hey, Alex,
what happened?
Um, yeah, I was making
an orange curd,
but it ended up
scrambling.
I threw out my orange curd,
and this is really bad
because this is a main component
of my cake.
So, you threw it away?
I just threw it out because
it would just not work.
Are you kidding me? You just,
like, threw out a whole --
and you're gonna start something
all over again?
Yeah.
I have to figure
something out
because this orange curd
took a while.
So, you've scrapped
the orange curd...
Yeah.
-...and now, you're going for...
Orange buttercream.
-Well, good luck!
-Thank you.
I'm trying to accomplish
the three flavors
of the rainbow sherbet,
so I get started on
my orange buttercream.
BEVERLY: Julia,
what are you making?
A raspberry- vanilla-swirl
cake...
-Awesome!
-...and then,
a vanilla buttercream.
JULIA: Two hours is not a lot
of time to make a cake
and have drips and have
an ice-cream cone on it.
When my batter is done,
I take some of it out
and put it in a medium bowl,
and I set that aside.
I slowly add in some raspberry
puree and red food dye,
and then, I swirl that
into my cakes.
I'm just lucky that I keep
getting something pink
because that's
my signature color.
LUKE: So, I think of butter
pecan as, like, sweet pecans.
So, I'm gonna melt butterscotch,
add that into my cake,
and also add
chocolate pecans.
My inspiration
is my dad.
He loves butter-pecan ice cream,
so we always have it
in the freezer in our house,
but I never eat it
'cause it doesn't
look great.
Man, I can't believe I put
my ice cream down earlier,
and now
I don't have any.
I'm super bummed.
VALERIE: Aw!
No!
-I think I have an idea.
-Really?
Mm-hmm. Bakers, may we have
your attention please?
Dun, dun, dun.
I scream.
Duff screams.
[ Screams ]
We all scream
for ice cream.
-Yes!
Yes!
I'm good at this.
I love ice cream
this much.
For this twist, you must make
actual ice cream
to serve
on the sides
of your ice-cream-cone
drip cake.
Fill up my cone!
LINSEY: Abby's pretty happy, and
everyone else is pretty happy.
-Boo-yah!
-I am not happy.
I don't want
to make ice cream.
Stay calm.
It's just so inconvenient
at the moment.
Okay, let's just start
making ice cream.
While I'm making
my Swiss meringue buttercream,
I also need to get started
on my ice cream.
While I'm trying to add
the butter to my buttercream,
I also need to try to make
a crème anglaise,
which is an
ice-cream base,
so I'm kind of two places
at once, and it's crazy.
I am multi-tasking
right now.
This is so...hard.
ABBY:
Mmm, perfect.
I love ice cream so much because
I'm from the dairy state,
Wisconsin.
Abby is whisking
and whisking.
She is whisking away
at her ice cream.
Got the baking guns
right here,
but I don't really know
how to make pistachio ice cream,
so, I think,
if I just make a classic vanilla
and add in
some toasted pistachios,
that will make the judges
really happy.
BEVERLY: Now, let me
whisk it up together.
I'm making
chocolate-chip ice cream.
Keep whisking!
I'm rushing a little to be the
first one in the ice cream maker
because there's only
two of them.
Oh, no, no, no.
Uh-oh. Beverly's cream for
her ice cream is boiling oven,
and that is not good.
Stop.
Go off.
Ugh! It boiled over.
The thing
with cream is, like,
you can't let it just sit there
and cook and cook and boil.
You heat it up.
As soon as it goes...
and starts coming up
and it's about to boil,
you take it off.
-Uh-huh.
And then, you start tempering it
into your egg.
I think I can save it.
I stir it,
and I turn the heat down,
and it goes back
to normal.
It's just a
little bit foamy.
So, I temper my eggs and get
that into the ice cream maker.
I just hope that
it doesn't, like, over-churn
or anything bad
happen to it.
Ah!
Duff, what is going on
with Beverly
and the
ice-cream machine?
I'm not sure.
That didn't work.
Bryn, what's your favorite type
of ice cream?
Probably peanut butter.
Peanut butter, nice.
I love ice cream.
I love to eat it.
Not so much making it,
but I love to eat it.
I am making a vanilla-raspberry
ice cream.
So, to make my crème anglaise,
I combine half-and-half
and heavy cream, and then
I swirl vanilla bean
to infuse that milk
with that vanilla flavor.
So, slowly, I add my dairy while
I'm whisking like a mad man,
so I don't get any
scrambled eggs
like I did in
my orange curd.
JULIA:
Looking good.
-How's everybody doing?
-Good.
I'm making a vanilla-raspberry
swirl ice cream
because I really want to stick
to the flavors.
This is so cool.
SOLEIL: I'm making
cookies-and-cream ice cream,
and it's gonna be
the best one
that Duff and Valerie
have ever had
because this ice cream maker is,
like, ginormous.
If I win, I'm just gonna
buy one for my house
so I can make ice cream
whenever I want.
What's up, Bryn?
What?
Oh, hey!
"What"?
Is this
ice-cream base?
-Yes.
-Awesome.
I've made ice cream
around four times in my years.
Were you happy
with the twist?
Um, I was okay about the twist,
but, you know,
y'all give us stuff, and we just
got to do it sometime.
So, I'm over here
slaving away.
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna make
a vanilla ice cream
with fresh-cut
strawberries in it
because it'll match
my Neapolitan ice-cream flavor.
Take it off.
I don't want to rush because
there's a really high chance
that you can
curdle your eggs,
and then, you have to start
all oven again.
Oh, no!
There's so much egg
that got cooked.
I don't have time
for this.
I started pouring out my crème
anglaise into a little strainer,
and I noticed that the eggs
got so scrambled.
And then, I take my cakes
out of the blast chiller...
Shoot.
...and it breaks right in half
when I try and flip it
to the right side.
And then,
as I'm leveling the cake...
Ooh, I cut my hand.
...everything just went wrong
at the same time --
everything, except for
my buttercream.
Thank you, buttercream.
It looks like Linsey's having
a bit of a meltdown.
Yeah.
My finger hurts.
My emotions hurt.
LUKE: I'm really happy
about the twist.
I'm gonna make
a peach ice cream.
I'm not gonna do
a crème anglaise
because that takes
a little bit more time,
and we're on
a time limit here.
I mix together heavy cream,
milk, and sugar.
Then, I add in a little bit
of vanilla extract.
In my blender,
I throw in peaches,
and then a little bit of cream,
and that's it.
It's that simple.
-Wait, you're already done?
-Yeah.
I'm just going make
a chocolate ice cream base
and sprinkle some peanut butter
chips throughout that.
I spill some of my crème
anglaise on myself and, like,
all over the place, so I guess
it's just, like, a messy day.
Hot!
SOLEIL: I'm seeing everyone else
pull out their cakes,
and I'm thinking, "I really need
to go check on mine
because I don't want it
to be over-baked."
Oh, that's so not done.
But I look and see
it's the complete opposite.
That's wonderful.
It is literally raw.
Okay.
I'm getting a little bit
nervous.
I think my cakes are raw because
I added way too much batter
to my cake pan.
Duff, check out Soleil.
This one
looks even worse.
I just cut the tops
off of my cakes
so that it will
bake quicker.
That is a really risky maneuver,
but she has to do it.
I can't really serve underbaked
cake to Duff and Valerie
'cause then they can't really
eat it, even.
So, I'm gonna go
put this back in.
This is cutting into
my decorating time.
My cake needs to hurry up
and bake.
Okay.
JULIA: I am decorating my cake
with vanilla buttercream,
and I'm hoping it'll make it
more raspberry.
And I add some
raspberry puree
because that will make
my frosting
a raspberry color
and taste.
I wish this were
real ice cream.
And then, I need to get started
on my ice-cream cone.
I want my frosting
to harden a little bit
before I put it on the cake,
so I put it in the freezer.
Beautiful!
ABBY: My ice cream is ready,
and it comes out perfect.
Cake frosting...
And now, it's time
to assemble my cake.
My drip cake is going to
stand out from everyone else's
because it's gonna be bright
green, like pistachio ice cream.
30 minutes, bakers!
30 minutes!
DUFF: Ice-cream-cone
drip cakes,
don't let your chance
at $25,000 melt away.
See, I see what
you did there.
-Melt...
-I see what you did there.
Ice cream melts.
[ Laughs ]
LINSEY:
Time is running out,
and I have so much decorating
and fixing to do.
Oh, wrong way.
I piece my cake back together
as best I can
and just start
frosting the outside.
I need to
get it together.
And then, I have to put
the drip topping on,
and I'm just running
out of time.
-How's everybody doing?
-Good.
ADITYA: I don't really
have a plan for decorating,
but I'm dying my peanut butter
buttercream blue
just because I just like
the color blue.
I just have to make
my drip.
I have to make sure that the
drips and the fake ice cream
match in color,
because otherwise,
it'll look really weird.
Girl: Is anyone frosting
their cakes yet?
LUKE: Yeah.
I'm frosting my cake, and it's
turning out pretty good.
Good job!
I make my
white-chocolate drip
by doing three parts white
chocolate, one part cream.
Then, I grab yellow food dye
and color it yellow
because I know yellow
goes well with brown.
How do you make the perfect
consistency for a drip cake?
All the bakers
are using something
a little bit
different.
Like, 1.2 to one.
You lost me.
You want a little bit more
cream by weight
than you do chocolate.
That's all.
BEVERLY:
I'm doing my drips.
The key is, make your drips
not too thin, not too thick,
and make your frosting
cool enough
that the drips aren't gonna
make the frosting drip, as well.
#Ilovedripcakes.
Somebody's timer!
It's mine.
BRYN: For my frosting,
I need it super smooth.
One, it looks really pretty,
and second-of-all,
when you put the drips, you
don't want it to be, like,
a lump,
and then it drips,
then it's like, "Woo."
SOLEIL: I baked
this one first.
I go back and check on my cakes,
and they are done.
My cake is still
pretty warm,
and that's not ideal, but I have
to start decorating now.
10 minutes left, bakers!
[ Suspenseful music plays ]
ABBY: My coating chocolate
is a little bit thick,
but I think that it looks good
against my buttercream.
LUKE: I'm starting to add
my drips.
I have made drip cakes
a few times before
because I love the style.
It's such a modern style
of cake decorating.
Yay!
I look at my cake,
and I'm actually pretty happy.
My drip cake screams "drip cake"
at my face.
5 minutes.
You got to go, go, go.
You got this, Soleil.
I know you can do it.
SOLEIL: Thank you.
There's 5 minutes left,
and my cake is still
in the beginning stages
of being frosted.
I'm crossing my fingers
and hoping for the best.
Oh, this is gonna look
so messy.
I just made ice cream.
ALEX: My ice cream smells like
vanilla bean and sweetness,
and it looks like heaven
inside of that little hotel pan.
I think I just
redeemed myself.
2 minutes, guys!
Now, I'm doing the drip
on my cake.
It's not, like,
covering the top well.
It's sort of
transparent.
Why can't one thing
just go right?
Oh, my God!
My ice cream is melted.
As I go to get my ice cream
out of the freezer,
I realize it's liquid.
Oh, no.
What the heck happened?
90 seconds, guys!
Oh, my God.
It's coming down
to the wire.
SOLEIL: Sprinkles,
more sprinkles...
Last minute, I decide my cake
is not good at all,
so I'm grabbing
some sprinkles.
VALERIE:
10...9...8...7...
DUFF and VALERIE: 6... 5...4...
3...2...1!
Hands up!
Man, cake and ice cream --
I love this job.
Abby, tell us
about your cake.
My cake is a pistachio cake
with a pistachio buttercream
and a coating
chocolate drip.
So, what flavor
did you get?
Not pistachio.
[ Laughter ]
Well, let's talk
about this cake.
I think it is
really nice.
I know for a fact that I'm gonna
taste pistachio.
Okay, now, with your drips --
your drips are really nice.
They could be
a lot nicer.
Your chocolate
was too cold.
Next time you do
a drip cake,
just make sure
it's a little bit warmer
so all those
melt into each other.
And then, it really does
look like you have a big thing
of pistachio ice cream
melting on top of your cake.
I think this cake
is absolutely stunning.
Whoa!
Oh, look at that.
That looks pretty.
I definitely
taste pistachio.
Pistachio
is all in there.
Abby,
that's a good cake.
Is that your recipe?
Uh, yes.
Keep it.
He is the king of cakes,
and he loves my cake.
I will be making this cake
forever and ever and ever
and ever and ever.
And your ice cream is
a vanilla ice cream
with toasted pistachios
mixed in.
Abby, those are -- are those
whole pistachios in there?
Yes.
I wanted you to get
the full crunch.
Tastes like pistachios.
Your ice cream is really good
and really smooth.
I'm definitely tasting
the pistachios
'cause there's
so many of them.
Okay.
-Thanks, Abby.
-Thank you.
Thanks, Abby.
Overboard
with the pistachios?
What?
Bryn. So, let's see,
you got bubblegum ice cream.
-No.
-No. You got Rocky Road?
No.
Chocolate raspberry?
No. You're getting further
and further away.
Neapolitan!
Neapolitan! Totally!
All right, Bryn,
tell us about your cake.
I made a chocolate-and-vanilla
cake
and then,
strawberry-buttercream frosting.
I see vanilla, strawberry,
and chocolate,
and I see drips going
all the way around.
I love that you did
the three flavors.
Thank you.
Your icing job
is really good.
You didn't just do a crumb coat,
which is great.
I'm excited about this.
So, you made two different
cake batters.
Yes.
Pretty cool.
I taste a little bit
of chocolate,
and a little bit
of vanilla.
I think both of your cakes
are a little dry.
Okay.
A moist cake is just heaven,
and a dry cake is, like,
"Well, what's the point?"
But I am getting
Neapolitan.
I got strawberry flavor,
I got chocolate flavor,
and I got vanilla.
Nice.
-Thank you.
What about
your ice cream?
My ice cream flavor is
vanilla ice cream
with strawberries in it.
This is rich!
I'm tasting strawberry.
It looks like
vanilla pudding.
At least they like
the frosting,
and all the flavors went really,
really well together.
-Thanks, Bryn.
-Bye!
Bye!
All right. Aditya,
what did you make today?
I got chocolate
and peanut butter.
Mmm, my favorite.
-Yep.
-My favorite.
I made a chocolate cake
with peanut butter buttercream
and peanut butter chips.
Why the color green for
chocolate and peanut butter?
I don't know.
I just like that color.
What flavor
is your buttercream?
My buttercream
is peanut-butter flavored.
It's blue!
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, it's weird.
That's weird.
Own it.
It's weird.
Uh, yeah, I guess, yeah.
But blue is my favorite color,
so I guess that's why I did it.
For drip cakes, you want a
ganache that's thick enough
that it will not go all the way
to the board, like this one did.
It looks like, here,
your ganache was just too thin.
Okay.
And tell us about
your ice cream.
I made a chocolate-peanut-butter
ice cream.
That looks like
chocolate peanut butter.
Mmm.
Nice, smooth
consistency.
Your ice cream
is really good,
you know,
it's really smooth.
It's really chocolate-y.
It's nice.
That's peanut butter
chocolate chip.
My mind is boggled
about this green.
Yeah. I mean, it really looks
like chocolate mint, now.
Yeah,
that's chocolate mint.
**
Dude!
That is such a moist
chocolate cake.
It is so yummy.
It is moist.
It is chocolate-y.
The buttercream
is peanut-buttery.
I just closed my eyes.
But the inside -- you nailed it.
Golly,
did you nail it --
except for the peanut butter
and the green.
It's like,
"No, no, no, no."
Never, ever do that again
with your chocolate cake.
-Okay.
-Thank you.
-Goodbye.
-Thanks.
-Okay, bye.
-See you.
ADITYA: I'm half-thinking that
I could be going home right now,
but the other half of me
is thinking, like,
"You'll be fine."
-Soleil...
-Hi.
-Hi!
-How's it going?
I'm good.
I got
cookies and cream.
So, I made
cookies-and-cream cake
with cookies-and-cream
frosting
and a hot-pink
chocolate drizzle.
I don't know if this is
a successful drip cake.
It is a cake.
-Yeah.
And there are definitely
drips on it.
But I don't think you controlled
the drips like you wanted to.
No.
Not really.
All right.
Let's cut this thing.
Let's cut it.
Oh, I'm getting through
all the cookies.
Wow.
That's a lot of sugar
on top.
I'm gonna avoid the layer
of sugar on the top.
I think that might be
a good idea.
Soleil, that's a really
fabulously moist cake.
Thank you.
Your buttercream is cookies and
cream, no doubt about it, good.
Your cake, though, while good,
I believe, was over-mixed.
What about
your ice cream?
Cookies-and-cream
ice cream.
That looks like real, real
cookies-and-cream ice cream.
Mm-hmm.
Tastes like it, too.
That is a really good
cookies-and-cream ice cream.
-Wow.
-Thank you.
All right. Well,
look, you know,
things taste pretty good,
but -- cake.
I think the cake
is very moist.
I'm more disappointed
in your decorations.
I know you can
do better,
and this is really not the mess
that I expect from you.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-See you, Soleil.
Bye.
Linsey. Tell us
what you got today,
and tell us how
your day went.
So, today,
I got mint chip.
I made for you
a mint-chocolate-chip cake
with a Swiss-meringue
buttercream
and a chocolate-ganache
drip topping.
You made
a Swiss meringue?
-Yeah.
-Wow.
Awesome.
I'm wondering
about your cake here
'cause it's not
Linsey-themed.
It's a bit messy.
Well, the cake kind of broke
into, like, a bunch of pieces.
Oh, are you kidding me?
So, I just, like, tried to
stick it back -- sorry.
Ugh.
Okay.
It's okay.
So, I just tried to stick it
back together the best I could.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
What's going on
with you right now?
It just, like, everything kind
of fell apart at the same time,
and it was just a little hard to
piece everything back together.
The more words that come out,
the more water coming out, too.
I'm just preparing myself
for the worst right now.
I was just not thinking
about my cake,
and just remembering
all the bad things.
I don't have time
for this.
And having to say it
to Duff and Valerie
just put all these things
in my head.
I definitely think you're being
a little too hard on yourself,
because your cake
is round.
VALERIE: Yeah.
So, it's all right.
I have a finished cake
in front of me.
It's just a messy cake.
Let's taste it.
-All right.
You've got mint in your
buttercream and in your cake?
Well, just in my cake.
Oh. That's a lot
of mint flavor.
Mm-hmm.
It definitely tastes like
mint-chocolate-chip ice cream.
That much on the verge
of putting too much mint in,
but I love it.
-Okay.
-And you use a nice
dark chocolate.
What about
your ice cream?
I also made a
mint-chocolate-chip ice cream.
I want to eat
this ice cream.
It's minty.
It's chocolaty, not particularly
creamy, like ice cream, though.
Okay.
Linsey, go breathe.
All right.
So embarrassed.
-Luke.
-Hello.
-How's it going?
-Good.
So, tell us about the flavor
of ice cream that you picked.
Butter pecan.
Interesting. So, what kind
of cake did you make us?
A butter-pecan cake with
vanilla butter-cream frosting
and a white-chocolate drip.
Is there supposed to be, like,
a moosh of ice cream?
Yeah.
I think it melted.
I think your cake was
a little bit on the warm side
when you put
the buttercream on.
This almost looks like
your crumb coat.
Let's dig into this.
The pecans
are coming through.
The buttercream isn't
overly sweet, which I like.
Luke, I taste it.
Yeah, I really taste
butter pecan.
I think you could have gotten
some more pecan flavor.
Whenever you're working with
nuts, toast them, always.
And tell us about
your ice cream.
LUKE: I made a peach
ice cream.
Peach ice cream
with butter pecan?
Are you working for the state
of Georgia, by any chance?
No.
I don't know
what that means.
Well, it's an
interesting duo.
Good ice cream.
It's nice and smooth,
but I'm not getting any peaches.
The only peach I'm getting
is that piece that's in there.
-Okay.
-Thanks, Luke.
Thank you.
Hi, Beverly.
BEVERLY: Hello.
You don't have as big a smile
on your face as you usually do.
What's going on?
My ice cream melted.
It wouldn't firm up.
So, tell us
what flavor you got.
I got the chocolate-chip
ice cream.
I have made a vanilla cake
with chocolate chips in it,
a crushed-up
chocolate-chip buttercream,
and chocolate drips,
and a chocolate-chip ice cream.
The ganache is obviously
a little thin
'cause there's a lot of drips on
your cake board.
Why did you choose
the orange?
Orange is my favorite color.
And it reminds me of my cat,
my snake, and my goldfish
that I won at the carnival
2 months ago.
And he's still alive.
There's so much information
in that.
I'm getting chocolate-chip
ice cream, though.
Yay.
It's a little on
the dry side.
That's why
she made a sauce.
**
VALERIE: Wow.
Uh-oh.
The ice cream
is delicious.
Well, I should say
the ice cream...
-Soup is delicious.
-...the soup is delicious.
It's tasty,
but it's not ice cream.
-Yeah.
-It's crème anglaise.
-And it's really sweet.
It's crème anglaise.
-Thanks, Beverly.
-Thank you, Beverly.
-Bye.
-See you.
Super dry
and super sweet.
-Yeah -- yeah.
-Yeah.
Julia.
Hi.
I got vanilla
raspberry swirl.
Mm-hmm.
I made a vanilla swirl
with raspberry cake
and then,
a vanilla buttercream,
And for the ice-cream cone,
I did a raspberry buttercream.
-Oh, okay.
-Cool.
I'm a little worried
about coating chocolate
on top of the cake, but it did
make for a beautiful color.
-Yeah.
But it's not gonna taste
like raspberry.
Okay.
That's dark.
Just a little dark.
Yeah, like, I cut that off
in the second layer.
I didn't do it
to the first.
You should have.
[ Laughter ]
That's a deliciously
moist cake.
I'm not getting
a lot of raspberry.
Yeah.
Much more of that raspberry
swirl needs to be in there.
Yeah, more raspberry.
It's a delicious
cake, though.
Yay.
All right, Julia,
tell us about your ice cream.
I made a vanilla ice cream,
and then,
I swirled in raspberry puree.
It's not too sweet, which I
really, really appreciate.
Thank you.
Your cake was so good,
and just, you know,
I don't know what to say
about your ice cream.
The ice cream
is perfect.
-Yay.
-Perfect.
You were scaring me.
It is delicious.
It is smooth.
I got a subtle
raspberry flavor.
I could use
a little bit more.
But, man,
it is perfect.
-Thanks, Julia.
-Thank you.
Scared her.
You scared me.
I'm like,
"What did Duff taste
that I didn't taste?"
Hey, Alex.
Okay, so,
I got rainbow sherbert,
and I made a key-lime cake
with a raspberry
and an orange frosting.
Yeah, I guess rainbow sherbert
is, you know,
kind of bright,
kind of acidic.
Okay.
Is is rainbowy?
It looks like you just
went with your crumb coat.
Yeah.
A timing issue.
Do you know how to
ice a cake?
Oh, yeah.
-Oh, yeah.
Please, okay. Please.
Please.
He just didn't want to do it
for us today.
Even though I know
this is not your best work,
I can tell you know
how to ice a cake,
because this is
a crumb coat.
-Ouch.
-But how does it taste,
I wonder?
We'll see.
It would have
been fun...
I know that Duff
doesn't like food coloring,
but just a little bit
of food coloring,
just so it looked
like lime.
Here, you could
definitely get away with
a little food coloring.
Why didn't I
think of that?
It's a tiny bit
overbaked.
I'm tasting orange
more than anything.
I don't taste lime.
It's nice.
It's refreshing.
I don't know if it screams
"rainbow sherbert."
Let's try
your ice cream.
I made a classic vanilla
ice cream, and then I topped it
with a raspberry
and some yellow sprinkles
'cause I love sprinkles
and I love the color yellow.
Okay.
It's a really delicious
vanilla ice cream.
Thank you.
Creamy, smooth,
lots of vanilla.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Alex.
Bye.
I am feeling really scared
'cause I got a lot of criticism
from the judges.
I do not want to be
the fourth boy to go home.
Like,
that would be crazy.
ANNOUNCER: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive a sweet
prize package
that includes a feature story
in Food Network Magazine...
-Yes.
-...and...
$25,000 dollars.
[ All screaming
and cheering ]
Drip cakes
are really tough,
and a few kids had
a few problems today.
Yeah. Like Soleil with her
cookies-and-cream cake.
SOLEIL: This is gonna
look so messy.
She got something on the plate,
and she made a cake.
It was crazy-looking.
So, what really hurt her was
making the cake way too thick.
She shouldn't have filled
those cake pans up that high.
That cake had drips on it
that weren't intentional.
But her ice cream
was really good.
Mm-hmm.
This lime smells delicious.
I was really disappointed in
Alex's rainbow-sherbert cake.
It tasted like
orange sherbert,
but I don't know what the
decoration looked like to me.
Yeah. And I feel like,
you know, decorating-wise,
when somebody says "rainbow,"
you can go to town.
Like, he could have made
something vibrant and
colorful, and he didn't.
Yeah. Basically, Alex made
an overbaked orange cake.
Yep.
BEVERLY:
I'm doing my chips.
I got to bring up Beverly
and her chocolate-chip cake.
The ganache
was too thin.
The cake was dry.
And the ice cream
was crème anglaise.
It's so upsetting.
You know, I don't know if
Beverly really did the challenge
because she didn't produce
an ice cream.
Oh, no. Yeah, there was
no ice cream there.
That didn't work.
Everybody made an ice cream --
even a bad one.
But, then again, Soleil
didn't produce drip cake.
It was a cake
that had drips on it.
Ish.
A lot of bakers
struggled today.
Bakers, in this Game of Cone
Cakes, a lot of you had issues.
In fact, only one baker
really brought it all together.
And that baker is...
Abby.
Good job.
Being the only kid to win today
is an awesome feeling to have.
You made a stunning pistachio
ice-cream-cone drip cake.
The drips were nice
and clean.
The cake was moist.
And the whole thing
screamed "pistachio,"
especially your ice cream --
wink, wink.
Congratulations, Abby,
you are in the top spot today.
Thank you.
This proves that I could
definitely win.
Now, a few other
cake-and-ice-cream combos
were good,
but not great.
However, they will keep you
around for another week.
Those bakers are...
Bryn...
-Good job.
-Yes.
...Aditya...
...Luke...
...Linsey...
Oh, I won.
Thank you.
DUFF:
...and...
Julia.
-Good job.
You're all safe.
Unfortunately, that leaves
Soleil, Alex, and Beverly.
Please step forward.
Not again.
ALEX: Throughout
this whole competition,
I'm like
a roller coaster.
Week 4,
I'm on the bottom again.
This is not good.
We're all great bakers,
don't forget that.
I agree.
All three of you
took this challenge head on,
but each of you made mistakes
we just couldn't overlook.
Soleil, your cookies-and-cream
cake was over-mixed,
and the whole thing
was really messy.
And for some reason,
you tried to fix it
with a pound
of sanding sugar.
DUFF:
Beverly, the ganache on your
chocolate-chip cake was thin,
and the cake itself
was dry.
And the thing is, this was a
cake and ice-cream challenge,
and your ice cream
was soup.
Yeah.
Alex, you had a chance
to impress us
with your rainbow-sherbert
drip cake, and you fell short.
It should have been colorful,
and it wasn't.
And the cake was
slightly overbaked.
The baker leaving us
today is...
Beverly.
So sorry, Beverly.
We are not gonna forget you.
Seriously.
-You are unforgettable.
Please keep baking,
'cause you're awesome.
Okay.
I will.
We'll miss you, Beverly.
-Bye, Beverly.
-We're gonna miss you.
I had lots of fun while I was
here, and I'll never forget it.
-You never stop baking, okay?
-Thank you.
#KidsBakingChampionshipRocks.
DUFF: Previously on "Kids
Baking Championship"...
Ice cream cone drip cakes.
And you must make
actual ice cream.
ABBY: I got pistachio.
I know for a fact that I'm
gonna to taste pistachio.
Only one baker really
brought it all together.
And that baker is Abby.
Soleil, your cookies
and cream cake was messy.
Beverly, this was a cake
and ice cream challenge,
and your ice cream
was soup.
The baker leaving us
today is Beverly.
**
Hmm. Which one
do you like the best?
Hmm.
That one looks like
coffee-cup stains.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Yeah, I'm going towards
that one, too.
Yeah.
Why did they just set up
an art exhibit?
Oh, hi, bakers.
-Hi.
-Hey, guys.
-Do you like our art gallery?
-Yeah.
-It's pretty.
This is your inspiration
for today's Big Bake.
What?
Today you will be making
an artful design
with doughnuts.
-Yes.
-Oh, my gosh.
And you'll be doing it...
in teams.
-Yes.
Yes, yes.
Oh, they like it.
Now, to choose your team,
you will each
take a doughnut.
On the back of the doughnut,
there will be a number
and the same numbers
will pair up.
Thank you.
Turn your doughnuts
over and pair up.
-I got two.
-I got one.
-I'm one.
-Are you one?
Yay.
Okay, so here's our teams,
Bryn and Soleil,
Luke and Linsey,
Aditya and Alex...
I think it can work out.
I think that we can
really work this out.
DUFF:
...Abby and Julia.
You each must individually
bake and decorate
one dozen doughnuts.
Then as a team, you will put
your two different doughnuts
together on one board
to create a unified design
that's good enough
to appear in our gallery.
I've never been
in an art gallery.
Walk around
and you're like...
That is not true.
Yeah, it is.
It's not...
You've never been to one.
How do you know?
I've seen one on TV,
in cartoons.
VALERIE: Your individual
doughnut will determine
whether you stay
or go home.
All right.
Bakers, you have 2 hours.
Are you ready?
-Yeah.
Your baking time
starts...
now.
-Now!
ALEX:
You got it, dude.
**
-Let's put it by the sink.
-Okay. Okay.
I decided to make
a strawberry doughnut
with coconut glaze.
Okay, okay.
So I was thinking maybe, like,
a chocolate doughnut, like,
cookies and cream, with, like,
a cream cheese glaze kind of.
Okay.
What kind of design
do we want to do?
We could do...We'll figure
it out when we start baking.
You could do
lemon blueberry.
Yeah.
So you're doing the...
-Bacon maple?
-Yeah.
Soleil had this great idea
to make doughnut flavors
for Duff and Valerie.
You ever try to nail
a doughnut to a wall?
It doesn't work.
Duff loves bacon,
and I have a great recipe
for maple bacon doughnuts.
I was thinking make it
shaped like a doughnut.
Okay.
We're gonna try
to make this look
like a doughnut made
out of doughnuts.
We grabbed some felt pieces
to map out our plan...
Say the hole is, like,
right here.
BOTH: Our team name is
The Doughnut Ladies.
I'm so happy
that I got her...
We're really excited.
...because she's amazing.
-Like, this is the glaze.
-Yeah.
-Oh, I like it.
-Do you see it?
-Yeah, I see it.
-I see it.
So I was thinking, like,
we could make, like,
a strawberry sort of thing,
where it's like this.
And if I do key lime,
I could dye it, like, green.
I was thinking
I would do cinnamon.
With a red frosting,
then I could make
a little strawberry.
ABBY: Julia wants to make
a strawberry design,
but it's going
to be really had
to make a strawberry
on a peg board.
ABBY: Should we just make it,
like, abstract?
Not try
to make a strawberry.
Okay.
I need to come up
with the perfect design.
What about this?
It's like a swirl.
Ah, these circles are
giving me a headache.
Let's get the doughnuts
done first.
JULIA: Okay.
Let's go.
So I'm gonna be doing
maple bacon popcorn.
So then mine would be,
I guess,
kind of colorful-ish.
-Yeah.
-So you know what?
I'll just pull together
my batter,
and then I can
flavor it later.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
BRYN: I'm so excited.
I could eat doughnuts
for breakfast every day.
I'm gonna start by making
the actual batter part
for my maple bacon doughnut.
So I sift together flour,
baking powder and salt.
I use the sifter so when
I mix it all together,
it won't be all clumpy.
For my wet ingredients,
I combine eggs, sugar,
milk, vanilla extract
and vegetable oil.
Then I fold the dry ingredients
into the wet ingredients
and mix them all together.
Soleil, how you
doing over there?
I'm doing good,
how about you?
Good.
I am making a blueberry
doughnut with lemon glaze
and blueberry drizzle on top.
I want to use whole blueberries
because when Duff and Valerie
bite into my doughnut,
I want them to just taste
the juice and the sweetness.
DUFF:
15 minutes down, guys.
You got an hour,
45 left.
I'm from Canada.
We love our maple syrup,
and we love our bacon,
so I'm doing, like,
a maple bacon doughnut.
And then since I love snacking
on popcorn all the time,
I think I'm going
to add that, too.
Maple syrup is one of
the national flavors
and one of the national
foods of Canada.
Everyone in Canada
loves maple syrup.
The doughnut part is basically
just a regular doughnut batter,
which I added some ground nutmeg
to give it more flavor,
and then I alternate between
milk and my flour mixture.
If you were to put, like, all
the milk at once and then mix it
and then put all
the flour at once,
the consistency of your doughnut
would be very,
like, dense, really,
really dense.
It looks perfect.
I hope this doughnut
makes Canada proud.
-Alex.
-Yeah?
I can do
a spiced doughnut.
ALEX:
That would sound good.
Okay, so you think that would
go with maple bacon, though?
It sounds
kind of, like, gross.
The flavors aren't supposed
to go together, dude.
They can be like
completely different.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm making a spiced doughnut
with a lavender glaze.
I've never used lavender before,
and I thought that would be a
good idea for a spiced doughnut.
To flavor the glaze,
I need to get my lavender
to steep in the milk.
Then I put my spices
into the doughnut batter
and that's that.
**
This is a handy tool.
I am making a strawberry
doughnut with coconut glaze
because I think those two
flavors go really well together.
I replaced some of the milk
with the strawberries
because I don't want
too many liquids.
I really want a natural
strawberry flavor
in the doughnut.
I don't want to get, like,
an extract or anything,
but I'm just afraid that the
strawberry may be too subtle.
It's fine.
How is everyone doing?
-Good.
What flavor are you making?
Cookies and cream.
My inspiration for this
is my love
for chocolate sandwich cookies.
If I put those
and a doughnut together,
it would just be
deliciousness.
I'm gonna make
a chocolate doughnut
to represent the cookie.
I add in cocoa powder
to make it chocolate,
and I'm gonna make
a cream cheese icing
to represent
the cream inside,
and then crush up
sandwich cookies
and sprinkle them on top.
I want to make
some doughnut art.
I'm gonna polka dot myself.
Look, kids, I'm art.
You should walk
around like that.
**
Just cinnamon.
I love cinnamon rolls, so I'm
making a cinnamon roll doughnut
with a cream cheese glaze.
And my sister's favorite
food is doughnuts,
so I hope that I do her justice.
I used the hand mixer
because the stand mixer
doesn't reach
the bottom of the bowl,
and it's much easier
with the hand mixer
to combine ingredients.
30 minutes down, bakers.
You have an hour
and a half left.
Will you be around
after this challenge?
Wow, that's so funny.
I'm making a key lime doughnut
because my signature baked item,
especially because I'm from
Florida, is a key lime pie.
To get the key lime pie
flavor into my doughnut,
I add lime juice and lime
zest into my batter.
Bakers, can we have
your attention, please?
You've got
to be kidding me.
What is that?
DUFF: Doughnuts
are great and all,
but doughnuts with texture
are a whole lot better.
-What?
-Texture?
We have Macadamia nuts,
potato chips,
graham crackers...
-Dang it.
I have to get the graham
crackers off that texture bar.
What's key lime pie
without a graham cracker crust?
...peanuts, pretzels,
cornflakes,
chocolate wafers
and fruit cereal.
You must grab one texture
from our texture bar
and incorporate it
into your doughnuts.
Come on up and grab one.
-Just one.
Just one,
you cannot share.
Chocolate wafer cookies.
LUKE: Fruit cereal?
Fruit cereal is awesome,
go with it.
-Wait, what did you need?
-Graham cracker.
Here, wait.
Does pretzels go
with cinnamon?
You can't share
with your teammate.
I have to keep
my graham crackers.
Blech.
I have no idea.
Luke,
that's a good one.
-Okay.
-I promise.
I don't know how to incorporate
this with chocolate.
-What is it?
-Fruit cereal.
LUKE: Fruit cereal really
doesn't go well with my
doughnut,
and I don't know what to do.
**
VALERIE:
Doughnut designs.
You must grab one texture
from our texture bar
and incorporate it
into your doughnuts.
LUKE: Fruit cereal?
DUFF: Fruit cereal is awesome.
Go with it.
The twist is, we have to add
in a crunchy component
into our doughnuts...
I don't know how to incorporate
it with chocolate.
...and I get fruit cereal.
Of course.
I was the last one up there,
so I got stuck with it.
Fruit and chocolate
is good.
I feel like it really
doesn't go well
with my cookies
and cream doughnut,
so I'm gonna crunch
them up real fine
so you don't
really taste them,
you just get
the crunch from them.
I pipe my doughnuts
into the pan
and just sprinkle
the cereal on top
before I bake my doughnuts.
I'm getting frustrated.
Luke is putting, like,
the tiniest amount
of the fruit cereal
on his doughnuts
before he's baking it.
Bake it, frost it,
take that doughnut,
stick it in there,
cover that thing.
Is that the sound that
it makes when a doughnut...
Yeah, okay.
**
Whatever.
This will go fine with it.
It doesn't taste different.
Now that I have pretzels
for my twist,
I'm switching the graham cracker
crumbs for pretzel crumbs.
I'm going for
a key lime pie thing,
so this will be
like the crust.
Hour and 15 minutes left,
bakers!
JULIA: I put my pretzel crust on
top of my doughnut batter,
and put it in the oven.
Glaze is usually just powdered
sugar and some sort of liquid.
For the key lime glaze,
I'm only doing powdered sugar,
juice and zest.
How are you feeling, Julia?
Oh, good.
Are these cinnamon
graham crackers?
**
Nope.
I'm really happy that I was
able to get graham crackers
for the texture twist
because I know that it goes
very well with cinnamon.
I'm going to make a graham
cracker cinnamon crumble,
so I crush them up
in the food processor
and add some sugar,
butter and cinnamon
and sprinkle that on
the tops of my doughnuts
so that it will form a nice
crunchy texture and crust.
Whenever we make cinnamon rolls,
they have a cream
cheese frosting,
so I'm adding in some cream
cheese in my glaze.
**
That's pretty good.
Linsey, what'd you get?
Chocolate wafer cookies.
I grabbed the chocolate
wafer cookies
for my strawberry
coconut doughnut
because I know there's, like,
some chocolate coconut candies
out there and chocolate,
strawberry, that's a no-brainer.
I put it in a piping bag,
crush it up
and just top my doughnuts
with the cookies.
-Those look good.
-Thanks.
LINSEY: I don't know if they're
strawberry enough though.
Now that my doughnuts
are in the oven,
I start working on my glaze.
Since I want it to be
coconut-flavored,
I just use coconut milk,
but kind of eyeball it.
It's too thin.
Just add either coconut milk
or powdered sugar
until I get the desired texture.
The consistency has to be,
like, just right
so it's not too, like, watery,
and it won't completely
soak into the doughnut,
but it also kind of
just stays on the top.
**
It's coconut-y.
Bryn, how are you
gonna use yours?
Are you just gonna crush
them up and put it in there?
-Probably.
-Okay.
I'm so glad that I did
not pipe my batter yet
because I can put
this twist right in.
My twist ingredient
is macadamia nuts.
I knew this was pretty much
the only thing that I could grab
because it's, like,
one of the only things
that goes with my lemon
blueberry doughnut.
Maybe I want to toast these.
I want to roast
these macadamia nuts
because that brings out
the natural flavors
and it gives them
a nice crunch.
Then I pulse them up
until they are nice
and small and fold
them into my batter.
**
To make my lemon glaze,
I'm mixing powdered sugar
with lemon juice.
I don't want to not have enough
lemon in there for Valerie,
so I need a lot
of lemon juice.
Is there a doctor in the house?
I'm seeing spots.
**
They're like
two big eyeballs.
I see you.
**
Cornflakes are kind of
all texture and no flavor,
so I'm going to just incorporate
some into the batter
and pulse some
of the cornflakes up
and sprinkle those on top,
that would also give
the doughnut a good texture.
The best doughnuts will
keep you in the running
for all the dough...
nuts.
I feel pretty good about
getting the potato chips
because I'm making
a maple bacon doughnut,
and the potato chips
add a little bit more saltiness
to go with my bacon.
You can't really put potato
chips into the doughnut
because it would be
kind of soggy,
so the only thing
that I can really do
is crush them up
and put them on the top.
So I set it aside and start
on my candied bacon.
I make a candied glaze
by mixing together sugar,
brown sugar and maple syrup
and brush it all over my bacon.
I put that in the oven
until it's medium,
in between soft and crispy.
Great.
I do not like peanuts
by themselves.
They're just weird.
What am I gonna do
with peanuts?
I don't want to use them,
but you know what?
I have to.
What can I do with nuts?
Caramelize them.
Caramelize the peanuts?
So when I'm thinking of texture,
I'm thinking of maybe like a
brittle or a caramelized peanut,
so I go with
caramelized peanuts.
Does anybody have
the maple syrup?
-Was that Alex that asked that?
-Mm-hmm.
-I do.
-Can I use it?
-Yep.
-Thank you.
You're welcome.
To make my caramelized peanuts,
I take brown sugar,
milk, maple syrup,
and then I add in my peanuts.
Once my peanuts are
in the caramel,
I put my bacon in the oven.
Bacon.
I take my doughnuts out when
they start turning golden brown
and check them
with a toothpick.
Came out clean.
They are done.
Alex.
-Yeah?
Do you have the maple syrup
over there?
Yeah, I do.
Trade off.
Again.
Are you doing
maple bacon, too?
Yeah.
ALEX: Bryn is not Canadian.
I am.
Mine is gonna be better.
Stay out of my territory.
BRYN:
I'm not worried at all.
Mine is gonna taste
the best and look the best.
I'm making a maple glaze
by combining maple syrup,
milk and powdered sugar.
I glaze it first
by dipping the top
of the doughnut
into my glaze,
and then I want a little bit
more coverage on it,
so I just end up pouring it
on top of my doughnuts.
My plan is to sprinkle
my candied bacon
and potato chips on top.
Ow.
I'm doing a lavender
kind of glaze...
Cool.
...so I'm gonna
make it purple.
So I think...
-All right.
...those will
go together, right?
I think this will really
work out pretty well.
Booyah.
I'm making a lavender
glaze with cardamom.
It's a really popular spice
in Indian deserts.
I strain the lavender
out of the milk
and add some of
the purple food coloring.
I'm going for the subtle
lavender color
rather than a really
bright purple color.
There's a bit of a,
like, zing to it.
I definitely
taste the lavender.
One hour left, bakers.
All right.
I'm ready to start my glaze.
I'll use a little bit
of maple extract
because I really
want it to be strong.
I'm mixing it like
a mad man, eh?
Maple glaze is delicious.
Hot, hot, hot.
My doughnuts look good.
Crispy bacon.
And I think this bacon,
I'm gonna have
dreams about it later.
Suddenly, I realized that
I forgot about my peanuts.
Uh-oh.
Oh, my goodness.
This is solidified.
Geez.
They are the consistency
of a rock.
Oh, my God.
I don't know if I can fix this.
**
LINSEY: These are done.
VALERIE:
One dozen doughnuts.
Then you got
to work as a team
to make
a doughnut design.
50 minutes left.
ALEX: It's solidified.
My caramelized peanuts
are solidified.
Not good.
This has solidified quite a bit,
so I need to thin
it out somehow.
I add about
a tablespoon of milk,
and it's not working for me,
so I add more until it becomes
that thick caramel consistency.
I think this will be okay.
Go nuts for doughnuts.
I have to go with it because
I still have to put the glaze
and my bacon on top
of the doughnuts.
SOLEIL: Oh, your doughnuts
look good.
I just glazed them twice
because, well, maple glaze,
it's delicious so...
Once my two layers
of glaze is dried,
I put my bacon and my
caramelized peanut clusters.
**
I get my glaze on my doughnuts,
and I sprinkle on some
of the cornflake crumbs.
I think I'll get
a bunch of texture
from sprinkling the cornflakes
on top of the doughnut.
LUKE: After I take my doughnuts
out of the oven,
I just throw them
right in the blast chiller.
I needed them to cool because
I don't want it to be all hot
and just melt the icing.
It's a chocolate doughnut
and then a cream cheese icing,
which is basically
cookies and cream.
You can see the fruit cereal
on top of the doughnuts,
but when I ice it,
those colors will disappear,
and then I sprinkle
sandwich cookies
and milk chocolate chips
to drizzle on top.
I just want to hide the flavor
of the fruit cereal.
Luke, when you finish
with your glaze,
do you want
to plan it out?
-Yeah.
-All right.
I still have
a little bit to go.
LINSEY: I put the coconut glaze
on top of my doughnuts,
then I take some
of the desiccated coconut,
sprinkle it on.
Take some red sanding sugar
and I'll sprinkle that
on top to indicate
that there's strawberry
in my doughnut.
I think my doughnuts
are looking really pretty,
but now we have to make a design
on a board that looks like art.
Try, like, an "X."
Actually, no, I don't know.
-No.
We don't exactly know
what to do because it's hard
to make a design
with circles.
Let's try that box thing.
Why do doughnuts
have to be so hard?
Oh, we can go in
and make a diamond...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
...because I only
I have two left.
Hi, guys.
What you doing?
We're trying
to make our design.
You just pulled one
totally away.
You weren't crazy
about it?
Yeah.
We just got a good idea.
You got a good idea?
Well, have at it.
I don't want to interrupt.
We finally settle
on this diamond design.
So now
we each have one left.
**
We have
two doughnuts left.
Okay, what do we do
with the extra ones?
We can just put
something right there.
-Yeah, in the corners.
-Okay.
-That's what we're gonna do.
-Okay, let's go.
It's settled.
Done.
So scared
I'm gonna drop one.
-Push this in more.
-Yeah.
All right.
Guys, 20 minutes left.
To glaze my doughnuts,
I take the bottom part of it,
since it's a smoother part,
and I dip it in about halfway.
So are we doing the swirl?
-Yeah.
Yeah, I think the swirl
was better.
ABBY: We don't have to use
red and green,
because I would do pink.
Red and green looks
too Christmas-y,
so I'm going to dye
my glaze beautifully pink
because pink is
my favorite color.
-I do. I like pink more.
-I like pink more.
Look at the apron.
Look at the doughnut.
Well,
my whole room is pink.
Me, too.
Well,
I have pink doughnuts.
Mm-kay.
I got the graham crackers
and the pink.
Ugh.
Julia, I'm gonna put
teal sprinkles on mine.
Do you want to put, like,
pink sprinkles on yours?
That's a good idea, yeah.
What a great idea.
We could use sprinkles
that are the same colors
as each other's glaze.
Matching sprinkles, it is.
The doughnuts are
looking really good.
Now Abby and I need to get
our swirl assembled
on the peg board.
-Does it fit?
-Yeah.
Soleil, what kind of doughnut
are you making?
Lemon blueberry.
Lemon juice is not going
to make my glaze
yellow enough for my taste.
I think I'm gonna try using
the air-brush machine.
It looks so cool.
I want to use
the air-brush machine
because I've never
actually used one before,
and it looks super cool,
so I just want to, like,
lightly add a little bit
more yellow color.
Okay.
To decorate, I made, like,
a blueberry compote
with blueberries, lemon juice,
lemon zest and sugar.
Then I made some candied
Macadamia nuts to put on top.
I'm about to be finished.
I just need to do
a couple more things.
Okay.
To assemble my doughnuts,
I put my potato chips
and candied bacon on top,
and there you go,
you have the maple bacon
potato chip doughnut.
13 minutes, bakers.
Okay, so one row of mine,
yours, mine,
well, kind of mine
and yours and yours.
To decorate our doughnut canvas,
we're going to try to do
a zigzag kind of pattern.
Yo, how are you doing?
-How's it going?
-Great.
What's the plan?
-A zigzag.
-Okay.
ADITYA: It's going to be
more mathematical
but still, like, art.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Should we flip it
so it's like this,
or do you think this way?
Um, I think it was good
the way it was.
-Okay. Good.
-All right.
I'm just gonna eat
one of these doughnuts.
-No.
-He's like, "No."
I need them.
I hope it's going to work.
Yeah, it's a design.
VALERIE:
Time is ticking away.
What can you do to make
that design the absolute best?
LUKE: This actually
looks really cool.
These kind of look
awkward, though.
We're making a doughnut
out of doughnuts.
SOLEIL:
Bryn and I grabbed dowels,
started sticking them
in everywhere,
and then we put
our doughnuts on.
Does that look
like a doughnut?
Yeah. Do you think it looks
I think so.
SOLEIL: We think it looks
like a doughnut.
You see the cake part
and then you see the frosting
like that.
Like that.
It looks like art,
I'm pretty sure.
DUFF:
Four minutes, guys.
I see some designs that
I don't know what they are.
Oh, my gosh.
She's talking about ours.
Okay, let's do
a new doughnut.
Okay.
DUFF: Is this
the best you can do?
Why don't I put one of my
doughnuts here instead?
ALEX: Yeah, I agree.
I feel like that would...
You know...
Okay.
What should we do?
I don't know.
We're freaking out, and we,
like, try and move stuff around
to make it look more
like a doughnut...
I don't know.
Okay, wait.
We're just making it worse.
-Three minutes.
-Switch these.
We don't have time
for this.
DUFF:
Is your design awesome?
Ours isn't.
**
DUFF: Doughnut Designs.
Will this design go
in our art gallery?
Yeah.
We'll be the judge
of that.
I see some designs that I
don't know what they are.
They have to be
talking about ours.
-Oh, let's do a new one.
-Okay.
We don't have time
to pull out the pegs
and then put all
the doughnuts back on.
One minute left.
So we're just trying
to rearrange it
to make it shape better.
Maybe if we, like,
put them closer together...
-10...
-Okay.
-9...
-Switch these two.
Wait, no.
Just leave it there.
-7...
-6...5...
4...3...2...1.
Hands up.
**
Does it look better now?
I can't really tell.
Doughnut Designs.
Edible art, man.
This is kind of my thing.
This is gonna be
so cool.
Do you think we should bring
in Alex and Aditya,
the "A" team?
-Yes, absolutely.
All right.
"A" team, get in here.
A little easier coming
in here with a buddy?
Yeah.
Tell us about your design,
you guys.
So for our design,
we both love to do fusion,
so I thought fusion of patterns.
Is that your explanation
for why there's
Aditya's doughnuts,
then your doughnuts,
then there's like oops.
ADITYA: I still think
the colors and everything
go well together.
VALERIE:
I think they do, yeah.
It's just it's such a pattern
and then all of a sudden,
there's, like,
a lavender doughnut
where a peanut maple
bacon doughnut should be.
Well,
I think if this doughnut
and if this doughnut
got switched.
Now, that's a pattern.
Yeah.
We're gonna taste
the doughnuts one at a time,
and we'll start
with Aditya's.
I made a spiced doughnut.
I put cinnamon, nutmeg, ground
ginger and allspice in it,
and then I made
a cardamom lavender glaze.
And for the twist,
I topped it with cornflakes
and also there are cornflakes
inside the doughnut.
I think it's
absolutely beautiful,
and I think it's
a very yummy spiced doughnut.
Really taste the ginger,
but with all those strong,
warm spices,
I still
taste the lavender.
But I think
it's slightly dry.
Now, you put cornflakes
in the batter?
Yeah.
The moisture that
you were looking for
inside your doughnut
is now inside those cornflakes,
but also the texture that
you were going for goes away.
Okay.
I definitely got some
from the top here,
but it was subtle.
Let's move to Alex.
Okay.
This just looks likes
a taste adventure.
I made a maple bacon
and caramelized peanut doughnut.
I call it the Ultimate
Canadian Fever Dream.
-You got your maple...
-Bacon.
It looks
like a hockey puck.
Yeah, it kind of does.
Mm-hmm.
The doughnut is great.
It's got
nice maple flavor.
It's not too much.
Your bacon is crunchy.
You rendered it
really well,
but your bacon is crunchier
than your peanuts.
-Oh.
-Always toast your nuts.
You're gonna get
a better crunch,
and you don't want
your nuts to kind of mush.
Yeah.
But I like that maple,
the brown sugar.
It's really nice
and it's brown
and it's just, mm,
it tastes good.
But it's a little dry
when you get into
that doughnut.
Yes,
you can have my bacon.
It's okay.
Thanks, guys.
-Thanks, guys.
-Thank you.
**
It's a diamond.
It's sort of the representation
of, like, a game.
Yeah.
I wonder if they're
listening to us out there.
Oh,
they wouldn't do that.
Would they?
-I don't know.
I think it looks like...
space checkers.
-Oh, no.
-Yes.
-Is that a good thing?
-Yeah.
Sure. Yay.
Woo.
DUFF: It's super weird.
Aw.
-L and L.
-L and L. Yeah.
So tell me
about your design.
Basically, our design
is a diamond
with a layer of my doughnuts,
and Linsey's doughnuts, and my
doughnuts and Linsey's doughnuts
going all the way down.
But you forgot two.
Those two didn't really
fit into the diamond,
so we just put them
on the top.
So it's a diamond
in the rough?
-Yes.
-Mm-hmm.
I really like the fact
that there are these
two extra doughnuts
on top
because I feel like it's one
of each of you, you know,
and this is something that
you guys have collaborated on.
I'm not buying it
totally.
Art is subjective.
-All right.
Linsey,
what did you make today?
I made a strawberry doughnut
with a coconut glaze
and chocolate wafer
cookies for a crunch.
It's the mullet
of doughnuts.
Business in the front,
party in the back.
Uh-huh.
You guys don't even know
what a mullet is.
I know it's a hairdo.
It's like the thing that's
short, but then it's long.
Yes.
I had a mullet when I was
about your age.
Wait, seriously?
-Yeah.
-What?
I want to see
what that looks like.
**
Really cool.
All right.
Let's eat this thing.
**
That kind of taste
like a pancake?
Mm-hmm.
It's a little buttery,
which is awesome.
I love pancakes.
Nothing wrong with that.
I'm definitely getting
the texture of the cookies
and that's really good,
and I'm getting the coconut,
but I'm really not
getting any strawberry.
Okay.
I love this doughnut,
though.
It's perfectly baked.
It's nice and moist,
but if you're gonna sell me
a strawberry doughnut,
I agree,
I should taste strawberry.
Okay.
Luke, what did you
make for us?
Today, I made for you
a cookies and cream doughnut
with a fruit cereal crumble,
cream cheese glaze
and then a dark
chocolate drizzle
and a crushed sandwich cookie.
-Okay.
What was your
twist ingredient?
-Fruit cereal.
So you were already gonna put
the cookie in there.
**
Looking for
the fruit cereal.
I see them.
They're really small.
Okay.
*M
So, yeah, you know,
the fruit cereal
really needs to be there.
You know what I mean?
This was
a texture challenge.
I can't really feel it,
you know?
I would have liked more
of the fruit cereal
because that together
with the chocolate
really does
taste terrific,
and I love your dark
chocolate drizzle
with the glaze
that's on top,
but you didn't fill up
the doughnut pan
with enough batter,
so the doughnut is
a little on the dry side.
It's not, like, the most moist
doughnut I've ever had,
but it's not super dry.
Maybe because your doughnut
is a little bit bigger
than mine,
it's not as dry as mine.
-Okay.
-Thanks, guys.
-Thank you.
-Bye, thank you.
Honestly, I'm really
nervous right now.
**
Doughnut Designs.
Our team name is
Team Doughnut Swirl.
Abby and Julia,
come on in.
Hey, guys.
-Hi.
-Hello.
What was your plan
for the design?
ABBY: We wanted it to look
like a swirl.
VALERIE: It does.
It totally looks
like a swirl.
I think it's really
groovy, man.
It's all crazy.
You coordinated on colors,
pink with green sprinkles
and green
with pink sprinkles.
You guys really
thought this out.
We did.
I think
that's pretty cool.
But how does it taste?
Delicious.
Abby,
what did you have?
I have made a cinnamon doughnut
with a graham cracker
cinnamon crumble
on the bottom for texture
and cream cheese glaze.
I feel like I'm getting ripped
off on the glaze here.
You could have gone
all the way
because it looks so good.
I want more of it.
I'm so disappointed,
because I love that glaze
so much, because
it's really yummy.
I love
the cinnamon flavor.
I would love a big cup
of coffee with this.
It would be perfect.
-Mm.
Mm,
that's a good doughnut.
It's got
a good density to it.
I think the graham crackers
is great texture,
but I think that your doughnut
could have been
a little sweeter.
Sweeter.
I think just
a tiny bit sweeter,
this doughnut would
have ruled.
All right.
Let's move onto Julia's.
Mine is a key lime doughnut
with a pretzel crumble
on the bottom for the texture,
and it's a key lime glaze.
A lot of times on this show
people tell us something
is gonna be key lime
flavored and it never is.
Okay.
It totally tastes
like key lime.
Florida is key lime.
You know what a key lime
is supposed to taste like.
It's nice and strong.
It's really upfront,
and it's good.
It's not too much.
It's really bright
and tart but sweet.
But I'm not a fan
of these pretzels.
They almost taste stale.
Okay.
Like they were sitting
in the oven,
and they lost
their pretzelness.
Your doughnut
is really good.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, guys.
**
Bryn and Soleil,
come on in.
VALERIE: We're looking
at your design
and going, "What is it?"
It's a doughnut.
So Soleil's doughnut
is, like, the frosting,
and then my doughnut
is, like, the actual
baked part of it.
SOLEIL: It's, like,
from the side view.
It's a side...
-There's the hole.
-Yeah, that's the hole.
-Here's the icing.
-Then you look like that.
BRYN: And then
here's the baked part.
-We tried to be creative.
-Use your imagination.
Do you see it now?
DUFF: I'm looking at it
from the side.
Let's hold up a doughnut.
**
Oh, now I see it.
-Yay.
-No, I don't.
We thought it looked like
a doughnut, but okay.
I bet they taste
really yummy, though.
I hope so.
Soleil, tell us
about your doughnut.
I made a blueberry doughnut
with some macadamia nuts in it,
and I have a lemon glaze and
it's not that yellow, actually.
I air-brushed it, and then I put
a blueberry drizzle
with some crushed
macadamia nuts on top.
**
DUFF: I'm not sure if the
air-brushing was your friend.
It looks like ketchup,
mustard, blue cheese
and garlic cloves.
But the blueberry and
the lemon on the glaze,
it all goes together
so beautifully,
and I can even taste
the crunch of the macadamias.
But here's the thing, Soleil,
you have a whole blueberry
and you put it
in the oven, it explodes,
and all you're left with
is just that citric acid,
and it gets really,
really sour.
-Okay.
-You want to bust them up,
and you want to mix
it into the dough.
-Yeah. Okay.
-Okay?
Bryn, tell us
about your doughnut.
Well, today I made a maple bacon
doughnut with potato chips,
and I caramelized
the bacon on top.
I love how much you've
glazed this doughnut.
There's a ton
of glaze on it,
all dripping
around the edges.
I'm about to take
a second bite.
You first get that
bacon saltiness.
I'm definitely getting
potato chip texture,
and that is the moistest
doughnut I have tasted today.
Really moist.
It's just soft
and pillow-y inside.
Let me give you
a tip, though.
This bacon is
not cooked enough.
Oh, okay.
I would definitely cook it
a little bit more,
a little crispier.
That being said,
it's really, really good.
-Thank you.
-Really.
-Good job.
-Thanks, guys.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
-Bye.
SOLEIL: I know they didn't like
my presentation,
and they didn't like it
last week either,
so I'm feeling a bit nervous.
**
DUFF: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a feature story
in "Food Network Magazine..."
Yes.
...and $25,000.
**
Doughnut Designs.
I liked Luke and Linsey.
That looks really good.
They made
this diamond shape,
and they had an extra
doughnut each.
They really did create
a good representation of them
working together
as a team.
I really enjoyed it.
I enjoyed
Julia and Abby's.
I liked the way they worked
with each other,
that one
had pink frosting,
the other had green
and then opposite sprinkles.
You know, I think
we're on the same page.
I'll tell you,
there's one doughnut
that really stood out
for me today.
-Who's that?
-Aditya.
It was a beautiful doughnut
and that looked like
it should have been in
a high-end shop in Paris.
He had
a beautiful glaze.
Who at 11, 12 years old
is using lavender correctly?
But it was
on the dry side,
and there were a few doughnuts
that really stood out
because they were
perfectly moist.
Bryn.
Perfectly moist.
I loved the maple flavor,
and I got the crunch
of the potato chip.
It needed a little more
crunch from the bacon.
You loved that doughnut,
don't deny it.
I got to be honest.
There are a few items
that I "dough" not
ever want to see again...
I see
what you did there.
Like Soleil's.
That doughnut, today,
was definitely
the messiest looking,
but the lemon
was nice and bright.
But it technically
wasn't sound.
True.
The blueberries exploded
inside the batter,
and so what I got was
sour bombs inside the doughnut.
For me today,
Luke stumbled.
His doughnut
was inconsistent.
Yours was really dry,
mine wasn't.
Mm-hmm.
Good chocolate flavor,
I thought.
But I don't think he thought
it through all the way.
Luke did not use
his twist very well.
Fruit cereal
is so good.
He should have rolled
the entire doughnut
around in that stuff.
-Right?
-Totally.
Yeah.
Which one of those two
bakers stumbled more
and has to go home?
**
Bakers, we asked you to go
nuts with doughnuts,
and you did.
Some of you,
maybe a bit too nuts.
And because this was
a team design challenge
as well
as a baking challenge,
we want to give
a special nod
to the most appealing
doughnut design today,
which came from the team
of...
Abby and Julia.
-Yes.
-Congratulations.
Your spiral doughnut design
was a knockout,
but that doesn't mean that
either one of you are safe.
We told you in the beginning
that you would be judged
on your doughnuts
individually,
and only one doughnut
was a hole in one,
and that baker is...
Bryn.
Yay.
I'm sorry, I'm just
really excited.
The bacon, maple
and potato chip
was a great combination.
Thank you.
A few other doughnuts
were also sweet enough
to keep you
in the competition.
Aditya...
Really?
-Linsey.
-Good job.
Abby.
Julia...
-Yay.
and...Alex.
Oh, thank God.
Unfortunately, that
leaves Soleil and Luke.
Please step forward.
LUKE: I'm really
scared right now.
I haven't been on
the bottom yet.
It's really not a good feeling.
Soleil, the presentation
of your blueberry
macadamia doughnut
left a lot
to be desired,
and using
the whole blueberries
just didn't work for me.
SOLEIL: These have been
the greatest weeks of my life.
I really don't want
to go home yet.
Luke, your cookies
and cream doughnuts
were inconsistent,
and the smaller doughnuts
were a little dry.
We really wish you would
have embraced
your twist
ingredient, too.
You both have brought so much
to this competition,
but unfortunately, the baker
leaving us today is...
**
...Soleil.
I'm so sorry.
Soleil, you're amazing.
Really gonna miss you here.
Keep baking, Soleil.
Being on "Kids
Baking Championship"
has made me a better baker,
and I feel like
I've learned so much.
We'll miss you, Soleil.
I'm really happy
that I made it this far.
DUFF: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Artful design
with doughnuts.
DUFF: And you'll be doing it
in teams.
ABBY:
It's like a swirl.
VALERIE: Abby and Julia, your
spiral doughnut design
was a knock-out.
But one doughnut was
a hole in one, Bryn.
Yay.
Bacon, maple, and potato
chip was a great combination.
Soleil, the presentation
of your doughnut
left a lot
to be desired.
Luke, we really wish
you'd embraced
your twist ingredient.
The baker leaving
us today is Soleil.
**
BRYN: What?
I don't get it.
What is this?
LUKE:
Ah, this looks like school.
Hi.
-Welcome back, bakers.
-Hi.
Bakers, it is time
for an anatomy lesson.
-What?
-Anatomy?
Today's big bake is inspired
by a legendary creature.
Duff, chart please.
**
[ Cheers and applause ]
-Oh, it's a unicorn.
-Yes, yes!
Behold, the unicorn.
-Yes.
-I'm so happy.
Yes.
I love unicorns.
They're magical
and amazing and colorful.
I'm so happy.
ADITYA: I'm not really
interested in unicorns.
First of all, they're not real.
They aren't useful.
The common unicorn features
a plush tail,
pointy ears,
multi-colored mane,
and, of course,
the all-important horn.
And, bakers, today, you
will be making a unicorn...
How about a unicorn pie?
Unicorn bread.
Let's do unicorn bread.
-Yeah, unicorn bread.
-Yeah.
Unicorn pizza.
No. No.
[ Laughs ]
You will be making
a unicorn cake.
Unicorn cake.
Okay.
But not just
any unicorn cake.
When time starts, you will
each come up here and grab
an emotion that you
must communicate
on your unicorn's face.
Okay, bakers.
Two hours,
one unicorn cake
with one emotion
on its face.
And your baking time
starts...
now.
-Now.
**
I got surprised.
I got happy.
I got sad.
I got angry.
I'm happy to get angry.
I got worried.
I got shy.
[ Laughs ]
I got loving.
I get, yes, the loving emotion.
I'm gonna do the ultimate
tie-dye unicorn cake.
Okay, I'm gonna make the
circle cake look like a unicorn
by creating like a mane,
a very colorful mane,
adding a nice little horn
and nice beautiful ears.
So I am making
a lemon, tie-dye cake
with a vanilla frosting.
So the four colors I am
doing are light blue,
dark blue, pink, and violet.
Looks like a unicorn.
I'm using an ice cream scoop.
I'm not washing it in between
'cause I want all those colors
to come together and make
that beautiful tie-dye cake.
Going in the oven.
Valerie, do you
believe in unicorns?
I believe in unicorns.
Do you believe
in unicorns?
I believe in the power
of unicorns.
They fart rainbows.
[ Laughs ]
I don't think unicorns are real
'cause I think it's more of,
like, a myth or something.
I know they will definitely be
in my dreams here and there.
Alex, how can you not
believe in unicorns?
Unicorns are my favorite animal.
They are real if you were
wondering, and they're amazing.
They poop sprinkles.
I got surprise for my emotion.
I'm gonna make
an orange cream cake
with a Swiss meringue
buttercream frosting.
I'm dying two of my cakes
pink because I love pink
and one of them orange.
I'm deciding
to do an orange cake
because it also
represents Florida.
I love Florida 'cause
it's really tropical,
and it's always like
a good temperature.
Are you doing
a filling in the middle?
No, but I'm doing Swiss
meringue buttercream.
Oh, that's complicated.
I could do a normal
vanilla buttercream,
but to me, it's
a little bit too dense.
Like, it's just
butter and sugar.
So I wanted to do
something a little bit
more light and fluffy
'cause unicorns
are supposed to be light
and fluffy and happy.
To make my Swiss meringue
buttercream in a double boiler,
I whisk together egg
whites and sugar.
When the egg mixture comes
to 160 degrees Fahrenheit,
I put it in my standard mixer.
I slowly add in vanilla,
salt, and butter.
I wish unicorns were real,
but they're not, so...
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna be a baker
and a scientist when I grow up,
so I'm gonna make a horse
turn into a unicorn.
[ Laughs ]
For my shy unicorn cake, I'm
gonna make a raspberry cake
with white chocolate
ganache filling.
I put my vanilla cake
batter into my pans.
Then I take some
raspberry puree.
Put little dollops
in my cake batter.
Take a toothpick.
Swirl it all around so that
when they cut into the cake,
they can see all the lines
of the raspberry.
Going in the oven.
**
ABBY: I've never seen
a worried unicorn.
I'm very worried about this.
Julia and I won
for the top design last week,
and I really hope that I can
keep this momentum going.
I am making an almond
cake with a raspberry
buttercream and
raspberry filling.
I'm choosing to do four layers
so that my cake
is nice and tall.
Now I need to
make two different
buttercream flavors,
almond and raspberry.
I flavor half of the buttercream
raspberry with raspberry puree.
Can I please use this?
-Yep, take it.
And then I add in almond extract
to the rest of the buttercream.
For my almond buttercream,
I'm going to make different
colors of buttercream
so that my unicorn
has a beautiful mane.
I do believe in unicorns.
They're just too magical
for people to see.
Unicorns are, like,
my favorite thing ever.
And they live somewhere far
away where global warming
and deforestation
can't get to them.
My cakes in the past rounds
have not turned out good,
so I'm gonna get this cake
right for the unicorns,
all you unicorns out there.
Got you.
I'm making a confetti cake
with raspberry and buttercream.
**
More sprinkles.
Confetti, everyone's
happy with confetti.
It's colorful.
You usually use confetti at
like parties and happy moments.
I don't put in the sprinkles
in the actual cake batter
on the stand mixer
because I don't want
there to be streaks of color.
I want these sprinkles
to stay sprinkles,
so it's, like, confetti
and not, like, tie-dye.
**
LUKE: I'm gonna make the
first-ever angry unicorn.
Unicorns are a little bit
girly, but an angry unicorn,
now, that's a manly unicorn.
I'm thinking, like,
hot, spicy cake.
Yeah.
I'm making a spicy
chocolate cake
with a cinnamon buttercream.
One time I was watching
Bobby Flay, and he made
this brownie, and it was like
a spicy chocolate brownie.
And then there was
a cinnamon ice cream.
And that's where I got
my inspiration for it.
It's kind of risky to make a
chili cake for the first time
here on a baking championship
where it really counts.
One hour and 40
minutes left, bakers.
I'm going to make
a lavender blueberry cake.
This is my best sad face.
Rather than making
unicorn cakes,
which sound pretty boring,
I'd probably rather be,
like, practicing my violin
or something like that,
but I really want to win.
So, you know, I have
to do the best I can.
-Aditya?
-Yeah?
LUKE: What are you doing
on the stove?
-Steeping lavender.
-Nice.
I'm going to be making
a lavender cake,
and the lavender needs time
to steep into the milk.
It's pretty much
the same exact technique
that I did last week.
I'm using lavender this
week because number one,
I was in the top
last week using it,
and also, the lavender is
a kind of like soothing flavor.
So if you're sad, you
need something soothing.
I taste my lavender milk,
and there's basically
no lavender flavor,
so I add crushed-up
real lavender buds
into the batter.
**
Only for you.
Only for you, Val.
Shoot.
Oh, God.
Bakers, bakers, bakers,
may I have
your attention, please?
-Oh, my God.
-This is not the twist.
Oh, okay.
This is something
even better.
I don't know who for.
Okay.
Hope for the best and
prepare for the worst.
**
VALERIE:
Bakers, bakers, bakers,
may I have your attention,
please?
Duff said if,
and only if,
the winning cake
looks amazing,
he might...
-Wait.
...get a tattoo
inspired by it.
-Yes!
-Oh, my God.
-[ Laughs ]
-Yes.
DUFF:
90 minutes left, bakers.
-Yes.
-Unicorn cakes.
[ Whinnies ]
Duff, you're gonna have
a unicorn tattoo soon.
Listen, the cake's
gotta be awesome.
If it's not awesome,
he's not getting the tattoo.
Pressure is on.
Boo-ya.
Okay, I need to win now.
Duff's unicorn tattoo
will hopefully be mine.
For the ears, I take
fondant, put it into the --
what's the fondant thing called?
-The sheeter.
I've never used a sheeter
before, and it was pretty fun
'cause you just slide
it through.
[ Whoosh! ]
Then I take a cookie cutter
that's teardrop-shaped.
For the horn, I take fondant
and wrap it around a skewer
until it looks like a horn,
and then I paint my horn gold.
-That looks really good, Bryn.
-Thank you.
And then the ears gold.
I get my cakes out of the oven.
-Whoa, those look amazing.
-Thank you.
Once they're cooled,
I start stacking my cake.
It's cake, frosting,
cake, frosting, cake.
Wait, is that right?
Cake, cake, frosting,
cake, frosting, cake.
Okay, I did right, okay.
You got this.
It's time to start
building my cake,
so I put some raspberry simple
syrup, some buttercream.
Then my last layer, I actually
put that layer on upside down
because there are cleaner
edges on the bottom side,
which makes for, like,
a cleaner edge for the cake.
Crumb coat the cake
and let it chill.
[ British accent ]
The parts of a unicorn
are plush tail,
multi-colored mane,
pointy ears,
of course, the horn.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my gosh, Bryn,
that is amazing.
What did you make
your horn out of?
-Fondant.
-Fondant?
Bryn's using fondant,
so so will I.
Fondant.
I grab blue fondant.
I wrap that around
a plastic dowel
and try to make a unicorn horn.
My fondant horn
is falling apart
because I don't make
my dowel long enough,
so there's nothing to really
hold it up.
And it just falls over.
Julia,
are you airbrushing?
-Yeah.
-That's so cool.
JULIA: To make my unicorn horn
on my surprise cake,
I'm taking a sugar cone,
and I'm going to airbrush
my sugar cone with a yellow dye.
And it looks really
cool, but I want to add
some extra flair, so I'm dusting
it with gold luster dust.
Who has the waffle cones?
Oh, me.
-Can I borrow them?
-Yeah.
Thank you.
For the horn, I'm gonna put
cinnamon buttercream on it,
and then dip it in sprinkles.
-What's up, Luke?
-Hi.
So are you down with unicorns?
Do you like 'em?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, me too.
Especially
angry unicorns.
Angry unicorns?
[ Laughs ]
How are you gonna
make a unicorn angry?
I'm gonna, like, make his
eyes, like, really small
'cause in cartoons,
when someone gets angry,
their eyes
get really small.
Eyebrows going down like --
-Yeah.
-[ Grunts ]
-That's cool.
And then the inside
of his ears turn red.
-Like fire?
-Yeah.
I like that.
Good luck.
Thank you.
I'm ready to build my cake,
and I'm gonna put down
a layer of cake and then
frosting and strawberries.
I'm gonna put the strawberries
in between the layers
because I want a little
bite of freshness in there.
Then, I use the cinnamon
buttercream and just spread
it all around the sides,
and then I'm gonna throw
that in the blast
chiller and let it cool.
Next, I grab fondant, and I'm
gonna start putting it through
the sheeter, so then I can
just drape that over my cake.
VALERIE: Oh, look.
We're gonna get
a fondant cake.
DUFF: I don't think
that piece of fondant
is big enough
to cover Luke's cake.
This fondant's annoying.
It just keeps ripping.
It looked a little bit sloppy.
The parts that don't really
look good, I'm gonna make
that the mane, so I can
cover it in buttercream.
-Hi, Alex.
-Oh, you scared me.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Hi.
So what kind of
cake are you making?
So this is
a lemon tie-dye cake.
Oh, lots of color in
there. Very smart.
Yeah, 'cause when I
think of unicorns,
I think of colors and
rainbows and dreamland
and all that good stuff.
I'm doing very well with
time management today,
and this icing is
being good to me, so...
The icing is being
good to him.
I'm soaking it in
a lemon simple syrup
to make it more moist
and more lemon flavor.
All right, you have fun.
I can't wait to taste this cake.
Thank you.
Okay, bye.
I made it to week six.
I'm looking to win a challenge
for once and for all.
Bakers, you have one
hour and 15 minutes left.
Cakes should be stacked,
frosted, and cooling.
ADITYA: I check on my cakes, and
they're definitely not done.
They're, like, wobbling
in the center.
Everybody seems
to be decorating
at this point
except for Aditya.
-Are your cakes done?
-Nope.
I'm really behind.
Not even close.
**
LUKE: How are you doing,
Aditya?
Not good.
I really need to get a move on.
I'm really behind.
Oh, the cakes.
I still have to do the
decorations and everything
that I forget about my
cakes, and they look a bit
over-baked, but hopefully,
they're not too bad.
I taste my cake, and I
definitely get the lavender.
It may be a little
bit overpowering,
but hopefully, it's fine.
One hour left, bakers.
DUFF: Unicorn cakes each
with their own emotion.
BRYN: For my eyes and mouth
on my shy unicorn cake,
I take dark coating
chocolate and make the eyes
with the eyelashes
and then a little smiley
face for the mouth.
And then for the rosy
cheeks, I take a big brush,
dip into some bluster dust,
and put it onto the cheeks
so that it looks
like she's shy.
It's blushing.
My unicorn is blushing.
-That looks so good.
-Thank you.
With the mane,
you kind of just go wild
with all the different colors.
Like the unicorn has
a head full of hair.
[ Harp plays ]
To make little
rosettes on your cake,
you can take a star tip
and just make circles.
And it looks like roses.
JULIA: For my surprise cake,
my unicorn ears are now dry,
so I'm dusting on some
pink luster dust.
**
I know I want to use
fondant for the face
because it's a really
clean-cut thing,
and you can get the
exact shape you want.
I'm using two different
colors of fondant --
black for the eyes, eyebrows,
and the mouth.
And then I'm using
red for the tongue.
LUKE:
For my angry unicorn cake,
the mane I'm gonna pipe
rosettes
and then, like,
little, like, kisses.
And then I grab licorice
and black sprinkles,
so I can make the little
black dots as eyes
and then the big
licorice eyebrows.
Now you look angry, little bud.
Then for the mouth, I take
a little strip of candy
and kind of put it
a little bit like a frown,
so it looks like he's,
like, mad like that.
And it actually
looks pretty good
considering that no one's ever
made an angry unicorn cake.
**
ABBY: I look across
at Luke's cake,
and it looks like
he just used some candy.
That's a great idea.
Yours looks amazing.
-Thank you.
I'm going to give my
unicorn a worried face
by making its face look
like the worried emoji.
I have used that a lot on my
phone when I text my friends.
My unicorn looks very worried.
You know what?
Ice cream cone.
I grab one, and it looks
like a unicorn horn.
It has kind of like
a golden color to it.
Does anybody have
a heart-shaped cookie cutter?
I do.
I have two.
I'll take the small one.
I start working on my heart eyes
and then have it look loving.
I want this unicorn
cake to scream "loving"
with those eyes and
that nice blue smile
because I love the color blue.
And I think it's a lovely color.
What do you think is
the typical emotion
a unicorn will be found with
on his face?
Probably annoyed,
you know.
Just like, "Stop petting me
and asking me for wishes."
[ Laughs ]
LINSEY:
I'll just mix it like that.
The way I'm making
my unicorn cake happy
is by drawing upward eyes
'cause usually when people
are happy, they smile and
the creases of their eyes
like wrinkle, and their
eyes kind of look upwards.
And add a big old smile.
Then I stick in my unicorn
horn, the ears,
and boom.
Happiness.
Jazz hands.
**
Bakers, may we have
your attention, please?
-Oh.
-Yes.
Are you kidding me?
Your unicorn cakes
are looking so great,
we think they each
deserve their own name.
What?
You must all bake up
an edible name plate
for your unicorn's stall.
Kinda like these.
My unicorn's name
will be Charlie.
And mine
would be Gazpacho.
You gotta bake up
something from scratch,
and put your
unicorn's name on it.
Wait, okay.
LUKE: Everyone's
going everywhere.
I think we threw a
horseshoe into the machine.
I think we can go now.
-Okay.
-That was a fight.
ALEX: Oh, my God, my legs hurt
from all this running.
I'm not very excited
about this twist
'cause I have to bake
something completely
different than what I'd planned.
I'm gonna bake this
leftover cake batter in this
and then use buttercream
to pipe a name.
**
ABBY: I'm going to do
a sugar cookie name plate.
I'm creaming together
butter and sugar.
Then I add in my
eggs and vanilla,
and then I'm pouring in
my flour, baking powder,
salt, cream of tartar,
and I mix that together
until it's perfect
sugar cookie dough.
I hate this twist.
But I'm gonna be
making a sugar cookie.
I decide to name my unicorn
Milo because, like,
when I was young, I used to have
this dog that was named Milo.
He died when I was
about 3 years old.
I had so much love for Milo,
so I want to put just as much
love for this cake
that's named Milo.
No wonder I got loving.
It reflects on how
I feel about things.
I absolutely hate the twist.
**
To make my edible name plate,
I'm going to make
a shortbread cookie.
I am angry just like my unicorn.
And then I cut it
onto a name tag.
And then just probably
pipe on some buttercream
and pipe out a name.
Right now, I'm making
a shortbread cookie
for the name plate.
I'm gonna name my unicorn Fred.
And I have nothing
against the name Fred.
If your name is Fred,
I applaud you.
That's a great name.
But imagine if you had,
like, a pet unicorn,
and he's like magical, majestic,
colorful, rainbow creature.
And its name is Fred.
**
ADITYA: To create my edible
name plate, I just bake
a shortbread cookie in
a rectangular kind of shape.
BRYN: Luckily, my cake is
pretty much done.
It's looking pretty
good at the point,
so I can focus on my twist.
I start to make
rice cereal treats
for this edible name 'cause
they're quick and easy.
DUFF: 30 minutes, bakers.
For a unicorn cake
and a baked name plate.
Oh, my God.
I realize that rice cereal
treats are not baked.
They are cooked but not baked.
I start freaking out.
I have no idea what I can do
for this edible name plate.
Uh-oh, Bryn's upset.
**
I'm freaking out
'cause I have no idea
what I can do for this
edible name plate.
What's going on, honey?
I'm just worried.
I'm scared that I'm not
gonna have enough time.
You got this.
Okay, keep working.
-Okay.
It's okay, Bryn.
You'll figure something out.
BRYN:
I get myself together.
I start making sugar
cookie dough right away.
I throw some balls of
cookie dough onto the pan.
I'm just hoping that they
bake fast and they taste good.
22 minutes, guys.
ADITYA: For my horn,
I'm going to wrap
gum paste
around a waffle cone.
How's it going?
Tell me about your twist.
What are you gonna make?
For my twist, I'm making
a shortbread cookie.
And do you have a name picked
out for your sad unicorn?
If I'm really pressed for
time, I'll just name it Duff.
But I'm never sad, ever.
Good luck.
Okay, thanks.
I'm running out of time,
and I have a lot to do,
so I pipe rosettes and just
kind of blobs onto my cake.
I definitely have
to make the design
a bit less complicated than
what I was planning in my head.
To draw the eyes and
the eyelashes onto my cake
to make sure that my
unicorn looks sad,
I've got tears on there,
so I just use
a bit of leftover
blue buttercream.
**
LINSEY: I'll make a mane out
of the colored buttercream.
I try to put them all
into one piping bag.
Then I kind of mix together
the edges of each color
'cause I want the blue
and pink edges
to have a little bit of purple.
So it's like the full rainbow,
and I kind of like
wrap it around.
Wrap it.
11 minutes for
a unicorn cake
and a baked name plate.
JULIA: My cakes look
a little bit too brown,
so I'm hoping they're
not like a rock.
I frost it with some leftover
white Swiss meringue
buttercream.
I decide to write the name
Pinkie on my mini cake
because I have this
one stuffed animal
I've had since I was born,
and I named her Pinkie.
**
LUKE: I take out my cookie, and
it's a little bit under-baked,
but I can live with it.
I just think cookie dough
tastes really good.
I don't know what
to do for my name.
I'm just thinking of any
names that sound really tough,
something like El Macho.
Big Balf.
Balf, yeah, I like Balf.
Oh, that's a good name.
It sounds tough and
like an angry unicorn.
Like, "I am Balf."
**
ABBY:
I'm taking my sugar cookie.
I write out my unicorn's name,
Dash, onto its name plate,
and it looks perfect.
I'm naming my unicorn Dash
because I'm a competitive
cross-country runner.
And she's very
fast just like me.
**
BRYN: The cookies look nice
and golden brown.
I douse them with powdered sugar
just in case my sugar
cookies taste like biscuits.
And I write the name,
Belle, on my cookie.
I named my unicorn Belle
just because I think
it's a pretty name, and I also
kind of thought of my sister.
Her middle name is Belle,
and my dad's middle name
is Belle, so it kind of
just runs in the family.
And these cookies are going
to be called cloud cookies.
-Six minutes.
-Six minutes, guys.
ALEX:
Golden brown perfection.
I pull out my sugar
cookie from the oven.
I trim it off to
make almost like
a Welcome to Las Vegas shape.
I start to pipe my "M."
It looks like ghostly printing.
Oh, my gosh.
DUFF: 2 minutes,
30 seconds.
Name plates, emotions,
finished cakes.
ADITYA: The last thing I throw
together is my name plate.
With an edible marker, I write
Duff Jr. on my shortbread cookie
and hope it
doesn't bleed too much.
**
LINSEY: No.
Some of my cookies break
because they're,
like, super thin.
I pipe on, like,
lines of frosting
and then arrange my cookies
on top of the frosting
just so it stays put.
I just gotta go with it.
Oh, it's sticking
out of the top.
And the top of the skewer
is showing on my horn,
so I grab some fondant,
roll it in a little ball,
and, like, try to stick it on.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Dust it with gold.
DUFF AND VALERIE:
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Hands up.
LINSEY: This is definitely
the best cake I've made
in this competition, and I
know this is like really lame,
but I'm kind of proud
it didn't fall apart.
**
VALERIE: Wow.
DUFF: Pinkie.
All right, you ready
to call in Julia?
-Yep.
-Julia?
Hi.
I got the surprise
emotion.
[ Laughs ]
And I did an orange cake
with a Swiss meringue
buttercream frosting.
For the name plate, I baked
some of the pink
cake batter I had left.
I put the name Pinkie on it.
[ Laughs ]
It's the name of
a stuffed animal I have.
Let's try it.
I love your piping.
I think your piping
is really clean.
It's very deliberate.
The face, the expressions,
everything is really clean.
Pinkie is
definitely surprised.
Thank you, Julia.
Thanks, Julia.
Pretty color.
You can really
taste the orange.
Yay.
I think the texture of
your cake is really good.
I think your Swiss
meringue is great.
It's just a little
too buttery.
The name plate, I would
have liked to have seen
you put just a little
bit more effort.
-Yeah.
-It's like a little box.
Uh-oh.
-Yeah, I know.
It's, yeah.
Julia,
that got torched.
Well, what happened?
I left it in for too long.
That's not pleasant.
It's a little over-baked.
-Thanks, Julia.
-Thank you.
**
Man, you know, great cake
and then
the name plate, whoo.
That was a stumble.
**
Luke, I think you get
the award for the person
who had
the most fun today.
I had a lot of fun.
[ Laughter ]
So today I made a chocolate
chili cake
with a cinnamon buttercream
and a shortbread cookie
name plate.
What's the emotion?
The emotion is angry.
Look how angry he is.
That's a grumpy,
old unicorn.
What's
your unicorn's name?
Balf.
Where did that come from?
I think
it sounds pretty tough.
Just like Balf.
I've never heard
that name.
Change one letter
there, barf.
[ Laughs ]
Balf.
What happened to
the fondant on that cake?
It's really bumpy
and lumpy for fondant.
You gotta roll it
big enough.
Yeah.
I love that
you did something
with the ice cream cone.
Thank you.
I love that you decorated it
and gave it some texture.
Let's taste it.
**
Hmm.
How much chili
did you put in there?
I put in 2 teaspoons.
2 teaspoons,
2 teaspoons.
**
DUFF: Chili.
2 teaspoons,
2 teaspoons.
[ Inhales sharply ]
Hmm.
I tell ya, man.
2 teaspoons was
absolutely perfect.
This cake is delicious.
-Thank you.
-So good.
I mean, this is
really sophisticated.
VALERIE:
This cake is so moist,
and I love
the addition of the cinnamon.
Let's try that cookie.
Really soft.
I mean, I like cookie
dough and all, but...
I think it's maybe
a little under-baked.
Yeah, you can see
it's definitely
not cooked through.
Sorry.
You know, you can
taste the flour.
It wasn't in
the oven long enough.
So amaze-balls
chili chocolate cake,
and Balf not so much.
-Luke, thank you so much.
-Thank you.
Delicious chocolate cake
and then just raw.
-Right.
-Ahh.
**
It sure is beautiful.
Love the face.
Hey, Linsey?
Hey, Linsey,
tell us what you made.
My emotion for the
unicorn cake was happy.
I made a confetti cake
with a raspberry
simple syrup and a buttercream.
What happened to the top?
The skewer was kind of
pointing out of the horn,
so I had to just
last minute cover it
with a bit of fondant.
That's the one glaring
mistake that I can see
because I absolutely
love the face.
You really thought about
how that mane was gonna
be wrapped around the cake.
-It was flowing.
Your piping is really good.
-Thank you.
-Really good.
And because it's so short,
it's kind of cute.
I think short things are cute.
I'm short.
You're short.
-I'm short.
-I'm so short.
-We're all cute.
[ Laughs ]
How did you make
your name plate?
I made a shortbread cookie,
and I cut out the letters.
And why Fred?
It's like
this magical creature,
and it has like a normal name.
And I think that's
kind of funny.
[ Laughter ]
I would have liked
to have seen you
be a little bit more festive
with the name plate.
What happened
to the "F"?
It kind of, like,
broke, the top of it.
Let's taste it.
**
I love the buttercream.
It's a delicious,
moist confetti cake,
and it's so festive
and fun to look at.
See, I think your cake
was a tad bit dry.
It's good cake,
and it's beautiful.
Let's taste
the name plate.
**
Mmm.
I really like that.
It is so buttery.
It's so delicious.
Thank you, Linsey.
-Thanks, Linsey.
-Thank you.
**
Milo.
[ Breathes deeply ]
Hey, Alex.
Hello.
My cake is a lemon tie-dye
cake with buttercream frosting.
This is inspired by a dog
that I had when I was young
who was named Milo, and the
emotion that I got was loving.
So I expressed that in his
face by adding heart eyes
and a nice blue smile because
my favorite color is blue.
I think
you nailed loving.
Thank you.
You know, I think the eyes
are really great.
I do wish they
had pupils though.
Oh, yeah.
I love the way you've
just covered the whole
top of the cake with all
different, lovely colors.
I am a little concerned
with how thin
your frosting looks
'cause your cake
is showing through.
-Oh, okay.
-Your horn?
Such a colorful cake
with a brown horn.
I would have colored it.
Let's taste it.
**
Nice and lemony.
Yes.
But, Alex, it is
a little over-baked.
Okay.
It's a little
on the dry side.
Your cake is dry.
The lemon flavor is great.
Goes great with
your buttercream.
Tell us about
your name plate.
So my name plate
is a sugar cookie.
What happened near the
end of Milo's name there?
Uh...
Let's taste
the name plate.
I wish the cookie was
a little bit thinner.
It's good flavor.
-Oh, thank you.
But there's some room
for improvement.
-Okay, thanks, Alex.
-Thanks, Alex.
Thank you.
I think Alex made
a lot of mistakes,
but a lot of easy ones
that he could have fixed.
Mm-hmm.
**
Hey, Abby.
Hello.
I got "worried"
for my unicorn.
I think that you
absolutely captured it.
How appropriate
because you seemed worried
the whole day.
Yeah.
What kind of flavor
cake did you make?
I made an almond cake
with a raspberry buttercream
and an almond buttercream
on the outside.
And my name plate is made
out of a sugar cookie,
and my unicorn's name is Dash.
Dash.
'Cause it's really
fast just like me.
You did a beautiful job.
I like that you used
licorice for her face.
Dash's horn
is a little droopy.
Yeah.
I think in his worry,
he's kind of...
Okay.
You want to cut into it,
so we can try it?
Sure.
My cake is four layers.
Wow, four layers.
Oh, boy.
Wow,
look at that cake!
Yeah,
cake looks great.
That has got some
great almond flavor.
And that jam really
works well together
along
with the buttercream.
I wish you had used a jam
that was seedless.
Oh, yeah.
I don't mind the seeds.
That's just me.
I don't like seeds.
I'll fight her.
[ Laughs ]
The cake is sweet.
The buttercream is sweet.
And I think with the jam,
it kind of gives you
a little bit
of an acidity.
Let's taste
that name plate.
I wish
it wasn't so thick.
Yeah.
I wish it was decorated
a little more.
Dash is so beautiful
and so vibrant.
It'd be nice to see
her name plate
just a little bit more fancy.
-Okay.
-Thanks, Abby.
-Thank you.
**
Aditya?
-Hey, buddy.
-Hi.
Hi.
I made a lavender cake frosted
with vanilla bean buttercream
and filled
with blueberry coulis.
My emotion was sad.
Kind of appropriate.
I think
he looks pretty sad.
You know how to ice
a cake, don't ya?
Really?
It's not perfect, put it
looks really straight.
**
Man, lavender two
weeks in a row, chef.
**
Aditya, I think the blueberry
in here is delicious.
Your vanilla buttercream,
it's really natural tasting
and really good.
It's really
perfectly done,
but you can really
taste the lavender.
The lavender
tastes like soap.
Like this time
you used too much.
Okay.
Okay, let's taste
your name plate.
It's a shortbread cookie.
Shortbread cookie.
Well, on your name plate,
you can't really
write on a cookie.
The cookie is gonna suck up
any liquid it touches.
So you need to make
some kind of frosting,
something that
isn't gonna [sucks]
Why is he Duff Jr.?
I didn't really
know what to put.
[ Laughs ]
-Mmm.
-That's so good.
Buttery.
Killed it on the cookie,
on the flavor.
-Thanks.
-Thanks, Aditya.
-Thank you.
ADITYA:
I'm not proud of what I did,
but I guess I'm just
trying to stay positive.
**
DUFF: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive a sweet prize
package that includes
a feature story in
"Food Network Magazine."
Yes.
And $25,000.
[ Cheers and applause ]
**
-Wow.
-Cheeks.
VALERIE:
I love the cheeks.
Unicorn cakes,
that turned out
to be
a really fun challenge.
-Yep.
-Right.
I can't wait
to bring in Bryn.
Bryn!
**
Tell us
about the cake you made.
The cake I made is a white
chocolate raspberry cake,
and it's a shy unicorn.
[ Laughs ]
So shy is your emotion?
Yes.
It is so cute.
It totally reads
shy to me.
She's blushing,
she's so shy.
I love the candy
and the fruit
in that buttercream mane.
-Thank you.
-That's really cool.
Tell us
about your name plate.
My name plate
is a sugar cookie,
and it's supposed
to look like clouds.
Clouds.
I think
it's really creative.
-And what's the name?
-Belle.
Let's taste it.
**
That's really lovely.
I love the raspberry.
It adds that tartness.
And I love
that toastiness.
It's actually kind
of interesting.
A really kind of --
-It's a great flavor.
It's like a toasted
grain almost.
-Yeah.
-You know what I mean?
Let's have a cookie.
They're clouds.
Mmm,
not super successful.
It's this weird
crunchiness on the outside
and then moist
on the inside.
I'm not expecting a sugar
cookie to taste like this.
Crunchy on the outside
and pillowy on the inside
sounds like a recipe
for deliciousness to me.
I think
that's a good cookie.
I really like it.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Bryn.
I love this cake.
It's not
what you're expecting.
But it's delicious.
And the decorating, please.
-It's really sweet.
-It's so beautiful.
**
Bakers, we adored your
expressive unicorn cakes.
And there were two cakes
that really
came to life for us.
Bryn, your raspberry
white chocolate cake
had a toasty unique flavor
that we really love.
Thank you.
Linsey.
Nice job.
The interior of your
confetti cake was good,
and the exterior
was even better.
Thank you.
We told you that
the winning cake
might inspire Duff
to get a tattoo.
Please.
Please, please.
We're not making
any promises,
but Duff just
might get a tattoo.
And that baker is...
...Linsey.
Good job.
I won the unicorn challenge,
of all challenges,
the unicorn one.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
I told you.
If you don't
believe in unicorns,
they're not gonna
be nice to you.
Yeah,
your cake was cute.
I don't know if
it was that cute.
We'll see.
You can't announce
that on national television
and not do it.
Well done, Linsey.
Thank you.
Now, a few other cakes
were also magical.
Luke.
-Yes.
Julia.
-Yay.
-Good job.
And...Abby.
-Good job, Abby.
-Good job.
You guys are safe.
Thank you.
Unfortunately, that
leaves Aditya and Alex.
Please step forward, guys.
**
Aditya, the lavender
in your unicorn cake
was too strong.
And your name plate
was disappointing.
Alex, your lemon tie-dye
cake was over-baked.
And the piping on your
name plate was messy.
You both should be really
proud for making it this far.
Yeah.
But the baker
leaving us today is...
**
...Aditya.
Sorry, man.
You made it really far.
This has been a roller
coaster for you, hadn't it?
Mm-hmm.
It was super fun
having you, man.
You were really great.
-Thank you.
-We're gonna miss you.
-Keep baking.
ADITYA: Even though I got
eliminated, I know I'm still
a pretty good baker.
I'm going to keep baking.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
When I get home, I'm gonna
make another unicorn cake
and then tag Duff
on it on Instagram.
Okay, thank you.
Keep baking.
DUFF: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
You will be making
a unicorn...cake.
More sprinkles, the better.
Because I absolutely
love the face.
The winning cake might inspire
Duff to get a tattoo,
and that baker is Linsey.
Good job, Linsey.
Alex, it is
a little overbaked.
Aditya, the lavender
tastes like soap.
The baker leaving us
today is Aditya.
**
-Uh...
-School?
-Oh, my god.
-School.
-[ Gasps ]
-Whoa.
School? What?
Aw, man.
I'm here to bake.
I do not want to have
to go to school today.
Oh, boy.
* Dun, dun, dun *
-Hi, guys.
-Hi.
Welcome back, bakers!
Did you get your tattoo?
Ugh. Man, kids don't forget,
do they?
-No.
Okay. Listen.
I know you guys wanted Duff
to get a tattoo.
Aw.
But when it came down to it,
I really honestly didn't think
that he could live without it!
-Yeah!
-What does it say?
Show them! Show them!
Show them the tattoo!
Come here, Linsey.
-I got the tattoo.
-Yay.
-Oh, my gosh.
-Okay?
See he has Fred's eyelashes?
Oh, yeah.
-That is so cute!
-That is so cute. Isn't he?
He's so fat and chunky.
It's so insane.
I can't believe it.
Like, every time he looks
at that unicorn tattoo
he'll remember
that Linsey made a really
pretty unicorn cake and so cool.
Bakers, we are down to half
the number of bakers
that we started with.
I cannot believe it.
Oh, my gosh.
-Yeah.
-Whoo!
The boys are dropping
like flies,
and the girls are killing
the baking game.
You better believe it,
but what shouldn't you believe?
Imposters.
-Oh, my gosh.
-Oh!
-[ Laughing ]
-Yay, kind of.
I'm excited that we're doing
dessert imposters,
but I'm kind of iffy
because you don't know
what you're gonna get.
You cannot become
Kids Baking Champion
without mastering
the imposter.
And today, we are working
with classic lunch-box items.
Oh, my god.
Duff, show us how you made
that tasty panini.
Okay.
For the bread,
I made biscotti dough.
You know, it's hard
like a cookie?
-It's like a cookie. Yeah.
-That's the bread.
Basil, took white chocolate,
painted it onto
a real basil leaf,
let it get hard --
-Whoa.
...peeled the leaf off
and then airbrushed it green.
So for the mozzarella cheese --
-Marshmallow.
-...it's marshmallows.
Okay. A little more basil.
You know,
you want some dynamic.
Tomatoes are made with gelatin
and then little sesame seeds.
-Smart.
-Tomatoes.
So realistic.
-All right?
-Looks real, doesn't it?
-Yeah.
Mmm.
I really wanna eat that.
Yummy.
Okay, bakers.
You have two hours.
When time starts, you're gonna
run up and grab a lunch box.
-I call the cow.
And you're gonna look inside
to see which classic lunch item
you must imposter-ize.
-Imposter-ize.
But there's more
to this challenge.
-Of course.
-[ Sighs ]
You have to create
a side dish --
Are you serious?
...to go with
your classic lunch item.
Don't forget, even though
the desserts are imposters,
one of you is actually
going home today,
so bake to impress.
Your baking time starts...
...now!
-Now!
-Oh, yeah!
-Yes!
Oh, wait!
Where is the last one?
This is heavy!
This is scaring me!
-This is actually scaring me.
-I got pink!
I got bologna sandwich.
I got chicken nuggets.
PB and J sandwich.
I got turkey wraps.
I got tuna salad.
Ham and cheese sandwich.
Ham and cheese?
I got ham and cheese.
That's, like,
one of my favorite sandwiches.
I'm so excited.
Loaf pan.
So I'm making an imposter
ham and cheese sandwich,
and I'm thinking, for my bread,
I'm going to do lemon
pound cake, as my cheese,
orange white chocolate.
I'm not sure what I'm gonna
do for, like, the ham yet,
but I think my side dish
is gonna be a salad,
so let's make
the lemon pound cake.
"Bread."
When my butter and sugar
is creamed together,
I alternate between
my dry ingredients
and my wet ingredients
until all of my dry
and wet ingredients
are all finished.
I'm putting my lemon pound cake
batter into a loaf pan
because I want it
to look like bread,
so I equally separate it
between two loaf pans,
and I get into the oven
as fast as possible
'cause these
things need to bake.
I do not feel that good
about getting turkey wrap
'cause I've never had one.
My mom has had one,
but she's not here so hope
I can pull this off.
I have turkey wrap,
and for the turkey,
I'm doing a blondie
sliced up and airbrushed.
For the tortilla,
I'm doing a crêpe,
so for the crêpe batter,
I'm whisking together
the eggs and the flour.
I slowly add in some water
and milk,
and then I add in salt
and some unsalted,
melted butter.
I start to add in some
green food coloring
so it looks like one
of those spinach tortillas.
ALEX: Time?
DUFF: 15 minutes gone, hour
and 45 minutes left, bakers.
ALEX: Oh, my gosh.
-Yay, imposters!
-Yay!
-It's imposters day!
-It's so much fun! I love it!
Whoo-hoo!
Nothing.
Bryn's looking at me
like I'm crazy.
[ Laughs ]
-Well, Bryn would be right.
-[ Laughs ]
At school lunch, I eat, like,
a mix of things.
Sometimes, it's, like,
really unhealthy,
and sometimes, it's pretty,
like, average, you know.
I got chicken nuggets.
I'm so excited.
I think they're one
of the easiest things
that you could get in your lunch
box to turn into an imposter.
-Whoa.
-You good?
-Oops.
-[ Laughs ]
BRYN: I'm making cake balls
because it's easy to mold
into chicken nugget shapes
with sugar cookie french fries.
My cake is in the oven.
Sugar, sugar.
For my sugar cookie
french fries,
I mix together powdered
sugar, eggs, and butter,
and then I add in
my baking powder and my flour
and mix it all together
until it stops sticking
from the sides of the bowl.
Cookie dough.
Then I put it
in the blast chiller.
Whoa. It's, like,
snowing in here.
If you don't chill it,
it'll stick to the board,
and it'll just be
a lot harder to work with.
But then I realize I totally
forgot the vanilla extract,
so I run back, take it out
and just mix in
my vanilla extract by hand.
That should work. See?
All you got to do
is problem solve.
Without the vanilla, it probably
tastes like a biscuit,
and you don't want a biscuit.
-Bryn?
-Yeah?
What do you think looks
more like peanut butter,
a cookie butter buttercream
or a pastry cream?
Probably the pastry cream
because it's thicker.
Pastry cream? Okay.
That's what I thought.
I'm gonna do that.
I got a peanut butter
and jelly sandwich,
and for my
lunch box imposter "bread,"
I'm making a vanilla cake,
and for my peanut butter,
I want to use
a vanilla bean pastry cream,
and I also want to have
a homemade jam as the jelly.
Yum.
To make my pastry cream,
I'm combining my milk
and cornstarch,
adding my egg yolks,
and then I'm heating up
milk and sugar on the stove
until it comes to a boil.
Ah!
Oopsies.
It's all good.
I'm slowly adding in
my milk and sugar mixture
to my egg mixture
to temper the eggs.
If you don't temper your eggs,
then you'll have
scrambled egg pastry cream,
and that is disgusting,
so you better make sure
that you temper your eggs.
And then I add in my butter
and vanilla bean
and pour it through a strainer
to get rid of any
leftover egg chunks.
I'm adding brown food coloring
to my pastry cream,
and it looks like
peanut butter.
VALERIE:
90 minutes left, bakers!
Come on.
Your lunch should look fake
but taste really good.
Yes. [ Chuckles ]
I wish my lunch could be
dessert imposters every day
'cause that means,
like, cake or cookies
or brownies or anything
every single day for lunch.
That's all I want in the world.
[ Laughs ]
Linsey, what are you
doing for the bread?
I'm just making a lemon cake.
A lemon cake?
Yeah, because I'm using
marzipan for the bologna,
and almond goes
with lemon, so...
Nice.
Going in the oven!
So to make my bologna,
I get marzipan,
which is an almond paste
that's been sweetened,
put some food coloring
in and dye it pink.
Look at Linsey's bologna.
She's coloring marzipan.
It looks exactly like bologna.
I love marzipan.
And that's no bologna.
[ Laughs ]
When I was little, I used
to eat bologna plain,
and you would, like,
bite little holes in it,
and, like, my face
was small enough
because the piece of
bologna was this big,
and you'd, like, look through it
and pretend that was your face.
I remember doing that so much.
My dad would do it, and then
the bologna slice was too small.
I love American cheese
on my sandwiches,
so I take some yellow
coating chocolate,
melt it and spread it out
on some parchment paper.
-What's that?
-I'm making cheese.
What the heck am I
gonna do with this?
Tuna salad, seriously?
Mayonnaise and tuna is basically
what a tuna salad is,
and those are two gross
things combined, just ugh.
This better taste good.
I'm making an imposter
tuna salad sandwich
with white cake as the bread.
For my tuna salad, I'm making
a coconut pastry cream
with whipped cream
and then marshmallows
for little chunks of tuna.
Hour and 15 minutes
left, bakers,
and one of you's
getting expelled.
-Aw.
-[ Laughs ]
Not me.
Can't we just send them
to detention for a couple days?
-Nope.
-No?
"Kids Baking Championship"
is kind of like school
because we get challenges,
which are like the tests,
and then Duff and Valerie
are like the teacher,
and, like, someone
gets sent home,
which is like someone
getting an F.
I don't want to get an F
on this tuna salad test.
Oh, shoot.
I'm done with my pastry cream,
and after I strain it and pour
it into the whipped cream,
I realize it is really
gummy and thick.
Okay.
This is a little strange.
Ew.
If I gave the judges
a gummy pastry cream,
they would say that it
looks like tuna salad, ugh,
but then it would
just taste nasty,
so I just have to throw
it away and start over.
-One hour left, bakers!
-Dish, wait.
Lunch box imposters,
the cafeteria will be
shutting down in 1 hour!
**
DUFF:
One hour left, bakers!
Dish, wait.
Lunch box imposters,
the cafeteria will be
shutting down in 1 hour!
Uh-oh.
I'm a little concerned.
Luke is scrapping
his pastry cream.
Wonder why.
Well, usually, that means
he scrambled it.
Ugh. Okay.
So my pastry cream
turned out gummy,
so I'm going to plan B
where I'm gonna make
a coconut whipped cream
as the filling for the inside.
This whipped cream
is super easy.
It's just heavy cream,
coconut milk, and sugar.
My whipped cream
comes together,
so I'm adding
in coating chocolate.
I'm gonna do orange and green
for carrots and celery
and then marshmallows
for texture
of, like, little chunks
of tuna in tuna salad.
This better work out.
Okay. What do I still
have to make?
I made the cheese, bologna.
Oh, pie.
For my side dish, I'm going to
use pie crust to create chips.
Here we go.
Usually, for school, for lunch,
I usually have, like,
a ham and cheese sandwich,
so I have had quite a few
ham and cheese sandwiches.
That looks like cheddar
cheese color.
Once my chocolate has melted
and is dyed orange,
I spread it on a sheet pan.
Duh, duh, duh, duh, cheese.
I love cheese.
I love, love, love,
love, love cheese.
Ham, what am I gonna
do for the ham?
Maybe a crêpe, I could do
a crêpe as the ham
and then just dye it.
Bakers, can we have
your attention, please?
-Oh, my god.
-Oh, boy.
Mm.
We realize we forgot to give you
a drink in your lunch boxes.
You need to double check next
time when you pack our lunches.
So we have juice boxes.
Great.
I don't need juice
in my lunch box.
Can't I just have water?
Your job is to incorporate
the juice into your dessert
in a way that we can taste
and that makes sense.
I love juice boxes, but I don't
like baking with them.
That's just unusual.
Come on up. First come --
-Come on up and get your juice.
-...first slurp.
**
Berry, berry, berry.
-This one.
-Mixed berry.
-Perfect.
-I guess passion fruit.
[ Laughs ]
Great.
Those guys were thirsty.
What the heck does
a passion fruit taste like?
Back to the cafeteria,
lunch lady.
Yes.
Okay.
I get orange juice
for the twist,
and I'm not very
excited about this
because I already
have everything made.
I already baked everything.
My blondies are baked, so my
orange juice can't go in that,
and I already have
my crêpe batter done.
Bye.
I decide the crêpes
are the easiest thing
to scrap right now,
so I just dump everything out,
and now I'm making
an orange-crêpe batter.
In my crêpe recipe, I replace
the water with the orange juice.
I'm adding green food coloring
because I want it
to look like a spinach tortilla.
VALERIE: 45 minutes left, guys!
45 little old minutes!
What?
Okay.
I'll get that in two seconds.
I've never had a passion
fruit before,
so I have no idea
what it tastes like.
First time you've ever
had passion fruit?
-Mm-hmm.
-You got it.
You got it.
Show me them muscles.
No. Ugh!
-Come on. You got it.
-Can you open it for me?
Yes. [ Laughs ]
Thank you.
Okay.
And you're tasting?
And what do we got?
It kind of tastes
like orange juice
but, like, strawberries
in it kind of.
Okay.
I like how you tasted it.
It was like tasting
a fine wine.
[ Laughs ]
You aerated a little.
-It's good.
-Yeah.
Got to get all those flavors,
make sure you taste
all those flavors.
You got -- Yeah, totally.
I definitely think
the passion fruit juice
will make a really good fruity
buttercream for my cake balls.
Butter.
So I cream together butter
and powdered sugar.
Then I add in some of
my passion fruit juice.
Ooh, it smells good.
For my chicken nuggets, I pulse
the cake in a food processor
until it forms small crumbs,
and then I put in some
of my buttercream
and form it into
chicken nugget shapes
and put it into
my cereal mixture,
and so it looks like
it's just been fried.
Ooh!
What are you making?
Your chicken nuggets?
Yeah.
-Are you gonna deep fry them?
-No.
-No?
-That's scary.
Ta-da.
I need one of these.
I get mixed berry juice.
I'm already making
a strawberry jam,
so now I can just make
a mixed berry jam instead.
I like to see that Abby
is making her own jam.
PB and J, I mean,
she could've grabbed the jam
off the shelf, but...
That's not a lot of work.
That's no "Kids
Baking Championship" move.
Mnh-mnh.
To make my mixed berry jam,
I'm adding in my strawberries,
raspberries, blueberries,
and blackberries
and my mixed berry juice drink,
powdered sugar for sweetness,
and cornstarch.
The cornstarch will help
to thicken my jam.
Perfect!
Linsey got grape juice
as her twist, and I just --
I don't know how that's going to
work with her bologna sandwich.
Never had a bologna
and jelly sandwich?
No.
-Think you're about to.
-[ Laughs ]
Darn it.
What do I do with grape juice?
I'm just so annoyed
because I get there last,
and the only juice left
is the grape juice
'cause no one else
wanted grape juice.
This will not be fun to figure
out how to use this grape juice.
Like, I'll figure you out later
'cause whatever I'm doing
doesn't involve juice.
Ugh.
LUKE:
All right. Let's go.
So now I have to use my juice
in my imposter
so they can taste it.
I still haven't made
my side dish,
so I decide, why don't
I just make applesauce?
I'm thinking,
for the applesauce,
I'm just gonna
make it more sweet
and add in a lot of sugar.
This is gonna be weird.
And then I add apple juice.
Basically, it's
an applesauce imposter
that's like a sweet
dessert applesauce.
[ Gasps ] I made applesauce.
36 minutes, bakers!
That's not very good.
This twist is so bad.
Oh, my goodness.
At school, usually,
I would drink a juice box
with my sandwich,
but I wouldn't incorporate
it in the sandwich.
That would just be disgusting.
Wait a second.
Doing lemon pound cake,
straw...
Since I haven't made
my crêpe batter yet,
I'm going to use
this juice in my imposter
by incorporating
it into my crêpe,
replacing the water
with this juice.
Strawberry lemonade crêpe,
that's not the worst thing ever.
Uh-oh.
Uh-oh. It's stuck.
Oh, darn it.
So I try to flip my crêpe,
but it's stuck
to the bottom of the pan.
Did not work. Oh, my god.
So I make another crêpe.
It just breaks.
Uh-oh.
Trouble in crêpe land.
Alex keeps throwing
his crêpes away.
-No, no, no, no, no, no.
-Time?
DUFF: 30 minutes left!
Ugh, this is driving me crazy.
I don't have time for this.
I have so much other stuff
to do still.
This is just not working for me.
**
-Time?
-30 minutes left!
Lunch box imposters!
Ugh, this is driving me crazy.
Hey, Val, lunch box imposters,
I wonder what's faux lunch.
What?
I don't get it.
-Took me a minute.
-[ Laughs ]
So I try to flip my crêpe.
Don't break off. Yes.
Yes. There we go.
And finally, it comes together,
and it doesn't break.
Oh, thank god.
Okay. There we go.
So for my "ham," I am taking
the strawberry lemonade crêpe,
and then I'm airbrushing it
kind of like an orange.
What's Alex airbrushing?
I don't know. It's orange.
What's supposed to be orange
in a ham and cheese sandwich?
The cheese?
Okay. Perfect.
Apples.
For my side dish,
I'm doing cinnamon apple chips
to look like potato chips.
I like apple chips because
they sort of remind me
of potato chips
with the texture,
but they taste like fruit.
I've never made
apple chips before,
so I'm just sort of
guessing here.
I really need to figure out
how to use this twist
because no one
likes grape juice.
I think I'm gonna make,
like, a sauce with it
for my chips, the side dish.
I'm really hoping that this
mixed berry plus grape sauce
has a grape flavor
because, I mean,
I put the whole bag
of grape juice
inside of the berry mixture,
but I'm worried that the other
berries will distract
from the grape flavor.
Oh, jeez.
Well, I made a mess.
Oh, my god. They're still raw.
So I go to check on
my lemon pound cake.
Ugh.
It's raw.
Like, it's soup.
-Hi.
-Hi. What are you making?
My cakes are not baking,
so I need to put this foil
to have them bake
a little faster in the middle.
Foil is going to help. Okay.
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Can I watch you do that?
Because I have no idea
what you're doing.
Yeah. Okay.
I've never done this before.
It's something that I'm just
improvising on the spot,
so I'm just hoping that,
you know, it works out.
Like, I got a little.
Oh, you're sticking it in there
so the metal gets hot --
Yeah.
...and creates
more heat inside like
when you put a nail
in a baked potato, right?
-Same thing.
-Yeah.
-Okay. That's a cool trick.
It's all about science.
I'm making my strawberry yogurt.
For my side item, I'm making
a strawberry whipped cream,
which will be
my strawberry "yogurt."
You gonna put anything
on top of your yogurt --
-Mm.
-...or just plain yogurt?
-Just yogurt.
-Just yogurt, okay.
-Yeah.
-All right.
Wisconsin is the dairy state.
-Yep.
I might be playing it
a little bit safe
by making a whipped cream,
but hopefully,
how it complements
my peanut butter
and jelly sandwich
will win the judges over.
A yogurt container, oh,
that's kind of cute.
You need to have a lot
of yogurt so,
that way,
you have strong bones.
That's what my mom says,
but I don't like yogurt.
Sorry, Mom.
20 minutes, bakers!
That's gross.
I'm scrapping this applesauce
because it's just mush,
and it looks gross.
I guess that's what
applesauce looks like,
but this just isn't turning out.
I still need to use the apple
juice, and I still need a side,
so I run to the pantry,
and I see oats,
and I get the idea
to make apple juice granola.
First thing I'm gonna do
is I'm going to throw my oats
in a pot and toast
them with butter.
Then I'm gonna chop up
pecans and add that.
I add in honey and I pour it
into a separate bowl
and pour in the apple juice
and let it kind of soak in
for a little bit.
This is really weird.
In a lunch box,
you have a granola bar,
but I don't really have time
to make a whole granola bar,
so I guess it's
a deconstructed granola bar.
That's an interesting
granola Luke is making.
What's he making it for?
This is really weird,
but it's actually good.
When I eat this granola,
it tastes like nuts
with apple juice,
and it's actually kind of good.
I'm just a little worried
they might say,
"This isn't a dessert imposter."
How's everyone doing?
So currently, I'm working
on my side dish.
It is going to be
a Caesar salad.
So I combine shredded coconut
and food coloring,
and then when it's that
perfect shade of green,
I add in some "tomatoes,"
which are actually strawberries.
The last thing I want to add
is some "Parmesan,"
which I'm going to actually have
white chocolate grated on top
because what's a salad
without Parmesan.
VALERIE: 10 minutes left!
All right, bakers,
so you're gonna be
serving on plates like this.
Your imposter goes here,
and then your side goes here,
and then you can fill this up
with whatever you want,
your chips, carrots.
Dried fruit, pretzels.
Bacon sandwiches.
[ Laughs ]
I'm looking at my turkey slices,
and they look like blondies,
and I don't want them
to look like that,
so I decide to airbrush them.
They're really blond blondies,
so I just wanted them to be
a little bit more realistic.
Pink!
To make my "lettuce,"
I whisk together
the coconut
and green food coloring
until it looks like lettuce.
I hope that this lettuce
will bring a little bit of color
to it and some taste.
That's good.
I take the bottom half
of my lemon cake, "bread,"
put some white chocolate
ganache for mayonnaise,
then the cheese, bologna,
more chocolate ganache, top bun,
and, boom, bologna sandwich.
Butt slice,
no one wants those.
This totally looks like
a peanut butter and jelly
dessert imposter.
Let's get some bread.
So I'm ready to
assemble my sandwich,
so the first thing I do is form
my bread, also known as cake.
Then I put the tuna salad,
which is really whipped cream,
and then I put on
another piece of bread.
VALERIE: 5 minutes!
[ Singsongy ] Chicken nuggets.
I'm gonna use the leftover
frosting that I have to make it
like a "honey mustard" dip.
Perfecto.
Bryn, you done?
-You sure?
-Yeah.
Is there anything else you could
make that plate amazing?
I don't see anything wrong,
but I'm just gonna
keep on looking
so she thinks I'm doing
what she said.
Sanding sugar or "salt."
[ Laughs ]
Ooh, delicious.
So I check on my cakes again.
Oh, so the top is done.
* Ah *
Thank goodness they are
finally cooked.
Hot.
So I am cutting through
my first loaf of bread,
and it's kind of breaking.
When I try to cut it very thin,
it's just crumbling.
Oh, darn it.
So I'm just gonna cut it
a little thicker.
I think having the bread
a little thick will be okay
because I know that
this cake is nice and moist.
That's a pretty
nice looking sandwich.
90 seconds.
Okay.
Oh, my god.
It ain't easy
to imposter-ize, is it?
-No!
-Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
You want to be
an imposter legend.
-Yogurt.
-That's so realistic.
DUFF AND VALERIE:
9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1, hands up!
-Those look really good.
-Thanks.
Way to go, bakers!
Good job, guys.
Time is up, and I'm
looking at my dish
and thinking it looks mushy
and gross like a tuna sandwich,
so I guess it's a good thing.
**
Lunch box imposters, you know,
I really think we put
this thing on the map.
Oh, you betcha.
I can't wait to see
what they've done.
Linsey.
-Hi, Linsey.
-Hi.
-How's it going?
-Good.
All right, Linsey, what was
your lunch box imposter,
and what'd you make for us?
So my lunch box imposter
was a bologna sandwich,
so I made for you
a lemon cake
as the bread and coating
chocolate for the cheese.
I used marzipan for the bologna,
and I made
a white chocolate ganache
mayonnaise inside
of the sandwich.
That's...
-Yeah, that's pretty good.
-[ Laughs ]
-Yes.
-That looks like bologna, man.
It really does.
Thank you.
I will say there's
a lot of bread.
That's more like a hoagie.
-Yeah.
-It's a bologna hoagie.
Yeah, it's a bologna hoagie.
Let's taste it.
**
-Ow.
-[ Laughs ]
Mm.
-I love this.
-Thank you.
I love the lemon
and the marzipan.
I didn't realize I liked them
so much together. I do now.
I love the crunchiness on
the edges of the bread -- cake.
You know, it's good,
but it is really thick.
I almost had to unhinge
my jaw like a snake
to get my mouth around it.
-Yeah.
So tell us about
your side dish.
I made chips, but they are
made of pie crusts,
and my twist juice
was grape juice,
so I made a grape
and mixed berry sauce.
You know, I'm looking at these
chips, and I'm like, "Okay.
They're too thick, and there's,
you know, not enough sauce."
I only see a little bit of sauce
down there, and I'm like,
"Okay. You know, I'm gonna
have to break Linsey's heart."
I can't.
They're good, you know?
[ Laughs ]
They just taste like
I'm eating pie.
Can totally taste grape juice.
Yes, taste grape juice.
Oh, I was so nervous.
Thank you.
-Great job.
-Thanks, Linsey.
Marzipan and lemon, delicious.
Julia, tell us
what you made today.
I got turkey wrap,
and for the juice twist,
I got orange juice,
and so for
the actual tortilla,
I did a orange flavored
crêpe batter.
And then for the turkey,
I did a blondie,
and I sliced it and airbrushed
it a little bit brown.
And for the lettuce, I did
shredded coconut dyed green.
I love, by the way,
that you made a green crêpe
because I love
those spinach wraps.
Your coconut is a little
on the green, green side.
Yeah. I feel like, if I ever got
lettuce that was that color,
I'd be a little wary
to be eating it.
It's pretty green.
It's pretty bright.
Your blondie
is deliciously moist,
and I love the flavor
of your crêpe.
I like that you put
orange in that.
Mm-hmm.
That's a fun way
to use the twist.
I would say that
it needs some sauce.
Mm.
Because it's, like,
dry coconut in a crêpe.
Okay.
Something to kind of
make it a little wetter.
Tell us about your side.
For the side,
I did apple chips,
and I baked them
with some cinnamon.
Apple chips that look
like potato chips.
They look like potato chips.
Look, even this one, being
a little bit on the burnt side,
that looks like
a real potato chip.
Now, they're a little floppy.
That's because they're apples.
Yeah.
They're a little soggy.
It's not the funnest thing.
[ Coughs ]
[ Laughs ] Too much?
-Yeah.
-That's a lot of cinnamon.
Sorry.
Well, thank you
very much, Julia.
Thank you.
That was a lot of cinnamon.
It's a lot of cinnamon.
Luke?
What did you get
for your lunch box imposter?
I got tuna salad sandwich.
-Tuna salad sandwich.
-[ Laughs ]
Can you say that
with more of a pout?
-Tuna salad sandwich.
-[ Laughs ]
You don't like tuna salad?
-Ugh.
-[ Laughs ]
Today, I made a tuna
salad sandwich,
and the bread is a white cake,
and the filling is
a coconut whipped cream
with chopped up
coating chocolates
as carrots and celery,
marshmallows as,
like, the little chunks of tuna,
and then, on the side,
I made a apple juice granola.
[ Laughs ]
It almost looked
like you were going
"apple juice granola,"
like a wink-wink.
What was it being
an imposter for?
A deconstructed granola bar
with apple juice.
Wow.
I feel like it's --
I don't know.
You're better than than that.
-More inventive.
-Yeah.
You can make all kinds
of good stuff.
I feel like that's not
a dessert imposter.
This doesn't necessarily say,
"Tuna salad sandwich."
It looks more like a, um...
Like a mayonnaise sandwich,
which are delicious.
[ Laughs ]
Really?
You've never had
a mayonnaise sandwich?
Just mayonnaise?
Mayonnaise. Yeah.
When you open the fridge,
and there's nothing
in there but mayonnaise.
-No.
-Okay.
That happens sometimes.
-Wait till you're at a college.
-[ Laugsh ] Right? Yeah.
Get to college, you'll be eating
a lot of mayonnaise sandwiches.
This tastes like a perfect
slice of cake
with some whipped cream in it.
I think you could have
definitely gone with
more of the orange
and the green chocolate.
The texture would've
been really great.
I like
the marshmallow in there.
I love marshmallows.
If tuna tasted like marshmallows
I would eat a lot more tuna.
[ Laughs ]
-Same.
-Right?
-Totally.
Now, your granola,
I don't really taste
the apple juice,
and I think what you probably
needed to do was reduce it,
put it in the oven,
toast it off,
and then all that syrup would
make it really stick together
and get really crunchy,
and if you took that granola
and folded it into
your whipped cream,
that totally would've
looked like tuna salad.
Totally would've looked
like tuna salad.
Oh, my goodness.
It totally would've.
Luke!
-Oh, man.
-Luke!
-Thanks a lot, man.
-Thanks, Luke.
Thank you.
Lots of missed
opportunities here.
**
The Imposter Challenge,
one of my favorites.
Yeah. You know, it's really
a litmus test for these kids.
Oh, you betcha. Uh-huh.
Abby!
-Hello.
-How's it going, Chef?
Good.
So what was your lunch
box imposter?
My lunch box imposter
was a PB&J sandwich.
I made a vanilla cake
for the bread,
pastry cream
for the peanut butter,
and my twist juice
was mixed berry,
so a mixed berry jam
for the jelly.
And what's your side dish?
My side dish
a strawberry yogurt,
which is actually
a strawberry whipped cream.
I love that you put
the yogurt in this.
It's bringing back memories
of when I used to box lunches.
It looks like a real
lunch box lunch.
Abby, this is great.
It really looks like
a PBJ, you know?
Really creative.
So it's pastry cream.
I'm gonna be thinking I'm
eating a peanut butter sandwich,
but I'm not.
**
Huh.
You know, Abby,
sometimes when bakers
are making dessert imposters,
you know, they focus
so much on the visual
that sometimes they forget
to make it good,
you know, to make it actually
something you want to eat,
and that is not the case.
This is really good.
The -- I want to say,
"Bread," but it's cake.
The cake is super moist.
I can really taste your twist.
You know, I can taste
your mixed berry juice
that you got in your juice box.
And it's the pastry
cream in there
that really puts it
all together.
I'm gonna have a little
bit of your yogurt.
Yogurt.
That is some yummy
whipped cream.
Big chunks of berry in there
add the tartness,
and then the sweetness
of the cream.
Yeah. I mean, it is.
It's good.
It's also really simple,
whipped cream
with some strawberries in it.
But yet, it's so delicious.
I want to slather that all
over the sandwich
and just stuff it in my face.
-Thanks, Abby.
-Thank you.
Thanks, Abby.
I just feel like Abby played it
safe with her side dish.
She didn't stretch herself,
but she also gave us
a really lovely tasting dish.
-Sure.
**
Hey, Bryn, come on in.
That is the smile
of somebody who thinks
they did a pretty good job.
[ Laughter ]
Okay. So, Bryn, what was
your lunch box imposter?
My lunch box imposter
was chicken nuggets.
I made the chicken nuggets
like cake balls
by crumbling up
some of my vanilla cake,
and then I took some
passionfruit buttercream
and put that into it.
And that was your
twist ingredient?
Yes.
I took mixed cereal and just
coated the outside a little.
My side dish is sugar
cookie French fries.
Oh, nice.
What's this?
Passionfruit buttercream,
honey mustard.
You know what I love about this?
The sanding sugar salt.
-Yes. It sparkles.
-Right?
It's perfect.
Now, these nuggets they look
95% amazing.
They're really good,
but they're a little blond.
They look like if I got them
from the grocery store
in the frozen food section,
right before
I put them in the fryer.
I think maybe even if you just
colored some of that cereal
a little darker before
you made the nuggets.
-Let's taste it.
-All right.
It even looks like chicken
nuggets on the inside.
-[ Laughs ]
-[ Laughs ] Look at that.
Totally tasting
the passionfruit.
Oh, thank you.
Totally tasting
the passionfruit.
That cake is moist,
perfect little bit of cake
and cream and crunch.
Thank you.
These sugar cookies,
by the way, delish.
-Thank you.
-Really delicious.
They're perfectly baked.
These cookies are a bit...
They're all right.
I like them.
I could've used a little
more excitement,
I think, in the flavor,
and you know what would've
made them really amazing?
An egg wash because right now,
they look like
uncooked potatoes.
I would've liked to have seen
all your food cooked up.
-Thanks, Bryn.
Thank you.
I feel like Bryn was so close
to being a
food imposter legend.
-Yep.
-I mean, these are really great.
They're beautiful.
Beautiful.
They're just the wrong color.
Alex!
I think being called in
for judging
is almost like going
to the principal's office.
It so scary.
So tell us what you got today
and how you made it for us.
So today I got a ham and cheese
sandwich, so as the bread,
I did a lemon pound cake,
and then for the ham,
I did a strawberry
lemonade crepe.
As the cheese, I did white
chocolate, which I dyed orange,
and then I put some
strawberries as the tomatoes.
Oh, lovely.
I think the bread,
it's really thick.
Usually with a sandwich,
I like lots of bread, so...
Because if you look at me,
I need the carbs, right?
[ Laughs ]
Okay, Alex, whatever you say.
You're so adorable.
What was your juice twist?
My juice twist was
the strawberry lemonade,
so I put it in my crêpe.
-For the ham?
-Yep.
Well, look at that. Yeah.
My ham is never
quite this orange.
Why didn't you use pink?
Oh, yeah.
That would work.
I think orange ham
would make me sick.
Okay. Here goes nothing.
Here is what's great about it,
the strawberry
and the chocolate,
when you crunch into
both of them together,
it tastes like
a chocolate-covered strawberry.
Ooh.
I didn't really taste
the lemonade.
Oh.
I think if you reduced it
and made it really strong
and then used that
in your crêpe,
you probably would've tasted it.
What did you make for your side?
So my side is a Caesar salad.
I did coconut flakes,
which I dyed green,
and also I put
some white chocolate
on the top as Parmesan.
You didn't dress your salad.
Well, sometimes I like to
eat salad without dressing.
I'm just getting a big mouthful
of, you know, dry coconut.
It looks amazing.
It's eh with the taste.
-Thanks, Alex.
-Bye.
See you.
-This is just weird.
-No.
I mean, I don't understand
what he was thinking with this.
I don't either.
**
DUFF:
The "Kids Baking Championship"
winner will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a feature story
in "Food Network Magazine"...
Yes!
...and $25,000!
[ Screaming and cheering ]
**
Lunch box imposters.
Lunch time
never looked so good.
Right,
especially Abby's PB&J.
It looks like peanut butter.
It really was a yummy dessert.
Like, it could've been
a dessert all on its own,
not even being on lunch
box impossibles.
Impossibles?
It's a new show.
Irvine in public schools.
[ Laughing ]
[ Imitating Robert Irvine ]
"Hello. Welcome to
lunch box impossible."
[ Laughing ]
I think Abby did an amazing
lunch box imposter,
but Linsey's
baloney sandwich...
Here we go.
...extraordinary.
The bread was too thick
on Linsey's sandwich.
I mean, tiny flaw,
but it was.
It looked like a...
We have to look at the tiniest
little mistakes.
We can't let them go by
like we did in Week 1.
I hate to say it, but there are
a few lunch box imposters
that I wouldn't mind trading.
Like Alex.
It's just is not working for me.
-Oh, Alex.
-The ham was orange.
For me, the person who
struggled today was Luke.
Okay. This is a little strange.
I mean, it tasted okay,
but it was just a bunch
of whipped cream
between two slices of cake.
All right. Val, we got to
make a decision here.
-Mm.
-Who's it gonna be?
**
Bakers, lunchtime will
never be the same again.
-[ Laughs ]
-No.
Two of you made lunch
box imposters
that really faked us out.
Abby.
-Good job, Abby.
-Good job.
-Linsey.
There was nothing phony
about how good
your imposters were today,
but only one of you
can be the real winner.
Abby!
Good job, Abby!
Ah!
It is so cool that I just
won another big bake.
Your PB&J imposter,
the cake was moist
and looked just like bread.
The pastry cream looked
just like peanut butter,
and the strawberry whipped
cream yogurt was super cute.
Congratulations.
You and Linsey will
be back next week.
-Yes.
-Good job, Abby.
Now a couple other imposters
had us doing double takes,
and those bakers are Bryn...
-Good job.
-And...
Oh, my god.
...Julia.
Really?
You're both safe.
Unfortunately, that leaves
Alex and Luke.
Please step up.
**
Alex,
there was too much bread
on your ham and cheese
sandwich imposter.
We didn't take the strawberry
lemonade in your ham crêpe,
and your salad badly
needed dressing.
Luke, your imposter didn't
say, "Tuna salad sandwich."
It needed more color and texture
to create the tuna salad effect,
and your granola side dish
needed more apple juice
and a trip to the oven.
Look, dessert imposters
are a difficult test of skill.
Both of you had great ideas,
but at this point
in the competition,
the details
are super important.
The baker leaving us
today is...
...Luke.
I'm sorry, man.
Thank you for the opportunity.
Luke, you are so awesome.
-Bye.
-You are a great baker.
We're gonna miss you.
You'll probably see me again.
Do they have, like,
"Teen Baking Championship"?
-Bye, Luke.
-See you, man.
Can I apply for
"Spring Baking Championship"
and try and beat
all the adults?
[ Laughs ]
That would be awesome.
**
VALERIE: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Imposters!
-Oh, my gosh.
-Oh!
And today, we are working
with classic lunch box items.
Ooh, delicious.
This is a little strange.
It really looks like a PBJ.
I want to stuff it in my face.
Only one of you can be
the real winner.
-Abby.
-Great job, Abby.
Good job.
This doesn't necessarily say
tuna salad sandwich.
It looks more like a...
Like a mayonnaise sandwich.
The baker leaving us
today is...
Luke.
**
-Oh, Snapchat.
-Oh, god.
Last week, I was
on the bottom again,
so I'm hoping that, this week,
I can redeem myself.
-Snapchat.
-Oh, it's space.
-Oh, this is cool.
-Space! I love space.
-Wow.
-I love the galaxy.
Galaxies are my favorite thing
in the world.
I am addicted to, like,
sci-fi stuff and coming...
Oh, god,
how great can this get?
**
ALL: Hi.
Bakers, we brought the galaxy
into our kitchen --
Galaxy!
...because, today,
you're gonna make something
out of this world.
Whoa!
We want to see colorful,
imaginative,
intergalactic desserts,
the kind of stuff we see
on the Food Network's Snapchat
Discover channel.
Whoa.
We're doing galaxy-themed stuff.
[ Laughs ]
When I'm older,
I'm going to have Snapchat
and take pictures
of all of my food
and desserts that I make.
-Macarons!
Oh, wow.
-Cool, right?
-Yeah.
-You're so excited, aren't you?
-I'm so excited.
You can make any kind of
intergalactic dessert
you want as long as it
takes us out there.
[ Laughs ]
Wow.
Okay, at least I get to pick
what I make.
But there's one more thing.
Oh.
Did you know astronauts
often ate freeze-dried foods?
Astronauts eat freeze-dried
stuff because it doesn't go bad
'cause you're not in space
for, like, two days.
You're in space for,
like, two years.
You must grab one of these
frozen dried ingredients
to use in your desserts --
strawberry, apricot,
banana, peach, or mango.
I'm not a big fan of a lot
of freeze-dried stuff,
so I feel bad
for the astronauts.
I've never worked with it
in my baking before.
We're giving you two hours
to go intergalactic,
and your baking time
starts in 3...2...1...
Blast off!
I got this.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
I got dried mango.
I got dried apricots.
I got dried peaches.
I'm the last boy standing.
I really want to represent
the boys
and make it to the finale.
Also, I'm representing Canada,
so there's a lot riding on this.
Mix that all together.
I know the universe is huge,
and I want to make
something that's big,
so I'm thinking a cake.
I am making a vanilla
tie-dye cake with
a dried peach
crème pâtissière filling
and American
buttercream frosting.
The first thing
I'm gonna work on
is my vanilla tie-dye cake.
It's a massive batch
of cake batter.
I think I'm taking a risk
with this tie-dye cake
because, in week six,
I got a lot of criticism
from the judges.
My tie-dye unicorn cake.
It is a little overbaked.
-Oh, okay.
-It's a little on the dry side.
I'm looking for redemption.
Bryn, if you were
to visit any planet,
which planet would you
want to visit?
Maybe Mars
because that's, like,
since they're kind of trying
to get there, it's pretty cool.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
When my batter's complete,
I color one blue, pink,
and purple
with gel food coloring.
Do I see Alex making
a tie-dyed cake?
It's a great idea.
I don't know how I feel about
him doing a tie-dye cake again.
Well, he had room
for improvement.
We'll see how it tastes.
I think these colors
look like space.
I swirl it around
with a toothpick
until it's like a galaxy.
Next week is the semifinals.
Only four people
are gonna be left,
so we have to get it perfect.
My cakes look like
a galactic soup.
The big bang theory
didn't come yet,
so it just needs to get baked.
How does this mango taste?
**
I get freeze-dried mangos.
Water?
I have never had mango before.
That is gross.
I don't know if I ever
will want to again.
Abby just tried her
freeze-dried mango.
I don't think she likes it.
I'm going to make a mango cake
pop and dip my cake pops
in different colored
white chocolate,
and that's gonna
look like a galaxy.
Cake pops are one
of my specialties,
so I'm very confident
in this challenge.
First, I get started
on my mango cake batter.
I'm going to process my mangos
and then add them in as some
of my flour into my cake,
and I'm also gonna
make a mango buttercream.
Oh, that smells really bad.
Hopefully, Duff and Valerie
like mango
'cause, if they don't, they are
not gonna like this cake.
Bake, baby, bake.
Bake, bake, bake.
To make my mango buttercream,
I'm creaming together
butter and shortening,
and then I'm adding
in my powdered sugar
and some mango purée.
The judges can't tell me
it doesn't taste like mango.
Oh, you're making
cake pops, Abby?
Yes, ma'am.
Quickly name the planets!
-Quickly name the planets?
-In order!
Oh, man, come on.
I don't know them in order.
-Pluto --
-Mars, Venus, Earth.
You asked me to do it.
I mean...
[ Laughs ]
Okay. Go.
Pluto -- Wait, is Pluto
a planet anymore?
I think Pluto is a planet.
I don't care what they say.
Yeah, but, like, it was,
and then it wasn't.
-It's a planet.
-Okay.
The space part of science
is really cool.
I like Pluto even though it's
not "considered" a planet now.
It's really small and tiny,
but I get bananas.
They smell weird.
I'd rather eat, like, a regular
banana than a dried banana.
Okay.
I decided to make cupcakes
because they're fast to cook,
and I'll have time
to decorate them.
I'm going to turn them into
intergalactic cupcakes
by swirling the frosting.
Hey, Bryn.
-Hello.
-What's going on?
I got dried banana,
and I have fresh
and dried bananas
in my cake batter,
and I'm gonna pipe
out, like, a planet
and, like,
a little rocket ship.
How bad do you want to be
the Kids Baking Champion?
So bad because I want to buy
myself a Labradoodle
and name it Snickerdoodle
and then some towards
my baking business.
I love it all.
When I put the freeze-dried
bananas in my batter,
it'll kind of turn back
into a "regular banana"
because it'll kind of hydrate
itself in the cake batter.
This actually looks good.
Make sure you taste.
Get some of that banana.
Ooh. It tastes good.
I get them into the cupcake pans
with a silver liner
and get them in the oven.
Oh, hot.
For my frosting, I separate it
into three bowls,
color one purple
and then the other teal
and then another one black.
I want my intergalactic
frosting to stand out.
Looking good.
All right.
Here's an eclipse.
-Don't move.
-Oh.
**
[ Laughs ]
Mm. Oh, that smells
like strawberries.
I have not had dried
strawberries before,
but I have had, like,
dried fruit before,
so I kind of know
how they work.
So my inspiration for this
dessert is my love for galaxies
because I'm, like,
in love with it,
so I'm making
a strawberry sugar cookie
with a royal icing decoration.
I decided on this
because I think a cookie
is a great canvas
for making a galaxy design,
and I also can just
grind up the strawberry
and use it as a dry
ingredient in the cookie.
Some natural pigment here.
So I start by making
my strawberry sugar cookie.
I take my freeze-dried
strawberries,
put them in a food processor
so it turns into a powder,
take it out,
and it just poofs everywhere,
and I inhale it,
and I'm, like, coughing.
Oh, in my lungs.
Does that mean my breath
smells like strawberry?
So I add some of my strawberry
powder into the dry ingredients.
It's really, like,
a really strawberry flavor.
Everywhere, it just smells
like strawberry.
-It's a pink powder.
-I know. My dough is pink.
I roll the dough out,
use a cookie cutter
to cut my shapes, into the oven.
Time to make some royal icing.
Royal icing is simply egg whites
and powdered sugar
and once it hardens,
and it's also a great
canvas for cool designs.
Put some food coloring
in and dye it black, blue,
purple, and pink.
Those colors are, like,
the classic colors
of the space galaxy.
I don't really like
strawberries, so...
You don't like strawberries?
It's, like, not as sweet
as you expect,
so then I feel like
strawberries, for me,
are like a bunch
of disappointments.
It's so sweet.
I grab apricots.
I never tried an apricot,
and I've definitely
never tried
a freeze-dried apricot,
but I like it.
It's really good.
Tell me about your
intergalactic dessert.
I'm doing cream puffs filled
with apricot pastry cream --
Okay.
...and, like, a galaxy
white chocolate ganache on top.
-Super spacey.
-Yeah.
Do you like space?
I used to, like, a lot a year
ago, but then I started baking.
-Mm-hmm.
-So...
Probably not a lot
of pink in space.
I think some of those
nebulas could be.
There's pink stars.
Maybe there's more pink than
we're giving space credit for.
To make my pâte à choux
dough, first,
I get started on heating
together water, butter,
and salt.
The butter mixture
is coming to a boil,
so I slowly add in my flour.
Now that my dough mixture
looks like
it's pulling away
from the sides of the pan,
I beat it, and I'm piping it
onto a greased baking sheet.
Brushing my pâte à choux
with egg wash
will give it a nice
golden brown color.
Ooh, we haven't seen
pâte à choux yet.
-Mm-hmm.
-This is exciting.
I know that the judges
see pâte à choux
as a pretty difficult
thing to make,
so I really want to show them
that I can do it right.
Going in the oven!
90 minutes left, bakers.
We want you to make
desserts and beyond.
To make my apricot pastry cream,
I first get started
on whisking together
the milk, sugar,
and vanilla bean
in a sauce pan over medium heat,
so I'm hoping that adding
the dried apricot to the milk
will get the flavor in there.
In a separate bowl,
I whisk together milk,
cornstarch to thicken it,
and egg yolks.
I need to strain this
apricot and vanilla steeped milk
so I can slowly add it
into the egg yolks.
Oh, my god.
And it looks like water,
chunky water.
Oh, my god.
I have no idea
why this happened.
Looks like water, and I don't
think that's what pastry cream
is supposed to look like,
and that's, like,
the entire dish.
Cream puffs aren't cream puffs
without pastry cream.
Like, it would just be puffs,
so this needs to work.
Come on.
**
Oh, my god.
It looks like chunky water.
Hour and 20 minutes, guys.
Intergalactic desserts,
blow our minds!
Come on.
All right. Julia is making
a pastry cream, I think,
and now she's got this weird,
broken apricot milk water.
Ugh.
Mm.
Ew.
Really?
This can't be happening.
These are dried apricots,
so I guess that it, like,
absorbed the milk
and just left water.
I have a good idea now.
I really have to restart fast.
I've done vanilla
pastry cream a lot,
so I'm going to skip
the apricots in it
and go with what I know.
Once my milk mixture is boiling,
I'm straining it,
and it looks perfect.
Oh, that's better.
Phew.
This is a huge relief.
I slowly whisk that into
my egg-yolk mixture
and cooking it
until it thickens.
I take some leftover apricot
powder that I made,
and I'm putting that into
my finished pastry cream.
Now I can move on to every
other thing I have to make.
My cream puffs look perfect.
I'm at least happy
that something worked out.
Hey, Duff, you know
what my favorite star is?
Sirius.
Yeah, I'm serious.
The Sun! What?
-The Sun rules.
-Yeah.
Bakers, can we have
your attention, please?
-What?
-Oh, my god.
You must also make
an edible Sun --
Sun?
...to go with your
intergalactic desserts.
[ Laughs ]
-I think Bryn's happy.
-What?
I'm pretty happy about this
twist because I love the Sun.
You cannot use fondant
or gum paste.
Okay.
Like, really edible,
not just semiedible.
That would be way too easy.
I'm really crunched for time
on these cake pops,
and now I have to make
a edible Sun to go with them?
Let's see what you got, bakers.
Who has the marshmallows?
I am feeling pretty
good on time,
so I decide to make my sun now.
Julia, can I have
the rice cereal?
Yeah.
For my Sun, I'm going to
make a rice cereal treat ball,
cover it in yellow
coating chocolate.
I'm gonna make mine different
by making the eyes
'cause it's a cute Sun.
It's a happy Sun.
Then, for the rays,
I'm gonna make little streaks
of yellow coating chocolate.
It's kind of like you blob it
and then spread it
and blob and spread.
Hey, Val.
Why don't aliens eat clowns?
I don't know. Why?
-'Cause it tastes funny.
-[ Laughs ]
-Hi, Abby.
-Hello.
-How do you feel about mango?
-I do not like it.
-Why?
-It's, like, too citrusy.
**
Yeah, I know.
You're the queen of lemons,
but I just --
I don't know.
I don't really like citrus.
What are you gonna do
for the twist?
I'm going to make
a rice cereal Sun.
I'm going to dip it
in coating chocolate.
That sounds great.
But I'll figure that out later.
Crumbles.
I'm taking my cooled cake
and putting it into
the food processor.
Hmm, it's already pretty moist.
I don't know.
I am food processing it together
with my mango buttercream
because then the cake pops
will hold their shape more.
Oh, perfect. Okay.
I'm scooping out my cake crumbs
with a cookie scooper.
That way, all of my cake balls
will be exact same size.
Are you going to be using all
of the black coating chocolate?
No, you can have it.
I'm melting my black
coating chocolate
so I can use a lollipop stick
and dip it in the chocolate
and then stick it
into the cake ball
so that they will not
fall off of the stick.
Alex, what are you making?
I made, like, a tie-dye cake
with, like, all
the colors of space.
-Ooh, pretty.
-Yeah.
They kind of look great.
Yay!
But I have to get started
on this crème pâtissière
'cause it takes a while.
This crème pâtissière is
actually my Nonna's recipe,
Italian grandma, if you're
wondering what Nonna is.
[ Gasps ] Oh, my god.
One of my cakes
was still in there.
Oh, shoot. Oh, my god.
I forgot about it.
Get this one out. Wow.
Whew, the second one is fine.
Oh, it's a big relief.
Okay.
I have my milk on the stove,
which I'm going to infuse
with my dried peaches.
When that's boiling, I will
actually temper it
with some eggs and cornstarch.
Oh, my god.
I look at the milk.
It's overflowing.
It's overboiled, but I just
have to work with it.
I temper it with my egg yolks,
sugar and cornstarch mixture.
Oh, my god. It's scrambled.
Oh, jeez.
Everything's going wrong.
These eggs are scrambled.
I don't know why
it's scrambling on me.
This crème pâtissière
has to come together.
This is part of my cake.
I'm just gonna strain it,
see what happens.
You know what?
I'll put it through a sieve.
I want to make sure
that there's no clumps,
and I think it's working.
I guess my mind was playing
tricks on me,
and then I have to fold
in my heavy cream.
DUFF: Okay.
Alex is focused right now.
It's good. I like it.
VALERIE: Mm-hmm.
Looks like he's got
everything under control.
Yeah, it's like his brain
is very loud.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
He's just thinking it through,
thinking it through.
I just mixed that up,
and then it looked okay.
Magic.
Then I get started
on my buttercream.
I separate my buttercream
into three bowls.
One I just leave white.
One I color pink, and the other
I color like a darker blue.
-50 minutes left, bakers!
-Oh, my god.
God, I have so much to do.
I have to take a chill pill.
I don't even know
if I can finish.
**
Duff, what are you doing?
Just playing with the ball.
Okay.
Oh.
I think Duff's head kind of
looks like another planet.
[ Laughs ]
Abby, can I borrow some
of your candy melt colors?
Yes.
I start working on my Sun
with no fondant or gum paste.
**
Okay. Thank you.
It's not the best thing,
but that's what rice cereal
treats are for.
Whoopsies.
I may have spilled
all over the place.
I put them into sphere molds,
and I get that into
the blast chiller.
While that's happening,
I prepare my coating chocolate.
I mix together some yellow
and some orange.
Then, once my rice cereal
treat is done,
I'm trying to spread
the coating chocolate
all over the rice cereal treat,
but it's really hard.
It's taking too much time,
so I just gave up
and took the whole thing
and put it in the bowl.
It's kind of messy.
-Hi.
-How's it going, Linsey?
Pretty good.
What do you really love
about space?
I don't know.
It's just it's so big,
and you don't know what's --
[ Buzzer ]
-Oh, I think that's my timer.
-Is that your -- Go, go, go.
-All right.
-Go, go, go.
-Ah.
-Good luck, Linsey.
Thank you.
It smells like strawberries.
That did not turn out how I
wanted it to, but that's okay.
Edges are a little bit
too brown.
I overbaked these.
Uh-oh.
These cookies are not serveable.
They're not soft
in the center at all.
They need to be at least
a little bit soft in the center,
so I'm like,
"What am I gonna do?"
Do I have time
to make another batch?
Ugh.
At this point in
the competition,
I cannot serve an overbaked
cookie to Duff and Valerie.
That just won't work.
All right.
**
30 minutes, bakers!
Intergalactic desserts.
With an edible Sun.
I overbaked these.
These cookies are not serveable.
Oops, Linsey's cookies
are a little brown.
It looks like space bologna.
They're overbaked.
I don't know why.
Do you think I have time
to bake more?
It only takes
10 minutes to bake.
If it only takes
10 minutes, then yeah.
Okay. I'm going to.
I'm going to take the risk
and try and bake
a new batch of cookies
for less time in the oven
because I need these
to be perfect.
I mean, I'm trying to get
into the semifinals.
I always make extra batter
just in case
for a time like this,
so, like, yay.
**
Hey, Bryn,
blast chiller's open.
It's time to start
frosting my cupcakes.
Thank you.
For my intergalactic design,
you can put three bags
into one bag
so it looks like it's all mixed
together and galaxy,
but I can't fit
the blue in there,
so I'm just going to have
to take that one out
and just do black and purple.
Come on, purple.
I frost little dollops
on each cupcake
and decorate them with
luster dust and white pearls.
I make my rocket ships by taking
black and red coating chocolate.
Then, for my black, I make
little V shapes on the bottom,
and for my red,
I make little ovals.
They're rocket ships.
For the planets, I just make
a circle and then a line across.
Happy.
We're somewhere here.
We're -- No, that's
South America.
-I'm turning it.
-I see us.
No, you -- Well, now
we're in Australia.
-Now I'm looking at Australia.
-Okay.
I want to be in Australia.
I like Australia.
[ Australian accent ]
Fat lot of good that'll do you.
[ Laughs ]
**
My cake pops are sticking
to the pan
a little bit
in my blast chiller,
but I'm just pulling them off
and hoping that
the judges don't mind
if there's a indent in it.
I'm drizzling blue
coating chocolate
and pink coating chocolate
on top of my black
coating chocolate
so, that way, I can create
a marble effect
for my cake pops.
If you stick it in Styrofoam,
then all the chocolate
melts down,
and you don't have
a ring at the top.
Abby's cake pops
are coming together.
Yeah, but I don't see the Sun.
My marbled cake pops
are turning out beautiful.
They look just like a galaxy.
Now my Sun.
I'm going to make
rice cereal treats
and mold them into a ball.
How do you get the cereal treats
to not stick to your hands?
Use the spray and, like,
spray it on you.
I'm going to coat them
in yellow coating chocolate.
Everybody feeling confident?
I want to hear, "Yes, ma'am!"
ALL: Yes, ma'am!
Next, I'm going to make
the little orange
coating chocolate sunrise.
Your Sun looks good, Abby.
Thank you.
My Sun is not
very smooth so yeah.
I'm really worried.
It is really important to do
well in this challenge
because this bake determines
who is going to make it
into the semifinals.
20 minutes left!
I have no time for this twist.
Okay.
Okay. An edible Sun?
That's fine.
But no fondant or gum paste?
That was my go-to plan.
I see in the pantry that
there's sphere molds,
so I'm gonna use
the molds to make a 3D Sun
out of my cereal treats
and cover it
in coating chocolate.
I'm using some orange sprinkles,
and I'm putting that on top of
my Sun to give it that flair.
I really want to win because,
with the $25,000,
I'd buy this huge cat
stuffed animal.
I love stuffed animals.
Why'd the Sun
go to school, Duff?
Why did the Sun go to school?
To get brighter.
[ Laughs ]
They look a tiny bit better,
not quite.
Intergalactic-themed things
in general have, like,
a bunch of colors
that just swirl together,
pretty and irregular
and beautiful,
so I'm using black
as a background
because that's, like, the main
color of, like, space galaxies.
Then I take my blue,
pink, purple
and make some swirls on top.
Then I use a toothpick, and I
drag all of the icing around
so it's a nice marbled design.
Linsey, how you doing
over there?
I'm going as fast as I can.
13 minutes left.
Final touches, I'm using
some peppermint extract
and luster dust,
mix them together
to create, like, a paint.
Then I put it on a paintbrush,
and I flick the paintbrush
so the paint splatters
onto the cookie,
creating, like,
nice scattered star effect.
I think these cookies
are out of this world.
Pretty sure some got in my eye,
but that's okay.
And I also put it on the Sun,
and now my Sun looks golden,
and it's glowing
like an actual sun.
Alex, how are you doing?
I'm a little behind schedule.
This twist is terrible
because I've had some issues.
I don't know if I'm gonna
get everything done.
Ugh!
I'm gonna make my edible Sun
by cutting the top of my cakes,
and then I'm gonna use
those crumbled pieces,
and then I'm gonna
put in some buttercream
and make, like,
a giant cake pop.
I need to speed up.
Let's wrap this thing.
And then I cover it in fondant.
I draw some eyes.
I wonder what Alex is doing with
a big block of yellow fondant.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
I forgot I can't use fondant
on this Sun.
Oh, my god.
What am I thinking?
Duff said I cannot use fondant.
Ugh!
I just wasted so much time.
I'm a pretty bad
listener sometimes.
Okay.
Okay. Oh, my god.
**
-This one --
-Thank you.
You got five minutes
to get to outer space.
Intergalactic desserts
with an edible Sun,
no fondant, no gum paste.
I wonder what Alex is doing with
a big block of yellow fondant.
Oh, okay.
What am I thinking?
I cannot use fondant.
Ugh!
This is costing me so much time.
Oh.
I have a lot to do still.
I need a miracle right now.
Does anyone have
the yellow or...
The yellow what?
Does anybody have
the yellow coating chocolate?
Yes...
I decide I'm just going to cover
it in melted coating chocolate,
and then maybe I'm just gonna
roll it in some sprinkles.
I have to finish.
I think, to me,
it looks like a Sun
that has been beat up
a little bit.
The Sun is pretty old.
It must've got beat up by
some of the other planets here
and there.
Now I'm in a mad rush to finish.
I have to finish, or else,
I will be going home.
To assemble my cake,
I take my peach crème pâtissière
and then put that
in the middle and then
my second layer of cake,
and then on the outside,
I put my American
buttercream frosting.
I alternate between my blue,
my pink and my white
to make almost, like,
a galaxy-looking cake.
-Time?
-Three minutes, Alex.
Aye, yi, yi.
There's almost no time left,
and Julia is just starting
to fill her cream puffs.
-I can't watch.
-You better pipe fast.
I'm so far behind.
I spent so much time
remaking my pastry cream.
My time management is not good.
Julia, you're cutting it close.
I know.
I'm doing the math
inside my head,
and making 12 cream puffs
in only a few minutes,
I don't think I'll have time.
Julia, are you gonna finish?
I don't think so.
-You can do it.
-Go, go, go.
-Am I even --
Everybody's gonna finish,
right?
-Yeah.
-You got it.
-It's okay, Julia.
You got this.
Take your time.
Take your time. Breathe.
Breathe.
Touchdown.
I'm rushing to get
this Sun on top.
Oh, my god. Disaster.
Keep your head in the game.
I want to make sure that
I cover the cardboard
because the judges
will really hit me
if I serve them cardboard again.
Looks like a little planet
is there.
I just put all these dollops
all over my cake,
and they look like
little planets
'cause there's eight of them.
They're all orbiting the sun.
One minute,
you've got this, Julia.
I can do this.
I'm taking an airbrush
and brushing on some black.
It does resemble a galaxy.
7...6...
5...4...
3...2...1...
Hands up.
Oh, no.
My cereal treat
is imploding right now.
Now I'm going to have to present
this sun to the judges,
and it doesn't even
look like a sun.
Oh...
Intergalactic desserts,
fantastic.
Can't wait.
Hey, Abby.
-Hi.
-Hi, honey.
How's it going, Abby?
So what happened to the sun?
It had a lot of gas in it
and then it exploded.
-So it's the end of the world?
-Yes.
I love that you took the time
to make different color
for the rays.
I wish it had stayed
together, though.
-Yeah.
-Darn it.
Tell us about your cake pops.
My cake pops are a mango cake
pop dipped in coating chocolate.
I hope it tastes
as good as it looks
because I love looking at it.
It's just sparkly and swirly
and colorful and fun.
I actually really like the fact
that there's like black, black,
black, black,
little bit of color,
black, black, black,
black, little bit of color.
Here we go.
**
Your cake here
is really mashed up.
Now it tastes good and it
really tastes like mango,
and that's awesome,
but I think it's a little dense,
and I feel like the texture,
you still want it
to be reminiscent of cake.
It's almost like cookie dough,
a touch on the sweet side
because the chocolate is sweet,
and I love it.
-You do?
-I love it.
Okay. [ Laughs ]
Let's taste this sun,
shall we?
Cereal treat, very tasty,
fell apart, though.
-Oops.
-Abby, thank you so much.
-Thanks, Abby.
-Thank you.
See you.
Oh, I'm really worried.
**
Intergalactic desserts.
I love this challenge,
love it.
Alex.
All right. So tell us your
freeze-dried ingredient
and your intergalactic
inspiration.
I got the freeze-dried peaches,
and my inspiration
behind this cake
is my love for science
and planets and stars,
so I made a vanilla tye-dye cake
with dried peach
crème pâtissière filling
and American buttercream,
which I dyed a few
different colors.
And then the sun
is actually a cake ball,
and on the outside,
you have yellow candy melts
and I rolled it in sprinkles.
-Alex.
-Yeah?
I am so proud of you.
Oh, thank you.
Are you looking
for redemption?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, aw.
I love the swirls.
It's almost like the sun
is exploding.
I love that you hid
the cardboard.
There are a couple
little technical flaws.
Your icing job, you just need
to be a little bit smoother,
and the sun is not
quite centered on the cake.
I wish the sun was
a little more round,
a little more well-defined.
I don't mind the finish
on the cake.
I really do think it looks
like a rustically-iced cake.
**
Hmm, now I was supposed
to taste peach in there?
Yeah.
Oh, my goodness.
Is he not tasting the peach?
Well, that's good 'cause
I totally taste peaches.
Oh, okay, good.
Don't you dare mess
with me like that.
You can really make me pass out.
I love all the colors in here,
and the crème pâtissière
is so lovely
and creamy and smooth.
That is a really light, fluffy,
tender, delicious, moist cake.
Thank you.
We need to try the sun
a little bit.
I love the crunch
of the non-pareils
and the coating chocolate,
and then that flavor.
You get that cake flavor
right inside.
-I'm impressed.
-I'm very impressed, Alex.
Oh, okay, that's good.
You redeemed yourself today.
-Okay, thank you.
-See you.
I think my galaxy cake is gonna
blast me to the semi-finals.
**
Bryn.
My freeze-dried ingredient
was freeze-dried bananas,
and I made a banana cupcake
with banana frosting.
That sun is so cool.
Thank you.
I love it, but what is
the red bug on my...
It's supposed to be
rocket ships.
Oh, it's a rocket ship.
Some have, like,
a planet on them.
-Oh, I got a planet --
-Yeah.
...and a rocket.
What I'm looking at here
is naked cupcake,
and it would have been nice
to fill all this nakedness
in with the blue.
I, too, would like to see
this a little fuller,
but I can't get too mad
because this is the color
of the Baltimore Ravens,
the greatest football team.
I don't think the purple is
enough to let me really say,
"Okay, yeah,
this is outer space."
This rocket ship
is kind of adorable.
**
Bryn, this is so moist --
-Oh, thank you.
-...and so yummy.
It's saying,
"Banana, banana, banana."
I don't know if it says
intergalactic to me,
but that is
one yummy cupcake.
-Thank you.
-A little dense.
Okay.
A little dense,
you need to be fluffier.
You got good banana flavor,
and that's really,
that's tough to do.
Let me try and taste this Sun.
You have anything to say, Sun?
Seriously, Bryn,
that technique with the rays
is just so wonderful.
Thank you.
You're like a child, just --
I am pretty strong.
Oh, no.
That looks so good.
Mm-hmm, that's yummy.
That sun was hilarious.
It was a fun, interactive
moment with your dessert there.
-[ Laughs ]
-Thank you, Bryn.
-Thanks, Bryn.
-You're welcome. Thank you.
**
-Hi, Linsey.
-Hi.
What kind of cookies are they?
Strawberry sugar cookies.
I made royal icing, and I piped
them in swirls and I did,
like, a drag marble.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Mine looks like
a far out galaxy.
It's pretty far out, man.
It's like you're flying
into a black hole.
For the sun, I made
a rice cereal treat.
I painted on some yellow
gold luster dust.
The sun is really beautiful.
If I was at, like,
the restaurant at NASA,
you know, and this
is what I got for dessert,
I'd be pretty happy about that.
You know?
Let's see what's going on here.
Ooh, looks like it's going to be
a little bit crunchy
and a little bit chewy,
and I think...
That's so good.
Is it good?
-Really?
-Thank you.
So strawberry, like, there's
strawberry all through that.
And my brain and my heart
explode with joy.
-Linsey, that's a good cookie.
-Thank you.
You know, I mean, look,
it's perfect on the outside,
nice and crispy.
On the inside,
it's a little bit chewy.
You've just blown me away.
There we go.
Thank you.
It's like one of those
chocolate mint candies,
but with the crunchiness
of the cereal treat.
Wow, is this good.
I love it.
I could use a little
more marshmallow.
What do you think of the mint?
I don't like it.
I love it.
That's a big bite
of coating chocolate.
Val, you're eating it
like an after-dinner mint.
Thank you, Linsey.
-Linsey, thank you.
-Thank you.
**
Hey, Julia.
I made a cream puff filled
with a apricot pastry cream,
and it's topped with
a white chocolate ganache.
It looks really cool, and I love
that you used a couple colors
on there, the orange
and the yellow.
It gives it dimension.
-I love sprinkles.
-Yeah.
Would I really know
that this was intergalactic?
Well, there is the sun,
so you could, like, guess.
It just looks like...
Moon rocks.
-Yeah, but, you know --
-That's spacey.
...yeah, I mean, cream puffs
are delicious, so it's still --
I'm still going to eat it.
It's frustrating because I
could see where you were headed,
and it just didn't happen.
Yeah.
**
So, Julia, your pastry
cream is delicious --
-Yay.
-...super smooth, super velvety.
Okay.
Your pâte à choux
is also really good.
It's nice and dry and crispy.
The bad part is I love
your pastry cream so much,
-I didn't get enough of it.
-Okay.
I'm tasting a little bit of
the apricot,
barely, barely, barely.
One thing I like
about your sun,
nice and big
and round and bulbous,
just like the sun, and I like
the orange sprinkles on there.
It kind of gives it some depth.
That is so yummy.
Just the right amount
of marshmallow.
-You need a lot of marshmallow.
-Mmm!
Well, it didn't really
take me to outer space,
but it definitely
took me to flavor town.
-Thank you, Julia.
-Thank you.
Thanks, Julia.
Ugh, I don't know
what to expect.
I'm crossing my fingers,
and I'm hoping for the best.
**
DUFF:
The "Kids Baking Championship"
winner will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a feature story
in "Food Network Magazine,"
and...
$25,000.
[ Screaming ]
**
There were definitely some
stellar desserts today,
like that tie-dye
cake from Alex.
He redeemed himself.
It had a cool
intergalactic theme.
The icing looked awesome.
I tasted peach.
And he was the only one
that didn't do a cereal treat
as the sun.
I like that.
For me, the baker that really
stood out today, Linsey.
Those cookies were
out of this world.
-[ Laughs ]
They were such beautiful
little pieces of art
that tasted
really delicious.
That sun was beautiful.
Yeah, it looked like it
should have been in a magazine.
It looked like a professional
pastry chef did that plate.
Yeah, but what about
Bryn's sun?
That was so cool,
the way she had the rays
just coming off the sun.
That was a very
advanced technique.
However, there were
a few desserts
that crash-landed today.
I cannot help but bring up
Julia and that cream puff.
There was not enough
pastry cream inside,
and I could barely, barely,
barely taste the apricot.
I didn't get intergalactic
by looking at it.
No.
If they were pure black and just
had a few little stars on there,
I could have seen it.
You know?
Yeah.
Like deep space,
like black holes.
Yeah.
And then Abby's cake pops,
or should I say,
cookie dough pops.
It was too sweet.
It did taste like mango --
Very much so.
...and Abby's poor sun.
-Oh.
-It went supernova.
Okay, we have a big
decision to make.
Oh, this one is
a really tough one.
But we're also down
to the final five,
and all five of them
are awesome.
They are awesome,
awesome bakers.
**
I really want to stay
in this competition
'cause I want
to show the judges
I'm the best baker here.
Bakers, you created
intergalactic desserts
that were as varied
as the stars in the sky.
However, two of you managed
to outshine the rest.
-Alex.
-Good job.
Good job, Alex.
I'm back.
Yes, I'm on top.
Boo-yah, I'm in the semi-finals.
You redeemed yourself today
with your tie-dye cake 2.0.
-[ Laughs ]
-Linsey.
Good job.
Your intergalactic cookies
were works of art.
Yes.
But only one baker
can rocket to the top,
and that baker is...
Linsey!
-Good job.
-Thank you.
And I won.
I am so happy I won this one.
It was, like,
my dream challenge.
-Congratulations, Linsey.
-Thank you.
You and Alex will be back
next week.
Now there was one other baker
that stopped
just short of the stratosphere,
and that baker is...
Bryn.
Good job, Bryn.
Yay!
Unfortunately, that leave
Julia and Abby.
Please step forward.
I could be going home today.
It would be such a bummer.
I want people to know me
as a consistent baker
who's always good.
Abby, your outer space cake
pops were really dense,
and the whole thing
was a bit too sweet.
As for your sun, well,
it imploded like a supernova.
Julia, your cream puffs
did not say intergalactic.
Your cereal treat sun
lacked luster,
and when we tasted
your cream puffs,
neither of us got apricot.
Both of you made it this far.
That's quite an accomplishment.
Unfortunately,
the baker
leaving us today is...
Julia.
I'm sorry.
Julia, you are amazing.
I loved all the pink.
We're going to miss you
and your pink apron
in this kitchen.
Please keep baking.
I'm feeling really sad
that I got eliminated.
Even though I didn't
win the $25,000,
I am still going
to try to, someday,
afford my pink snake,
my pink dog,
my giant stuffed animal cat,
and a pink house.
[ Laughs ]
**
DUFF: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Today, you're gonna make
something out of this world.
Intergalactic desserts.
[ Laughs ]
Linsey, if I was at
the restaurant at NASA,
and this is what
I got for dessert,
I'd be pretty happy
about that.
Alex, I love all
the colors in here,
best cake
I've seen from you.
Only one baker
can rocket to the top.
Linsey!
Julia, I can see
where you were headed,
and it just
didn't happen.
Yeah.
Julia and Abby...
Julia,
you crashed today.
I'm sorry.
**
ABBY: Final four, woo-hoo!
I was in the bottom
two last week,
so I need to step up my game
so I can get into the finale.
-What's this?
-Castle, a sandcastle.
This is so cool.
-What is that?
What if it's, like, we have
to use, like, a beach flavor.
A beach flavor,
what's a beach flavor?
I don't know.
Hey, there, bakers.
-Hi.
Isn't this time of year
just the best?
Spring Break is around
the corner...
-Yeah.
...and we can finally go
to our favorite place,
the beach!
Yes.
Totally, dude.
Oh, my goodness.
And one of my favorite
things to do at the beach
is build sandcastles
and snack our faces off.
So, bakers, today we are
giving you 2 hours
to create a cereal-treat
sandcastle...
-[ Gasps ]
...and you're
gonna fill it
with one dozen
baked goods.
Uh, wait.
Hold on.
Oh. Those smiles
went to frowns.
Yeah.
Alex, you all right?
I don't...
Never built a sandcastle
in Alberta?
We don't have any beaches
in Alberta.
[ Laughter ]
Bakers, we are down
to the final four.
-* Dun, dun, dun *
-Oh, my God.
This big bake
will determine
which three of you
will make it to the finale,
where you'll be competing
for a chance
to win $25,000
and the title
of Kids Baking Champion.
We're so close.
One more challenge,
then I'm in the finale,
and I have a chance, a real,
real chance to win $25,000.
Oh, my God.
All right, bakers.
Give it everything you've got.
-I'm so nervous.
-Same.
Your baking time
starts...
now!
**
When I go to the beach, I
usually go to the Jersey Shore.
**
I sometimes build sandcastles.
Usually I don't because I don't
have, like, the buckets.
I usually, like, dig a giant
hole and then sit in it.
It sounds, like, really boring,
but it's actually
really satisfying.
For my baked treat, I am going
to make a mini berry hand pie.
Cold butter.
First I get started
on my pie crust.
I put flour, butter and salt
into the food processor,
grind it up until
it resembles crumbs,
and I add in my water and I
also add some white vinegar
because that makes it
more flaky, pulse it
until it forms into a dough.
All right.
Now I start making my filling.
I take some blueberries,
blackberries and raspberries,
put them into a saucepan,
add some lemon juice,
lemon zest,
a little bit of water
and a little bit of sugar.
I think berries and, like,
fruit and stuff,
they're, like, really great
snacks to have at the beach.
I'm making a hand pie
because I think those are easy
to put inside of a sandcastle,
and it's also more interesting
than, like, cupcakes or cookies.
I'm gonna make
orange sugar cookies,
and then I'm gonna
cut them out like stars
and make them look
like starfish.
I feel like starfish goes
perfectly with a beach theme.
I know that my sugar cookie
recipe is really good,
and when you think of beach,
you think of, like,
seashells and starfish,
so it's perfect.
For my sugar cookie dough, I'm
gonna cream together butter,
powdered sugar, eggs,
vanilla extract.
For my dry ingredients,
I'm gonna add my flour,
then I'm gonna add in my
orange juice and orange zest.
I don't know what I'm going
to do
for my rice cereal-treat
sandcastle yet,
but I'm gonna
figure it out as I go.
I'm gonna make rice
cereal treats after
because rice cereal treats
are really easy to make.
Duff. Duff.
Duff.
[ Laughs ]
What are you doing?
Chilling in my crib.
Is this
your mobile office?
I like it
in here, you know?
-Yeah.
-Mom, I got to go.
[ Laughing ]
The beach reminds me of fruit
because you get a lot
of fruity drinks on the beach.
So I'm making my sandcastle
out of fruit cereal treats
and my baked item
will be peach cobbler cupcakes.
Let's grease these guys.
I'm spraying the bottom
of my cupcake pans
just so the peach
cobblers don't stick.
Butter.
To make my peach cobbler,
first I get started on melting
my brown sugar
and butter in a pan.
**
ALEX: For my baked good, I'm
going to do, like, a mini tart.
Crust is gonna be,
like, sablé dough,
and then I'm gonna fill it
with a chocolate ganache
and then some raspberries.
I want to make tarts
because I love making tarts.
It's so cute,
elegant and beautiful.
Of course they're delicious.
To make my sablé dough,
I add butter
and then I whip that up.
I add egg yolks and vanilla,
and then on the side,
I have granulated sugar
and confectioners' sugar,
and I mix them together.
There we go.
To my flour, I add
a little bit of salt
because usually a sablé dough
is kind of like sweet and salty.
I like sablé
because it's almost
like a pastry crust.
Oh, it's like heaven.
See how those turn out.
ABBY: Ooh, those are cute.
I am slicing up my peaches
and laying them
into my peach
cobbler cupcakes,
and right as I finish
my last one,
Duff and Valerie
come walking in,
and Duff has a pineapple
in his hands.
Bakers, may we have
your attention, please?
Why?
Just let us bake in peace.
Please no twists,
please, but no.
Beaches are
often tropical.
And one of our favorite
tropical flavors
is pineapple.
So you must use pineapple
in your baked treats.
Pineapple doesn't go with any
of the flavors that I'm using.
Hot, hot, hot.
So I got to just scrap
my chocolate raspberry tart
and think of something else.
Do something cool
with the pineapple.
ABBY: I was so excited to make
these peach cobblers,
and now I have
to use pineapple?
Gross.
So I'm going to have to
totally change plans.
DUFF: 90 minutes left,
bakers!
Cereal-treat sandcastles
filled with
yummy baked goods.
We have to incorporate pineapple
into our beach desserts,
but a pineapple cobbler
sounds disgusting,
so now I'm restarting
with pineapple.
Abby just dumped a muffin
tin into the trash.
Mm-hmm.
When you got 2 hours,
you're trying to make
a sandcastle,
you cannot be
throwing stuff away.
I'm thinking, "What goes
better with pineapple
than a pineapple
upside-down cake?"
Shortening.
To make my pineapple
upside-down cake batter,
I'm combining flour, sugar,
shortening, salt, milk and eggs.
I have to decide between which
type of pineapple I want,
rings or chunks.
I usually use the rings for
my pineapple upside-down cake,
but the rings don't fit
in these cupcake pans,
so I'm just gonna put some
chunks in the bottom of each one
and then a maraschino cherry
right in the middle.
This is the worst twist
and the best twist ever.
Pineapple upside-down cake
is my mom's favorite,
and I know I'm good at it.
Aye, aye, aye.
[ Groans ]
We have to use pineapple
in our dessert.
If I was to use pineapple,
chocolate and raspberry
that would be weird, so I'm
just thinking totally new plan.
But I'm starting to think
I could do something tropical
and do, like,
a piña colada tart.
Now I am making a piña colada
tart with coconut milk,
pastry cream filling
and a pineapple on top.
Luckily, I can still use
my tart shells
because I know tropical,
I think of piña coladas
because usually in Mexico,
whenever I went with my parents,
usually on the beach,
I would sit there
and have a virgin piña colada.
Virgin, virgin piña colada,
not one with alcohol
because I'm too young.
I'd just sit there sipping it,
and I think of tropical flavors.
Look at that beautiful
coconut pastry cream.
I feel I'm a kid trapped
in an adult's body.
Oh, so good.
Oh, no.
I think I'm an adult
trapped in a kid's body.
DUFF: Hi, bakers.
Sandcastles!
Still back here.
Pineapple.
ALEX: Duff can be
ridiculous sometimes,
but sometimes he's
just hilarious as heck.
LINSEY: For my twist, I'm just
going to chop up the pineapple
and put it in the berry filling.
I don't know if pineapple goes
with what I'm making too much,
but right now that's the
only place that it can go.
Can't put it in the crust.
Can't put it in the rice
cereal treat
or else that
would be too soft.
Everything would fall over.
Bryn, how are you planning
on using pineapple?
What?
I'm gonna use my pineapple
by adding it into my royal icing
and into my rice
cereal treats.
Perfect.
To make my rice cereal treats,
I put marshmallows and melt
those down with some butter.
I'm putting in
my pineapple juice
with my marshmallow mixture,
hoping that I'll get
the pineapple flavor
and Duff and Valerie
will be able to taste it.
I'm using the regular
rice cereal
because it's the tan
color like sand.
Do I have enough?
Probably.
I need to work really fast,
so I don't put my pie
crust in the fridge.
I just roll it out, so I'm
noticing they're a little small,
so I roll them out a bit
more to make them bigger
because there's nothing
worse than a hand pie
that's, like, this much filling
and, like, this much dough.
Close up my hand pie
and use a fork to seal it,
and then you also use the fork
to poke holes in the top
so the air inside
doesn't make the thing explode.
You do not want
an exploded hand pie.
BRYN: Abby, how you doing?
-Good, how are you?
-Good.
I am gonna use fruit cereal
to make my cereal treats
because it's like the rainbow,
and that just reminds
me of the beach.
Hello.
-Hello!
How badly do you want to win
"Kids Baking Championship"?
I want to win "Kids Baking
Championship" so badly.
Why?
Because I want money.
If I win, I'm gonna take
my family on a cruise
and go on a headband
shopping spree
because I wear them
all the time,
and they're my
favorite accessory.
I also want to represent
Wisconsin.
What?
I said it just like you.
No. You said...
No.
She's totally
over-exaggerating it.
It's just Wisconsin.
Teach me how to say it.
-Wisconsin.
Wisconsin.
Yeah.
That was better.
-Oh, thank you.
-Yeah.
-Okay. You get going.
-I'm going.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
ABBY: The secret to making
the perfect cereal treat
is having lots of butter
and marshmallows.
I'm going to have to watch
the butter, though,
for this challenge
because I need my cereal treats
to be strong and sturdy,
and if I make them
with too much butter,
then they won't be
able to stand up.
Does anybody have
the rice cereal?
I do.
I get started on my s'mores
rice cereal treat.
For my cereal mixture,
I have 7 1/2 cups
of regular rice cereal
and then 7 1/2 cups
of chocolate rice cereal,
and then 1 cup of
chopped graham crackers
and then 1 cup of semi-sweet
baking chocolate chips.
There we go.
I hope that I can make it
to the finale
because I'm
the last boy standing,
and I am so close
to getting that dog I want.
That little puppy just keeps
coming closer and closer.
Whoa!
Right now I'm cutting out
my starfish cookies,
and then I'm gonna put them
in the oven so they bake.
I'm gonna make my sugar
cookies look like starfish.
Perfect.
Starfish are so cool because you
can break off one of its arms
and it'll grow back.
Going to the oven.
But I wish, like,
starfish cookies,
if you, like, bit into it,
it'd just grow back
and you could keep eating it.
Those look good, Abby.
-Thank goodness.
ABBY: I'm checking on my
upside-down cakes,
and they look like
they're ready,
but them I'm trying to
get them out of the pan
and they are not
coming out at all.
Oh, look what's going on
at Abby's station.
My cakes are kind of
sticking to the pan,
so I have to, like,
pry them out.
This is bad.
It's not how I wanted this
to go.
**
One hour left, bakers!
DUFF: Cereal-treat sandcastles
and baked treats.
Mmm.
Who wants to stay?
Who wants to go home?
ABBY: This is a major
setback for me
because these pineapple
upside-down cupcakes,
they're supposed to be
my key to the finale,
but they are not
my best baked good.
**
LINSEY:
Just need to pour it in.
Let's start with that.
-Chef Linsey.
-Hello.
DUFF: Ooh, what is that?
I'm making a rice cereal treat
with chocolate cereal.
-Awesome.
-That smells so good.
I'm gonna use chocolate
rice cereal for my sandcastle
because I love chocolate.
Who has the cinnamon?
Me.
Thank you.
I'm making a cinnamon-chocolate
rice cereal treat sandcastle
because, you know,
you don't want to make, like,
a regular rice
cereal-treat sandcastle.
That's boring because
I love chocolate.
We've established that.
And also, cinnamon is a nice
flavor to put with chocolate,
and I think it'll kind of
spruce things up a bit.
Man, this thing would be
great for snowball fights.
ALEX: Perfecto.
Now, I'm from Canada, so I have
never made a sandcastle,
but I've made a snowman
and snow forts.
Oh, this smells so good.
I think my rice cereal treats
are gonna stand out
from the others
because I'm doing s'mores.
I'm just gonna spray
a sheet pan,
put some on there
for my walls,
and then I'm gonna have
some more for my molds.
DUFF:
Look what Alex is doing.
That's gonna be
his mold, I think.
Oh, smart.
Okay.
There we go.
This Bundt pan and these molds
is just like what you would use
to make a sandcastle
at the beach,
I think, because I don't really
make sandcastles at all, so...
It takes a lot
of rice cereal treats
to fill this Bundt pan.
It's huge, but you know what?
It's gonna look really good.
ABBY: Bryn, your sugar cookies
look pretty done.
Thank you, Abby.
Next I get started
on my royal icing.
Royal icing is
simply egg whites,
powdered sugar
and cornstarch.
Perfect.
I'm using the pineapple
in my royal icing,
and I'm coloring it yellow
because I like
the color yellow...
Yellow.
...and most starfish are, like,
a yellow-orange color.
I want to be in
the finale so bad.
There's only four of us left,
and my decorating is going
to help me stand out
because it's beautiful
and clean and wonderful.
Bryn, do you ever
make sandcastles on the beach?
Every time we go to the beach,
I always make a sandcastle.
Me, too.
They're, like,
my favorite thing.
ABBY: I had never made a
cereal-treat sandcastle before,
but I love the beach
because Katie and I
are very competitive sisters,
so when we go to the beach,
we have sandcastle competitions,
and our parents are the judges,
but they always say it's a tie
because they don't
want to, like,
have favorites or anything.
VALERIE: No pressure.
You're just baking to
make it to the finale.
That's it.
That's all, no pressure.
DUFF: Yeah. We're not gonna be
critical or anything.
You know what?
Let's not even judge it.
Nah.
I really wish that
my mom and dad
were the judge
of this competition
and not Duff and Valerie.
How are you building
your sandcastle?
I think I'm making mine like
a classic sandcastle because...
-Okay.
-...I love making sandcastles,
and that's usually
the vision I have.
All right.
So, Linsey, how badly do you
want to be in the finale?
I really want to be
in the finale
because, I mean,
you've worked really hard.
You've beat out, like,
thousands of kids
even just to get here,
and then just being
in the finale is,
like, it's unbelievable.
-You really want it?
-Yeah.
Okay. All right.
Well, then, better deliver.
-Okay.
-Good luck.
Thank you.
LINSEY:
I want some for decoration.
If I win, I would save a bunch,
give some to, like, my parents
and then the rest I would spend
probably on a bunch
of baking stuff.
45 minutes left, bakers.
**
Cereal-treat sandcastles
in 45 minutes!
You better start
dumping that, girl.
I'm going!
Sounds like my children.
This is a lot of cereal treats.
"I'm going, Mom."
ABBY: Valerie would be
a really cool mom
because she would
cook delicious dinners
and she's a celebrity,
so I would be
a celebrity's child.
I just have to flatten them.
Flat.
But my mom's cooler.
-Bryn, you okay?
-Yeah.
I always build sandcastles
at the beach.
They're so much fun,
and you can do so many
different things with it.
Two years ago, my dad
and I and my sister,
we made this huge sandcastle,
and it was, like,
3 stories tall,
but Sun's more into tanning now.
She wants to be tan.
Now I just build
sandcastles with my dad.
30 minutes, bakers.
Do I have enough time
to make walls?
I got my molds filled
and cooling,
and I'm thinking,
"Oh, my goodness.
Am I gonna have enough
rice cereal treats
to make the walls
and enough for the judges?"
Linsey, do you have
extra marshmallows?
-Yes.
-I think, "You know what?
I've just got to
start another batch."
I'm doing another quick batch
of these rice cereal treats.
This is to get us to the finale.
I want to have a nice
big castle, big display.
VALERIE: Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa. Whoa.
Alex is making a new batch
of cereal treats.
What is going on?
I need to hustle because
if I don't get this done,
well, bye-bye me.
Another batch, stressful.
**
DUFF:
30 minutes, bakers!
I need to focus, focus.
I think I'm taking a risk
because I'm making
more rice cereal treats.
I'm using the same pot, throwing
in some butter and marshmallows.
I add my cereal,
mix it together.
Boom. I'm done.
There we go.
I think I'm like
Speedy Gonzales right here.
Hopefully these tarts
will turn out.
So after my rice cereal treats,
my second batch is all done.
I'm gonna start
building my tarts.
I think my little tarts look
so good, look like the tropics.
I should see sandcastles
starting to be built.
I should see
walls going up.
I want to see turrets.
VALERIE: Hurry, bakers.
You got to get
these sandcastles made,
and they need to be
beautiful and impressive.
ABBY: Time's running out,
and I need to start assembling
my sandcastle,
like, yesterday.
To build my sandcastle,
I'm taking each of
my sheet-pan walls
so that way, it forms a box.
Abby, how are you doing?
Good.
Not really, actually.
That's a big sandcastle.
Seriously?
[ Sighs ]
I'm definitely starting
to stress...
Does anyone have
the waffle cones?
I do.
...because I'm down
to the wire on time,
and I still have to
assemble my castle.
My sandcastle plan is
to make a regular square,
then take my turrets
and put them on each corner,
and then I'm gonna use
some coating chocolate
to make it as sturdy
as possible.
There's a lot of pressure riding
on this rice cereal castle.
I am so close to the title
of Kids Baking Champion.
I can almost reach it.
If I am the next Kids
Baking Champion,
my business will blow up.
Who doesn't want a birthday cake
from the Kids Baking Champion?
Probably do it like that, right?
Okay.
I start assembling
my sandcastle,
and I take two of my walls,
spread on some
coating chocolate.
All right.
I go with coating chocolate
to hold it all together
because coating
chocolate hardens,
and I think it'll look good.
So, you know, my ancestors
lived in a castle.
-Really?
-So I kind of...
You know, I could live in
a sandcastle because I get it.
I think my ancestors, like,
tilled the ground
around your
ancestors' castle.
Hopefully
they can come out.
I'm ready to get my rice cereal
treats out of these molds.
**
I'm trying to get them out,
but they're just not coming out.
**
Uh-oh.
Oh, my goodness.
Are these gonna come out?
Oh, shoot.
Come on.
So I really bang it,
and then...
* Ahh *
Yes.
Two of them came out.
Phew!
**
ABBY: Crap.
To try and make
the walls more study,
I'm cutting them in half
and then using that
as the wall instead.
Then I'm sticking toothpicks
in each corner
so that way the walls
stay together.
Now I'm thinking to myself,
"Well, this looks
really boring,"
so I'm deciding
to cut a door out,
but when I cut it,
the wall starts to cave in,
and it is a big mess.
LINSEY: Nope.
I think I should reinforce
the walls a bit.
At this point, everything
is just not holding,
and the walls
are way too thin.
This has to be a sandcastle,
not a pile of sand.
What the heck?
Then I realize, "Oh, there's
that cold spray,
that magic cold spray
in the pantry."
Whoa.
So I'm spraying it on, and it's,
like, drying the chocolate.
Whoa!
This is cool.
Why haven't I used this
in the past?
Some magic...
And I feel like a superhero
with that gun,
like, my freeze ray.
10 minutes, bakers,
10 minutes left.
BRYN: I finally have
my castle assembled,
and I have to put
my cookies in there.
Then I'm like,
"This looks way too boring."
So I run over to the pantry and
grab these charcoal rock things.
The charcoal candies are
supposed to be like rocks
around my sandcastle,
and then I put the two
gumdrops on the front
so it looks like bushes.
ABBY: Oh, seriously?
My wall is caving
in really fast,
and my door situation
is not helping
and I need to add
some extra support
so I'm grabbing
some plastic cups
just to help hold up my castle.
I'm ready
to build this thing.
I get my main piece
which is my Bundt.
And then I try to figure out
how I'm gonna build this.
All right.
I grab my tarts, and then
I place them into my castle as,
like, little soldiers
walking into battle.
My tarts are gonna fight
all the other girls'
little treats.
Well, you know what?
Let's not get too mean.
BRYN: Your sandcastle
looks good, Linsey.
Thank you.
DUFF: Looks like Linsey is
brushing the outside
of her castle
with coating chocolate.
It's probably smart,
help keep it together.
Are there
graham crackers?
-I have them.
-Like mortar.
And crushed graham crackers
to make it look
like sand, very smart.
While I'm building
the sandcastle,
it's looking
a little bit boring.
I realize, "Oh, I should
probably use
some graham cracker crust
because that would be cool.
That would help it look
like a sandcastle."
Abby, how you doing?
You okay down there?
ABBY: No.
The cups are not working.
This is terrible!
These walls look like
an elephant stomped on them.
I'm frantically replacing
the one caving-in wall.
Seriously?
Things are not looking
pretty right now.
90 seconds, bakers.
BRYN:
I'm looking at my sandcastle,
and it's definitely not
the prettiest thing you'll see.
You can definitely see a lot
of my coating chocolate,
but I'd rather see
the coating chocolate
than not have
a castle at all.
Bakers, remember, your stuff
has to hold together.
**
[ Gasps ]
I'm freaking out right now,
and I just see it fall apart,
and it's just so sad to see your
masterpiece go crumbling down.
This thing can't fall.
That's the whole challenge.
I'm holding it together
until they call time,
and I'm just gonna
hope that it stays.
ABBY: I'm deciding to take off
the wall with the door on it
because it is caving in.
Now I'm adding an arch
so it looks a little better.
DUFF AND VALERIE:
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
DUFF: Hands up.
**
Surf's up, dude,
beach day.
Yeah.
Cereal-treat sandcastles.
Filled with goodies.
Hey, Abby.
Come on in.
ABBY: There's a lot of pressure
on me today
because I really want
to make it to the finale,
but I don't know
if this is good enough.
Hi.
What's going on?
Um, it's kind of tippy,
but it's a rainbow.
Yeah.
I like your choice
of cereal treats.
Thank you.
So tell us what you made
for us today.
I made a pineapple
upside-down cupcake
with a fruit
cereal-treat sandcastle.
What happened
with your arch?
It fell in.
Yeah.
The arch is tough.
Your walls are really high,
and that's cool,
but I think that might
have contributed to this.
You know?
You know what might
have helped, too,
is in real castles,
when the walls go up,
they all have a base
to them.
Yeah.
But I noticed you did use
some toothpicks
to try
and keep it together.
-Yeah.
-All right.
So your castle,
it's a little funky.
-It's a little wonky.
-Let's taste the wall.
-Mmm.
I forgot how much
I love fruit cereal.
Fruit cereal is a really
nice choice
because
it's really colorful.
I love the way
this stuff tastes.
I love that you made pineapple
upside-down cakes.
Let's taste it.
-All right.
It looks like you had
a little trouble
getting these out
of the pan.
Yes.
I hoped
he wouldn't notice that.
Mmm.
It's moist,
sweet, pineapple-y.
It's a really delicious
pineapple upside-down cake.
Yeah. Abby,
your cake is really good.
Getting a lot of
pineapple flavor.
Man, I just wish
that it came out
of the pan clean, you know,
because that's just
such a great look.
Yeah.
-Thank you.
Thanks, Abby.
I loved her cake,
absolutely loved her cake,
but her castle didn't quite
turn out how she had hoped.
I think here she was
just too ambitious,
but the cake
was delicious.
Yeah.
Alex.
Hello.
Hi, Alex.
Well, tell us
about your castle.
So my castle is actually
a s'mores-rice-cereal-
treat castle,
and then the baked item is
actually a piña colada tart.
These are adorable.
I just want to cut it open
to see how deep.
I would have liked to have
seen a little bit
more
of that pastry cream.
There's a lot
of crust in there.
Okay.
But the flavor itself,
you really nailed it.
Good coconut flavor,
it's in there,
and the pineapple
is in there, too.
Okay.
I do love that crust.
It falls apart like a really
great sandy cookie.
Okay.
Tell me about, like,
the design
of your castle here.
Like,
what goes on in here?
The soldiers go in
through that doorway,
and then they all meet up
in that big little
volcano-looking thing,
that Bundt, and then
they have their meetings,
and then they go to battle here
and there with all
the other castles.
Okay.
You're definitely planning
on some sort of siege.
Well, isn't that what
castles are all about?
Yeah.
Protection.
I love that
you used a Bundt pan
to make the big
soldier-gathering place.
It just is a really interesting,
fun-looking castle.
Let's taste it.
**
Do you know what
a third-party manufacturer is?
I do not speak French.
I don't know.
We need to call
a third-party manufacturer
and have them start making
these and selling them
in stores
because they're amazing.
-Oh, really?
-Amazing.
-It's delicious. Yeah.
-Thank you.
-It's...
-S'mores.
...s'mores
in a cereal treat.
Well done, you.
-Thank you.
Booyah.
Yeah.
-Thanks, Alex.
Okay. Thank you.
Like, I knew this was
gonna be delicious
because I picked up
this little thing,
and it's, like, 3 pounds.
Yeah.
It's really tasty.
**
It looks like there's
a vampire or a werewolf
in there that's
waiting to get me.
Let's bring in Linsey.
-Yeah.
-Hey, Linsey.
This is the last round
until the finale,
and I just really want
to get through it.
How's it going, Chef?
Pretty good.
Tell us about your day
and your castle.
So for my castle,
I made a cinnamon
and chocolate rice cereal treat.
I tried to cover my castle
with graham cracker crumbs
to kind of make it
look more like sand.
Hmm.
Okay.
I like the graham crackers
on the outside,
and it's holding
together really well.
All right.
Let's taste your treat.
I can smell the cinnamon.
I'm very excited about this.
**
This starts off so good,
but as the cinnamon
builds,
maybe you're a little
heavy-handed on the cinnamon.
Okay.
I have a problem with adding
too much cinnamon.
You can do less cinnamon,
and it would be really good,
and you could also keep it
just the way it is,
and it's still
really good.
You know what I mean?
-Okay.
And what is your treat
that you baked?
It looks like an empanada.
My treat is a mixed berry
and pineapple hand pie.
-Oh.
-Hand pie.
See, with all those
berries in there,
I hope we can taste
that pineapple,
but this looks really...
I mean, you know?
It's beautiful.
If I got that
at a restaurant,
I'd be totally fine
with that.
Yeah.
That...That's a really
big accomplishment
because restaurants,
I mean, their sole purpose
is, like, cooking
and baking and stuff.
Let's taste this pie.
You know, you got a good ratio
of pie crust to filling.
Right off the bat,
I got my pineapple.
One small, tiny little
problem, though --
I would have liked it
a little bit sweeter.
More sugar.
It's the "Kids
Baking Championship."
Don't ever,
ever skimp on sugar.
Okay.
This is the only place
I allow myself to eat sugar...
-Right. Right.
-...is on this show.
Thanks, Linsey.
-Thank you.
This concerns me, like,
just pineapple on top
of a cereal treat.
Yeah.
I believe she put it in,
but I'm not sure.
Oh, okay.
And that's just, like,
a garnish maybe?
-Maybe.
-Okay.
-Want to talk to Bryn?
-I so want to talk to Bryn.
All right.
Hey, Bryn.
-Hi.
Tell us how it went today.
Not too, too well,
but I got something
on the platter.
[ Laughs ]
You did.
I wanted to make it look
like a real sandcastle,
so I used just
the regular cereal treat
so it has the tan color.
Well, I like
the landscaping.
-Okay.
-I think it's neat.
It looks like you put a lot
of chocolate on there.
It was just to try to keep it
from falling and tumbling.
Got you.
That can be a little neater.
That's one thing I know.
Decorating is my thing,
and it's in front of them,
and it looks like poop.
It's unfortunate
that you've got
three fairly good turrets,
and then the one,
it just keeps tipping over,
and if you had
evened out the walls,
it would have made all
the difference in the world.
Now, is there pineapple
in here?
There's pineapple juice.
There's pineapple juice in.
Okay.
This is
a good cereal treat.
I purposely didn't take
any of the pineapple
from the top
to see
if I tasted any pineapple
in the actual treat,
and I really don't.
I don't taste any
pineapple either,
and I think you needed
to smash these down
a little bit more.
I know
you weigh 30 pounds,
but, you know, you put
a little weight on them,
and then they'll be able
to hold themselves up
a little bit more.
Tell us
about your cookie.
My cookie is an orange
and pineapple sugar cookie.
Oh, so you're making, like,
starfish cookies.
-Yeah.
-That's clever.
You know, the cookies
look good in there.
I like the idea
that you were going for.
I'm getting orange
all day long.
I do not get
any pineapple.
I like the crunchiness
with the nonpareils on top.
It's a good sugar cookie.
I just don't taste
any pineapple.
I got the orange flavor,
but there's no pineapple,
but, yeah.
It's a good cookie.
-Thank you.
-Yeah. You're welcome.
-Thanks, Bryn.
-Thank you.
Not Bryn's best work.
**
DUFF: The "Kids Baking
Championship" winner
will receive
a sweet prize package
that includes a feature story
in "Food Network Magazine"...
-Yes.
-...and...
$25,000.
[ Cheering ]
**
Val, this is rough.
Yeah.
We have to decide
which three bakers are
going to the finale.
I need to get this
in the oven.
There was a couple bakers
that really attempted
some more challenging
baked items.
Hopefully these tarts
will turn out.
Alex's tart was a much
more sophisticated
undertaking than
some of the other bakers.
Mm-hmm.
You know,
he made a little tart.
He used the sablé dough.
I'm pretty impressed
with Alex this week.
I think my little tarts
look so good.
Look like the tropics.
You know, I feel like Alex
has really knuckled down.
He's focused, and he's really
expanded a little bit,
and he's really
sort of shown
that he's not
a one-dimensional baker.
Alex's wall was out
of this world, man.
So good.
You also liked
Linsey's castle wall.
Mm-hmm.
You know, Linsey has
really shown today
that that girl can bake.
Yeah.
I mean, look.
That was
a beautiful hand pie.
I think
she forgot the sugar.
-Yeah.
-Just got to get these on.
And she is a good
little architect.
That was
a fun little castle.
It had character.
Didn't look like
a sandcastle to me.
It looked like a castle
that had been abandoned
150 years ago
in the hills of
Italy somewhere.
-Filled with pies.
-Filled with pies...
-Yeah.
-...as it should be.
BRYN: Make this baby sturdy.
Let's talk about Bryn.
Oh, you know,
Bryn's castle,
every wall was
a different size.
The turrets,
one was falling down.
The one redeeming thing
about Bryn's castle
was the fun rocks
she put all around it
with her landscaping.
And I got to wonder
where Bryn's time went
because her baked item
was very simple,
and weren't we supposed
to get pineapple?
Yeah.
I didn't get any.
This is gonna be amazing.
In 2 hours,
everybody did something.
You know,
they'd flavored something.
I feel like Bryn
did the bare minimum.
I will say that Bryn managed
to get four walls up,
and Abby did not,
and her arch fell over.
Abby and her great
collapsing castle, you know,
she only had two turrets,
and one of the walls
was just, you know,
ready to go.
And that was a really
disappointing castle.
You know what I was
really disappointed in?
She stacked up all of her
pineapple upside-down cakes
one on top of the other.
That's not how
you serve those.
So only three of these bakers
are gonna get to go
to the finale next week.
-Ay-yi-yi.
-I think the question is,
which bakers had
the least flaws today?
We got to make
that decision.
**
Bakers, you gave us
a heck of a Beach Day,
but there was only
one baker that delivered
on both design
and flavor.
Alex.
-Oh, really?
-Nice job, Alex.
Really.
Yes.
Your s'mores sandcastle
was cleverly designed
and really good,
and the sablé crust
on your piña colada tarts,
crispy, buttery
and delicious.
Thank you.
I'm serious, man.
You should package
and sell those walls.
-Really? Maybe I should.
-Seriously.
Maybe I will.
Talk to me after.
I got a guy.
Congratulations, Alex.
We will see you
in the finale.
I am in the finale, last boy
standing in the finale,
first Canadian in the finale.
Feels really good.
-Good job.
-Thank you.
Now that leaves Abby,
Bryn and Linsey.
Please step forward.
Today was all about earning
a spot in the finale.
Unfortunately, each one
of you did have issues.
ABBY: It is very nerve-racking
to know
that any one of us
could go home
because we are
all amazing bakers
and have become best friends.
Abby, the walls of your
fruit-cereal castle
were too high,
and that left them
leaning really badly,
and your little pineapple
upside-down cakes,
although they tasted good,
they were torn up from
sticking to the pan.
Bryn...
you made a really decent
simple sugar cookie
and an uneven,
wobbly castle.
We didn't taste pineapple
in your cookie,
and using it as a garnish
on your cereal treat
really didn't work
for us.
Linsey, your castle was
rather dark
and foreboding.
We liked the graham-cracker
sand idea,
but your berry-pineapple
hand pies
were definitely
not sweet enough.
Each and every one of you
are incredibly
gifted bakers,
and you've become part
of our "Kids Baking" family.
But unfortunately, the baker
leaving us today is...
**
...Bryn.
I'm sorry.
Bryn, you're the best.
You are
the sweetest, Bryn.
I don't like it.
-Yeah.
**
I'm really proud of myself
that I made it this far.
Good luck.
We all have bad days sometimes,
but if I see
a sandcastle standing,
I'm gonna kick it over.
Bakers, you are
in the finale.
-Yes.
-Guys, we did it.
Booyah.
ABBY: Finale!
VALERIE: Previously on
"Kids Baking Championship"...
Cereal treat sand castles
filled with yummy baked goods.
With pineapple in it.
Your stuff has to
hold together.
Did not get an pineapple.
-It's...
-S'mores.
S'mores in a cereal treat.
-Well done, you.
-Thank you.
There was only one baker
that delivered
on both design and flavor.
Alex.
The baker leaving us
today is...
...Bryn.
**
DUFF: They have no idea what
they're about to get into.
They're gonna love
this challenge.
-Yeah.
-They're gonna love it.
**
-What the heck?
-Oh, my goodness.
-Wow!
-That's so many balloons.
I am in the finale,
and this is, like,
the greatest thing
that's ever happened to me.
This is the most balloons
I've seen in one place.
-I just want to pop them all.
-Exactly.
-Hi.
Welcome to the finale.
Whoo!
Finale!
Woot, woot!
I can't believe it.
You have baked your hearts
out for nine weeks,
and it definitely feels like
it's time to celebrate.
-Mm-hmm.
-Yes.
But this celebration
is not for you.
-Mm.
-Oh, okay.
Guess whose
birthday it is, bakers?
Food Network?
**
"Food Network Magazine."
-Oh!
-Really?
"Food Network Magazine"
is 10 years old,
a decade of greatness,
and guess who gets to
make the birthday cake?
-[ Gasps ]
-You.
-Aw.
No pressure, but the winning
cake must be good enough
to represent a magazine
with nearly
14 million readers.
Holy smokes.
Minds blown.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, and by the way, the cake
itself is worth $25,000
and the title of
Kids Baking Champion.
Oh, my gosh.
I can probably get, like,
100 dogs with $25,000,
but I only want one.
We are giving you five hours to
create birthday cake magic --
-Oh, my goodness.
-Okay, okay, okay.
...and we want your cakes
illustrate the color
and richness
of "Food Network Magazine."
Okay.
By the end of today,
one of you will be
the Kids Baking Champion.
-Oh, my god.
One of us, guys.
All right, bakers.
Your baking time starts...
...now!
-Now!
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
**
I need cinnamon.
I am in the finale,
so I am going to bring it today.
I'm making an ultimate
pumpkin spice cake.
I really wanna wow the judges
with sophisticated flavor,
and I think pumpkin spice cake
with an orange cream cheese
frosting is pretty darn good.
I'm thinking of a whole
bunch of colors.
Then, probably on the top,
I'm gonna put,
"Happy 10th birthday,
'Food Network Magazine.'"
To get my cake started,
I pour in butter in the mixer,
and I take some granulated
sugar and brown sugar,
put in my pumpkin purée.
I mix a lot of eggs
and a lot of milk.
For my dry mixture,
I have flour, baking powder,
baking soda, and salt.
Okay. Now my spices.
I add all my spices
to my dry mixture.
I have ground cinnamon,
ground cloves,
ground allspice, ground nutmeg,
and ground ginger.
There's a lot of spices in this.
No wonder it's called
pumpkin spice.
I alternate between my dry
mixture and my wet mixture.
I don't want to put
all my wet mixture,
or my butter will curdle.
If I was to put
all my dry mixture,
it just won't be
the right texture.
Mm. That smells so good.
Abby, what are you making?
I'm making a vanilla bean cake
with strawberry buttercream
and lime buttercream.
Ooh, that sounds delicious.
First, I'm getting started
on my vanilla bean cake batter.
That's a lot of butter.
I'm quadrupling my cake recipe
because my cake is going to be
two tiers tall.
First tier is going
to be fondant
and the second tier, sprinkles.
Instead of adding
vanilla extract,
I'm going to add in vanilla
beans to my cake batter
because vanilla beans
are very expensive,
and my mom doesn't like
to buy them for me,
so I want to use
as many as I can.
I'm making way too much batter
to fit in this bowl,
so I've dumped it
into another bowl
so I can just mix it by hand
and hopefully get
everything incorporated.
-That is one full bowl.
-Uh-huh.
Abby, what is that?
Cake batter.
So you're making just
a little, tiny cake?
-Yep.
-[ Chuckles ]
No, it's gonna be big.
This bowl still isn't
quite big enough.
This calls for
the jumbo metal bowl.
This'll work.
**
Four.
Linsey, what kind of cake
are you making?
I'm making a chocolate cake,
and I'm going to have, like,
a coconut filling
and raspberry buttercream.
-Oh, that sounds good.
-Okay.
This is the one challenge
where we get to make
whatever flavor cake we want,
and I love chocolate.
It's my favorite thing
in the entire world,
and now I get to make
a chocolate cake,
and I also think that
coconut and raspberry
are two flavors that go well
together and with chocolate.
I'm gonna make
a dark chocolate cake
with a marble fondant,
and, just,
I'm making it two tiers.
To make my chocolate cake,
I use oil instead of butter
because it will keep
the cake moist,
and I add in some
coffee extract
because coffee helps bring out
the flavor of chocolate,
and I want this chocolate cake
to be the most chocolaty cake
that there is out there.
Bring out the flavor
of the chocolate because,
dude, this cake
needs to be so perfect
that it's worth $25,000.
I have made this cake
so many times before,
and I love making it,
and I love eating it, too.
Well, chocolate
comes from a tree,
so technically it's,
like, a vegetable.
-Hi, Linsey.
-Hi.
Have you always loved
decorating cakes?
Because I've noticed you've got
quite a skill for decorating.
I love decorating cakes.
I don't make them too often
because my mom doesn't like
when we have, like,
so much cake in the house.
[ Laughs ] I get it. I get
your mom. I can tell, yeah.
Yeah.
All right, well, I'm really
excited to see your cake.
Thank you.
I really don't want there
to be giant air pockets
or air bubbles in the cake,
so I bang it on the counter
in order to bring all
those air bubbles up
so they kind of
just go up and pop.
**
[ Laughs ]
I'm too small to transport
my cakes by myself.
Yeah, because you had,
like, so many layers.
Yeah.
45 minutes have gone by.
You have 4 hours
and 15 minutes left.
Whoo. This is a lot of cake, eh?
[ Laughs ]
My cakes are baking, so
I'm gonna start on my frosting.
Alex, what are you making now?
My orange cream cheese frosting.
I need a lot of cream cheese.
I take my cream cheese
and butter, cream it together.
I add a lot of powdered sugar.
**
Powdered sugar
right in my face.
Got my nostrils. Ugh.
I'm putting a little bit
of heavy cream
because I need to thin
it out a little bit,
and then I zest some orange,
add some orange extract.
Not too much 'cause, yeah,
I don't want it to be
overpowering.
That's silky.
My silky, smooth,
pillowy heaven in a bowl.
We have to make, like,
pounds and pounds
and pounds of buttercream.
I know. It's crazy.
Now it's time to start
my raspberry buttercream.
Just going to sift everything,
and this is gonna take a while.
Then I start sifting my sugar
'cause I don't want any lumps.
So much powdered sugar
everywhere.
[ Groans ]
This is taking such a long time,
but I cannot give the judges
lumpy buttercream.
That's just not gonna
happen in the finale.
[ Groans ]
Okay.
I finally get done sifting my
sugar, so I add it to my butter.
Then, instead of adding milk,
I add raspberry purée
because I want it
to taste like raspberry.
I'm gonna add some lemon
for tartness.
I decide to add a little bit
of tartness,
so I put in lemon zest
and a little bit of lemon juice.
Abby, what would you do
if you won the $25,000?
I would take my family
on a cruise.
Wow.
If I win the cash prize,
I'm gonna take
my family on a cruise
because we went
on one in 2015,
and it was amazing,
and I want to go on another one.
I'm making three different
kinds of buttercream.
I add shortening because
it makes it super stable.
To make my buttercream
strawberry,
I need to add
in strawberries.
**
It doesn't look right.
My buttercream is looking
really curdled.
I think I added in
the strawberries too early
before the powdered sugar
was mixed with the butter.
This is a big problem.
**
VALERIE: Birthday cakes for
"Food Network Magazine"'s
10th birthday.
$25,000 and the title of
Kids Baking Champion
rest on this cake.
My buttercream is
looking really curdled.
I cannot serve the judges
curdled buttercream.
There is no way to save this,
so I have to make a whole
new batch of buttercream now.
How you doing, Abby?
Uh, I could be doing better.
I'm going to fix this
strawberry buttercream
by making sure that
my powdered sugar and butter
and shortening are
all fully combined
before I add
in the strawberries.
**
It's looking really good
the second time around.
Perfect.
I'm also going to make lime
buttercream with lime juice,
and I'm going to add in some
green and yellow food coloring
to give it the nice lime color.
Now I'm making a vanilla
buttercream
for frosting
the outside of my cakes
and putting fondant on top of.
I don't want to add vanilla
bean because for decorating,
I don't really want
black dots in my buttercream,
so I add extract.
**
Oh, that's my cakes.
Now, I'm probably gonna see
if I can make something --
I don't know.
It's the finale.
This has to be the best thing
I have ever made
in my whole life.
What else could I do other
than cream cheese frosting
and a cake?
Maybe pastry cream, I'll do,
like, some crème pâtissière.
Pastry cream
or crème pâtissière,
whatever you want to call it.
I'm currently working on
orange spice pastry cream
that I'm gonna fill
the middle of my cakes with.
I heat up some milk with some
cornstarch and orange extract,
just a little bit, not too much,
because I don't want it
to overpower all those spices.
I start to temper my eggs
and my sugar.
I'm whisking like crazy
because I don't want
to get scrambled eggs.
Ah. That's quite the workout.
Okay.
Pastry cream is all thickened,
and then I add ginger, cinnamon,
cloves, nutmeg...
An 1/8th of a teaspoon.
...allspice, cardamom
and apple pie spice.
That's seven spices,
so the judges better like it.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Alex, what would you do
if you won the $25,000?
I think I'll probably buy
a stand mixer and get a dog,
like, in the future.
Yeah, I would buy a dog, too.
Yeah.
I think I'll get a beagle.
I don't think beagles
will be very happy
with the winters in Canada,
but I know they're
gonna love me.
I'd get a Maltese.
I'm, like, allergic
to most dogs --
Oh.
...and I'm not allergic
to that one at all.
So I need to start making
my coconut filling.
I take some coconut milk,
sweetened condensed milk,
and a little bit
of cream of coconut,
and I've got my coconut filling.
Ooh, that is coconut-y
to the max.
**
Oh, that was so satisfying.
I take my cake leveler
and level my cakes.
Actually, that's a good height.
I need to level them because
they'll be easier
to stack that way,
and I'll just have cleaner,
straight, even layers.
Please be baked okay.
Yes. Oh.
This is the most satisfying
thing in the world.
Peeling the parchment
paper off...
Oh, that was so satisfying.
...is, like, the best.
I poke holes in the cake,
and then I brush
on the coconut filling.
**
All right.
Let me get a turntable.
Now I have to start
assembling my cake.
I put on a thin layer
of raspberry buttercream.
I repeat that
for all the layers,
and then I crumb coat and chill.
I assemble my bottom tier
of four layers
and then my top tier
of three layers.
Hey, our faces should be
on this cover.
There.
Now it's a proper
"Food Network Magazine" cover.
**
My cakes are all leveled,
and they look amazing.
I have never made a cake
that has to be worth $25,000.
I made a cake for my library,
but that was just
for a $15 gift card.
Alex, how many layers
are you making your cake?
I'm making my cake
actually two tiers
and three layers in between.
That's what I'm doing, too.
I was gonna do four layers,
but I want to be
able to carry it,
and if it was four, I think
it would be too heavy.
Oh, okay.
I'm taking one layer
of vanilla cake
and then piping
strawberry buttercream,
and then I'm taking another
layer of vanilla cake
and piping lime buttercream
in the middle.
**
Okay. Let's put you in
the blast chiller.
I wanna make sure that I put
enough buttercream
in between the layers
because it tastes super good
with a lot of buttercream.
2 1/2 hours, bakers.
Trim it a little bit,
not too much or else my layers
are gonna be way too thin.
I'm starting to trim my cakes
to make them flat,
but they are a little too thin,
so I can't trim them too much.
Next, I need to soak
my cakes in simple syrup,
so I just combine equal
parts water and sugar.
Put that on the stove
until all the sugar dissolves,
spreading it all over the cake,
and then it will
be nice and moist.
Holy smokes.
I take one layer of
the pumpkin spice cake,
and then I get
my spice pastry cream,
put it in the middle.
As I'm stacking my cake,
it's kind of wobbling around.
Oh.
But it's too late now,
so I'm just jamming
frosting inside.
I was hoping maybe it would kind
of stabilize it a little bit.
Holy smokes.
This is just a disaster.
It's leaning.
The frosting is melting
a little bit,
and it looks like
it's gonna fall over.
It's not very good.
This is not what I want
to present
Duff and Valerie
for the finale.
**
Two hours left, bakers.
Birthday cakes for
"Food Network Magazine"'s
10th birthday.
This is the finale, guys.
You got to make
these cakes amazing.
It's the Leaning Tower of Pisa.
Oh, my god.
Two hours left, I'm trying to
fix this leaning tower of cake.
Leaning Tower of Pisa,
that's what I got.
I get my bench scraper.
I'm trying to get it straight.
I think this is as straight
as I could get it now.
I'm gonna put it
in the blast chiller.
I really, really hope
it stays together.
**
This cake is supposed
to represent
"Food Network Magazine"'s
birthday.
What better thing to do than put
Food Network logo on the cake?
I should just make
the Food Network logo.
Cut a circle out of some
rolled out red fondant.
Then, with a toothpick,
I use the magazine
in the front to kind of make
the Food Network letters,
and I cut them out,
place them onto the red,
and using an edible marker,
I write the word
network underneath.
It's looks really good.
Like, this logo came out so much
better than I thought it would.
**
I wonder if we can do,
like, a ball pit.
Turn the camera sideways.
[ Laughs ]
**
I love this awesome balloon wall
that is in the kitchen,
and I want my first tier
to be just like that,
so I'm going to cover it in
fondant and put fondant dots on.
To make the dots for
the bottom layer of my cake,
I want to use all
the colors of the rainbow
and three different
size cookie cutters
so that way I can have different
size dots just like the wall.
Baby blue.
Gosh, 10 is such an important
number, double digits.
[ Gasps ]
Bakers, can we have
your attention, please?
Oh, god.
You must also make
an edible standing
number 10 cake topper --
I just...
...for "Food Network Magazine"'s
10th birthday cake.
Why now?
Will your 10 be a 10?
-Oh.
-Oh, see what I did there?
[ Laughs ]
Oh.
The Food Network logo
was already gonna be
my cake topper,
so I cut out a one and a zero
on some white fondant,
and I use some water to stick
the fondant on the back.
Linsey, what are you doing
for your edible 10?
I was making this
Food Network logo,
so I just put it
on the back.
Oh, that's cool.
I still have a lot
of decorating,
so I'm just going to make
a 10 out of fondant.
I'm rolling out my fondant
super thick
so that way my 10 will stand up
on the top of my cake.
I have some leftover dots,
so I'm gonna put them
on my number 10
so they will match all
throughout the cake.
You are the best kid
bakers in America
and possibly Canada.
-Yeah.
-Let's just say North America.
-Yeah. [ Laughs ]
Shout out to our
Canadian friends.
I love Canada.
I do, too.
I put the second layer of
the buttercream on my cakes,
ready for the fondant.
All together.
I really want all the colors
on the cake
because "Food Network Magazine"
is very colorful,
so I figure
the best way to do that
is to marble my fondant.
To marble fondant, you need
to roll out tubes
of each of your colors.
You stick them all together
and twirl them.
Roll it into a ball and knead
it to must it all together.
Then, I put it in the sheeter.
[ Gasps] Love the marbling
fondant thing
that Linsey is doing.
You got to be careful
when you're marbling fondant.
-You don't want to overdo it.
-Mm-hmm.
If you overdo it,
it just turns kind of gray.
Yeah.
I think that this
marbled fondant
will really impress the judges.
Oh, it's not big enough.
The sides are not
big enough at all,
but I can't remix it
and reroll it
because then the fondant
is just going to turn,
like, a muddy brown-gray.
I'm just gonna have
to make do with this.
It's a little bit messy
and kind of ripping,
but it's the best
I got right now,
and it covers the entire cake.
Don't freak out.
Cover up my top tier
and smooth everything out.
It's not like this cake
will determine --
Oh, well, it does.
So I roll out a piece of white
fondant and wrap it around.
And make a bow with some white
fondant, place it on,
and it looks like
a nice little present.
I'll just put a border
around the bottom.
On a scale of 1 to 10,
what's your stress level?
Mm, five.
-Five?
-Yeah.
Five?
Mine's, like, a seven,
and I'm just standing here.
-[ Laughs ]
Scared as heck.
I'm trying to cover
a 10-inch cake.
That needs a lot of fondant,
so I'm taking about
four bags of fondant.
I have to literally put almost
all my weight onto this fondant
just so it rolls out.
I need more strength.
This stuff is so hard.
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
...fondant rolled out.
I have passed nine weeks of big
bakes to get to the finale.
I am not gonna give
up this time.
Come on.
Oh, maybe I might just --
Maybe I got it.
I know it's not perfect,
but I just have to roll with it.
With the holes,
I'm just gonna cover them
in these little
red polka dots,
and then I'm thinking
I'm just gonna do, like,
a little ribbon
to represent, like, a gift.
I put my red polka
dots on there,
and I think it looks
pretty good.
My 6-inch fondant is coming out
so much better than my 10-inch
because it's a smaller cake.
It's easier to cover it.
I need to cover this cardboard
because Duff does not
like cardboard.
Who would love cardboard?
I don't know.
I have to get this done
'cause I still have to make
that number 10 cake topper.
I just need to cover that first.
Now that my dots are all
on my first tier,
it's time to get started
on my second tier.
I'm going to roll it
in sprinkles.
I'm adding a lot of frosting
so that way,
when I roll it in sprinkles,
they'll have plenty
of room to stick.
That's an amazing method
that Abby's got right there.
Yeah, it's a cool technique
because, you know,
you got a cake
with no decoration on it.
Ten seconds later, you have
a cake that looks amazing.
Yeah.
**
Boom.
Well, that was fun.
Abby, what are you
using for your 10?
Fondant.
I'm doing rice cereal treats.
I know the other two girls
are doing fondant, like,
just fondant,
and they said edible,
so I'm thinking
rice cereal treats.
I'd like something a little
bit more edible
as opposed to just fondant.
-For the 10?
But, you know,
in the world of cakes,
you don't care about what
the topper tastes like.
Right.
You want to make sure
it really holds up well.
-And really looks good.
-Yeah.
I dip my one and zero
in the white chocolate
and then kind of like almost
bread it in my sprinkles.
I put them in the blast
chiller for a little bit
so that white chocolate
can kind of solidify.
15 minutes left, bakers.
What can you do to make
your cake really stand out?
Well, it's "Food Network
Magazine"'s birthday.
Usually, on a birthday cake,
there's candles.
I'm gonna make 10 candles.
So I'm going to make candles.
This will also be a candle.
You need 10 candles 'cause
it's the 10th birthday.
I'm going to pipe a border.
Let's get a tip.
10 minutes, guys.
Ooh, this is going to be
a good little showdown.
It's very close.
I'm piping a buttercream border
because it will draw
the whole cake together,
and also it will cover up
the seams where the cakes meet.
Mm...
Something just doesn't
look finished about it.
Glitter is awesome because
it makes everything sparkly,
and some little pearl
sprinkles are super cute
and would add the perfect
detail to my birthday cake.
Six minutes, bakers,
$25,000 cake.
What are you doing, Linsey?
I'm just making another little
10 on the front of the cake.
I want to have one in the front.
**
Okay, these are stuck.
So I'm trying to pull off
my one and my zero
off the cooling rack,
but they are really frozen.
Oh. Oh.
Trying to get my one off
and it just broke in half.
-Four minutes.
-Oh, jeez.
Why is this happening to me?
I'm not gonna finish.
I don't think I will.
I have some extra, so I quickly
whip up another one.
I take my zero off,
and I need to be
really delicate.
Oh, my god. I got it. Yes!
I got it off.
There we go, mister zero.
I realize that I should put
"happy birthday" on here,
so I grab a red edible,
edible, marker,
and then I write,
"Happy birthday."
Two minutes, two minutes.
**
Alex, get that one
on top of your cake.
Holy smokes.
On the cake,
there's only a zero.
It's not the birth of
"Food Network Magazine."
It's the 10th birthday,
so I need to get a one done.
This is gonna work.
30 seconds.
This is exciting.
-It's like watching tennis.
-I know.
**
DUFF AND VALERIE: 10, 9, 8,
7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1...
There we go.
Hands up.
Season four is in the books.
-Whoo.
-Who's it gonna be?
Okay.
I got the one on there.
**
I'm feeling pretty
confident in my cake.
Wow.
I think that the judges
are going to like how it looks,
and I hope that they like
how it tastes
and that they pick me
as the Kids Baking Champion.
10th birthday cakes
for "Food Network Magazine."
I love this challenge.
Abby, come on in.
Look at that ponytail swing.
Someone's feeling good.
[ Chuckles ]
-[ Laughs ]
So, Abby, tell us about
your experience here
at "Kids Baking Championship."
I had a super fantastic time.
[ Laughs ] Awesome, awesome.
Tell us about your cake.
I wanted my cake to be rainbow
because that reminds me
of birthdays and parties,
and the balloon wall
was super awesome,
and I wanted my cake
to kind of look like that.
Cool.
Tell us about your number 10.
How did you make that?
My number 10 is made
out of fondant.
-Just straight fondant?
-Yep.
-Technically, it's edible.
-Yeah.
Abby,
that cake is spectacular.
Anybody having a 10th
birthday would love
to have that cake
in front of them.
I love that you chose two
different looks for each tier
and your rosettes
all the way around,
each having a little
pearl inside to show
that they're all
these little flowers.
It was so meticulous.
I can tell you really put
a lot of thought into this.
I'm absolutely blown
away by this cake.
I think the technique
of rolling the cake
in the sprinkles
was really good.
You know, it's nice and even.
I think your fondant is really
clean, and I love the glitter.
I put glitter on everything.
I'd put it on my steak
if they let me.
[ Laughs ]
Let's taste it.
It is a vanilla bean cake
with lime buttercream,
strawberry buttercream,
and the outside is frosted
in vanilla buttercream.
-Wow.
-Mm.
That's lots of
buttercream, huh?
Yep.
That's, like, a one-to-one
buttercream-to-cake ratio.
It's a lot.
**
Mm.
-Lime-y.
Very lime-y. I like that.
That buttercream is lime-y,
and that other buttercream
is strawberry-y,
and your cake is vanillla-y,
and it's all really
good, big flavors.
It's definitely a bit dry.
It's not, like, super dry.
It's not like, "Oh, god, I feel
like I'm eating a cracker,"
but it could definitely
be a little more moist.
Don't be afraid
to soak your cakes.
Some syrup in there, it really
makes a big difference.
It's really
disappointing because
it's such a gorgeous cake,
and the buttercream
is so flavorful,
and the cake is just
a little on the dry side.
It would have been perfect
had the cake been moist.
-Thank you very much, Abby.
-Thank you.
Thanks, Abby.
Everything about that cake
is just so fun,
but it's disappointing.
That cake is dry.
**
Hmm.
My presentation's not the best,
but I heard the both the judges
love pumpkin spice cake,
so I think taste is on fleek.
Alex.
That was a good determined
walk right there.
-Yeah.
-I liked it.
So, Alex, tell us
about your cake.
My cake is inspired
by "Food Network Magazine."
I have a whole bunch
of colors on there
because if you look at the cover
of "Food Network Magazine,"
you see a whole
bunch of colors.
How cool would it be
if you got your own spread
in "Food Network Magazine"?
Oh, my goodness.
That would be crazy.
It would be cool, right?
What would you tell
"Food Network Magazine"
about Alex?
I would say that I was
the first Canadian
on "Kids Baking Championship,"
and first Canadian
as the winner would be
just a whole different --
It would be amazing.
Well, listen, Alex,
I think that, you know,
your cake is kind of
sitting a little wonky,
sitting a little funny,
but it has a lot of character,
and I think character
counts for something.
Oh.
You know, I mean, technically,
it's not perfect.
Yeah, I know.
There's a big wrinkle
I can see right here.
Mm-hmm.
I think the flat polka dots
is probably not the best thing
to cover up that seam with
because they have to sort of,
like, bend in there,
and they kind of --
You know what I mean?
Oh, yeah.
But I like all the colors,
and you know what I think
my favorite part is?
The zero because it looks
like a giant donut --
Oh, really?
...and it's for
"Food Network Magazine,"
so there should be
some food on there.
Yeah.
-You know?
-I agree.
I absolutely love all the colors
that you chose.
It's a very happy cake.
I'm not real keen on you
writing on top of the cake
with just a marker.
It really would have
been nice to see
a little bit
more artistic effort --
Okay.
...because I know
you got it in you.
-Yeah.
-I've seen it.
-Okay, let's taste.
-All right. Let's eat this.
What kind of cake did you make?
So it's a pumpkin spice cake
with an orange cream cheese
frosting and a spiced
pastry cream filling.
-Thank you, sir.
-Look at that color.
Oh, it smells delightful.
Mm!
**
Mmm.
Alex, that's a yummy cake.
-Oh, thank you.
-It's super moist.
All those great spices
are in there,
and you were not
afraid of the spices.
You just pounded away
on those spices here,
but I can take it in a pumpkin
cake because I expect it.
-Yeah.
-I could eat this all day.
-Aw.
-It's really lovely.
Thank you.
I wish that there was a little
bit more frosting
because I really love
cream cheese with pumpkin,
and your pastry cream
is lovely,
but there doesn't seem
to be enough of that either.
Okay.
In between each layer,
I would have put a layer
of your orange
cream cheese frosting
'cause it's delicious --
-Oh.
...and then put the pastry
cream on top of that.
Oh.
You would have had cake,
cream cheese frosting,
pastry cream, and every bite
would've had it,
but your cake itself
is really good.
It's really moist.
It's all the great flavors
you expect in a pumpkin cake.
-Thank you.
-You're quite a baker.
-Thank you, Alex.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, Alex.
-Bye.
Hey, did you have fun?
Oh, yeah.
Tell me about it.
All right. Good.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, that's a very
delicious cake,
I mean,
scrumptiously delicious.
Pretty good.
It seems like he is such
a natural with good flavors.
He really is.
The taste was there,
and the decoration, it was okay,
so maybe I might have a shot
at winning this thing, maybe.
**
DUFF: 10th birthday cake
for "Food Network Magazine."
That's so cute with
the candles.
The final judging, it's really
crazy that I got to this point,
and I'm just really nervous.
-Fun.
-It is fun.
-A lot of fun.
-Yeah, a lot of colors.
I love the logo.
My heart is just beating really
fast and just shaking a bit.
Hey, Linsey.
**
-Hi.
How did you feel today?
I feel pretty good.
Did you ever think that
when you started nine weeks ago
that you'd be standing
here in the finale?
I did not think I'd be here
in the finale at all.
Really?
I didn't think I would just last
this long, and it's really cool.
-All right. [ Chuckles ]
-[ Chuckles ]
So, Linsey, tell us
about your cake
and the inspiration behind it.
So today I made a chocolate cake
with a creamy
coconut filling
and a raspberry buttercream.
I made a chocolate cake
because this entire competition,
I haven't really had
a big chance to make, like,
chocolaty desserts,
and chocolate
is, like, my favorite thing
in the entire world,
and also, for decoration,
I used marbled fondant
because I feel like
the "Food Network Magazine"
is always really colorful
and interesting, so...
You know, we're celebrating
"Food Network Magazine"'s
10th birthday,
and that is a celebration cake
if I ever seen one.
It definitely looks like
a birthday cake.
It is so classy and beautiful.
I love that you made
a Food Network logo.
That's a lot of fun,
and you did a really,
really great job with it.
I love that you put
candles up there.
And I'm looking at your cake,
and it is whoosh, whoosh,
whoosh, totally straight --
-That looks great.
-Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
...but there's only
eight candles.
Oh, the Food Network
symbol is two.
No, I counted,
even with those two.
**
-Oh.
-[ Laughs ]
I thought I made more.
D'oh.
Doy! [ Laughs ]
The marbling is beautiful, but
there's a few technical flaws.
There's some rips
on the bottom cake.
-Mm-hmm.
-It's dried out in places.
Yeah, I love the marbling.
I think it's a really
fun technique.
A little bit less kneading
of the fondant
and I think it would
have been a little brighter
'cause once those colors start
to mix, they get a little muddy.
-Yeah.
-I love that you attempted it.
Oh, yeah. It's cool.
-Let's taste it.
-All right.
Please, please
just like the cake.
Please, I'm begging you.
Creamy coconut.
Mm-hmm.
**
Very raspberry. Mm.
Nice tartness to it.
Yeah, I added a bit of lemon.
I don't taste a ton
of the coconut filling.
All it did was really moisten
your cake quite nicely.
So the coconut filling,
it was more of a soak than a --
-Yeah, it was a soak.
-Got you.
I wish there was more
of the coconut.
I could definitely use
more coconut flavor.
I can taste it.
It's really faint --
Okay.
...but it has a lot of
good big chocolate flavor,
really good raspberry flavor.
It's really nice together.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, Linsey.
-Thanks, Linsey.
-Thank you.
I thought it was an incredibly
moist chocolate cake.
I'm just a little bit
disappointed in the fondant
on the bottom cake,
to put all that
work in to marble
and then have it not
quite come out.
I know that everyone else
did a really great job,
so I may not...
I don't think I'll, like, win,
but I think I did
a really great job.
**
We have three amazing
bakers in the finale,
and each one of them had
a unique take on a birthday cake
for "Food Network
Magazine"'s 10th birthday.
All right.
Let's talk it through.
-All right.
-How about Alex?
Spices.
Oh, my goodness.
That cake tasted so good,
might've been
the best bite of the day.
Listen, that was
a very moist cake.
It was very sophisticated,
pumpkin, spices.
-He made a pastry cream.
-Yeah.
I like his festive
10 on top, too.
I like the zero because
it looked like a donut.
[ Laughs ]
But his decorating had
a lot to be desired.
It was a little rough.
I think Abby's cake was beyond.
I mean, that cake did not look
like a 13-year-old did it.
I like how Abby switched up
her techniques,
but then she brought them all
together with her piped flower.
And the little pearls
on each one.
The strawberry flavor
was really big in Abby's cake.
The lime flavor was really big.
But, whoa, the ratio,
there was almost
more buttercream than cake,
and for me, the biggest
problem with the cake
was how dry it was.
It was very
disappointing for me.
Got you.
Linsey's cake, that was
a moist, chocolaty,
delicious slice of cake,
and the raspberry
buttercream with it.
I love that cake.
I love the flavor
of Linsey's cake,
but I could definitely
use more coconut flavor.
Linsey's decorating
had more flaws.
She also did more stuff,
and she tried more
advanced things.
-She marbled fondant.
-Wow.
She sculpted fondant
into 3D shapes.
She made candles.
She made the Food Network logo,
and I have to say Linsey's
cake was a lot tastier.
But Abby's cake was so clean.
It was definitely
for a 10th birthday,
but, you know,
when you think about it,
the challenge here was to make
a 10th birthday cake
for "Food Network Magazine."
It's this close.
This is only our fourth
Kids Baking Champion.
I want to make
the right decision.
I think we do every year,
and I think
we're going to again.
**
The moment is here, bakers.
-Can you believe it?
-No.
-No, not at all.
We started with
12 amazing kid bakers,
and after a series of really
demanding challenges
and unexpected twists,
the three of you emerged
as our finalists.
[ Sighs ]
Today, you spent five hours
making the cake of your lives.
Linsey, you made
a sophisticated,
moist chocolate cake
with precise, even layers.
You used multiple techniques,
like fondant marbling
and sculpting the Food Network
logo, very, very impressive.
Thank you.
Abby, your vanilla bean
cake was gorgeous.
It was neat and clean
and festive with strong,
intense flavors,
and your details,
like the meticulous pearls
and the tier covered
in sprinkles,
really beautiful work.
Thank you.
Alex, you made a delicious
pumpkin spice cake
with lots of character.
I mean, we could eat
that cake all day long.
It was so delicious.
Thank you.
We appreciated your
rice cereal topper,
and the whole thing made
for a really happy cake.
Thank you.
So we had to ask ourselves,
which cake was
the most successful
in meeting the challenge
of celebrating "Food Network
Magazine"'s 10th birthday?
And the thing is, only one
of you can walk out of here
with the title of
Kids Baking Champion
and $25,000.
**
If I win, every Canadian
will be proud of me.
Super nervous,
this is the most nervous
I've ever been
in my entire life.
In an incredibly
close decision,
like, ridiculously
close, like --
"We're not friends
anymore" close.
...splitting hairs,
the winner of
"Kids Baking Championship"
is...
**
Oh, my gosh.
DUFF AND VALERIE:
...Linsey!
-Oh, my god.
-Congratulations.
Congratulations, Linsey.
You are
the Kids Baking Champion.
Congratulations.
[ Laughs ]
Other than being born,
this is the best moment
of my entire life.
-All of you guys --
-So good.
-...you're all the best.
-Bring it in. Bring it in.
Yay!
Even though I didn't win,
I am so proud of myself
that I made it
to the final three
in "Kids Baking Championship."
-You guys have fun?
-Yeah.
-Awesome.
I still think that I'm a winner
in everyone in Canada's eyes.
Yeah, maybe I might get
a parade when I get home.
-Wow!
-Whoa!
I am the Kids Baking Champion.
**