♪ ♪
Tim Cook:
Good morning, and welcome to WWDC.
We have a big day of announcements
about our latest technologies
and platforms.
These platforms,
and the products they drive,
deliver amazing experiences for our users
and provide developers
with incredible opportunities
so they can use their superpowers
to innovate, create,
and collaborate, making apps
that continue to change the world.
And WWDC is designed
to give this community
what they need to do their very best work.
We love to support our developers
beyond WWDC
with comprehensive world-class support
and other important initiatives.
We just opened our brand-new
Developers Center across from Apple Park
where developers can engage
with our engineers.
And to reach our global community,
this past fall we introduced our first
online Tech Talks for developers
to learn more about our new technologies
and directly connect with Apple engineers
in live sessions
and one-on-one office hours.
We are also committed to cultivating
the next generation of developers,
including efforts to reach
underrepresented communities.
So our developer academies teach
students the fundamentals of coding
as well as the other necessary skills
to find and create jobs
in the app economy.
There are 17 around the world
including the academy in Detroit
we founded in October
as a part of Apple's Racial Equity
and Justice Initiative.
And in Saudi Arabia, we launched our first
developer academy for women in February.
Our Entrepreneur Camps provide developers
from underrepresented communities
with mentorship, inspiration,
and insights from Apple.
The first camps were for female founders,
and this past year,
we expanded the camps
to reach Black and Latin founders.
Alumni have gone on
to secure major funding
and see great success on the App Store.
These ongoing efforts empower
all developers with the tools,
technologies, and inspiration
to change the world for the better.
Last year, many millions of developers
engaged in WWDC,
and we expect millions more
to join us again this year.
In fact, we're excited to say
we've grown our developer community
to over 34 million Apple developers.
We have a huge week ahead of us,
with an amazing online experience,
including sessions, labs,
and digital lounges,
which will all be available for free
to our developers.
Today, we're going to push
our platforms further than ever
for our developers and our users.
So let's get started
by sending it over to Craig.
♪ ♪
Craig Federighi: I'm really excited about
what we have to show you today.
But first, let's head downstairs.
♪ ♪
Now, let's talk about iOS.
Together with iPhone,
iOS helps you get so much done,
whether you're at home or on the move.
And the next release, iOS 16,
offers new intelligence,
sharing, and communication features
that are going to enhance
so much of what you do with your iPhone.
And those come together with an incredible
set of new personalization features
that will make your experience
feel fresh and completely you.
Let's get started
with the all-new Lock Screen.
The Lock Screen is the first thing you see
every time you pick up your iPhone.
It's a place where you can check
the date and time,
look out for key messages,
and launch the camera
to quickly capture the moment.
And it's just as much
a place for personalization,
where so many of you put a photo
that makes iPhone uniquely yours.
In iOS 16, we're bringing the biggest
update ever to the Lock Screen,
completely reimagining
how it looks and works for you.
Let's take a look.
♪ ♪
Craig: The new Lock Screen remains
undeniably iPhone,
while also giving you new ways
to make it more personal,
beautiful, and helpful than ever.
Let me show you.
Here's my Lock Screen.
You'll notice the subtle depth effect
with my daughters appearing
in front of the time.
I really love it.
Now, if I just press and hold,
I can personalize it further.
I'll just tap Customize,
and now I'm in the editor.
Now, check this out.
I can simply swipe
to try out different styles
that automatically change
the color filter, the background,
and the font for the time,
all to complement each other.
These look really beautiful.
So let's go with this one.
Now, of course,
if I want to change anything,
it's easy to dial it in further
to get it just the way I want it.
All I need to do is tap on any element
of the Lock Screen to start editing.
So let's customize the font.
I can audition different typefaces
and choose from different colors.
And I like this color.
I'll just adjust the shade a little bit.
I think this looks awesome now.
Now, I can also make my Lock Screen
more helpful
by putting widgets
right on the Lock Screen.
So let me move the girls down here
and tap in to bring up the widget gallery.
And these are really useful
for getting information at a glance,
like upcoming calendar events.
So I'll add the temperature,
my Activity rings,
and let's drag in the calendar widget.
Now, this is great.
And what's even better is,
I'm not limited to just one.
Let's create another.
I can bring up
our brand-new wallpaper gallery,
which showcases
a bunch of options for inspiration.
And there are plenty to choose from here.
So much room for personalization,
with millions of combinations.
With Photo Shuffle, I can choose a set
of photos to shuffle throughout the day,
And we also have Suggested Photos,
intelligently curated
from my personal library,
like the best shots of family
that look great on the Lock Screen.
Now, this is an awesome one
to add to my collection.
Now, I've created
a bunch of other Lock Screens,
and by simply swiping,
I can switch between them.
It's amazing the range you can create.
Here's Weather,
which shows live weather conditions
like a downpour and lightning.
I just love this animation.
Here's a really cool emoji wallpaper
and our Pride wallpaper.
And here's one
from our Astronomy collection.
Watch how it animates fluidly
as I swipe into the Home Screen.
So cool.
So that's a quick look
at the all-new Lock Screen.
And for developers,
WidgetKit makes it quick and easy
to put glanceable information
from their app here as well.
The new Lock Screen is so beautiful,
we wanted to make sure
that you can always enjoy it,
even if you get a lot of notifications.
Sometimes, notifications can
cover up your personal photo.
So we've rethought how they appear.
Notifications now roll in from the bottom
of the Lock Screen as you receive them,
and you can choose to hide them
throughout the day.
Now, sometimes you get
a bunch of notifications from an app,
like when you're following
the score of a basketball game.
Well, now
there's a better way to keep tabs
with something called Live Activities.
Live Activities make it easier
to stay on top of things
that are happening in real time
right from your Lock Screen.
And for developers, starting in an update
to iOS 16 later this year,
they can use the Live Activities API
to create these compact
and glanceable experiences.
This will make it really easy
to follow that NBA game,
track the progress of an Uber ride,
see how you're doing
on your workout, and more,
all while letting the other elements
on the Lock Screen shine.
One of the most popular activities
for many of us is listening to music.
And now with Live Activities,
the Now Playing controls can expand
to a full screen view that celebrates
album art while you listen along.
So that's the all-new Lock Screen.
There are some really powerful ways
these updates tie together
and build upon what we introduced
last year with Focus.
Focus has helped people reduce
distractions and stay in the moment.
And this year, we're taking it further,
starting with extending Focus
to your Lock Screen.
This means your choice
of a photo and widgets
can all be tied to a particular Focus.
And now that you can have
multiple Lock Screens,
you can match them to the appropriate
Focus throughout your day.
You can have a dedicated one
for when you're in a Work Focus,
with widgets showing your upcoming meeting
or to-do list.
Or, with just a swipe,
you can activate your Personal Focus.
All of your corresponding
notification settings apply,
and it extends to your Home Screen too.
So now you can elevate
your favorite apps or widgets
for keeping up with friends and family.
And now, your Focus can also carry
into the apps themselves,
with Focus filters, which let you
filter out distracting content.
Let's take Safari, for example.
Instead of seeing all of your websites,
you can turn on the Work Focus filter
and see only the tabs that relate to work.
And you can filter
not just tab groups in Safari,
but also conversations in Messages,
accounts in Mail, and events in Calendar.
And for developers, we have a new API
so they can help you focus
in their apps as well.
These updates to Focus
can help you draw boundaries
and find balance throughout
all of the moments in your life.
Now, let's talk about
what's in store for Messages.
Hundreds of millions of people
rely on Messages every single day.
It's integral to how we communicate
with the people who matter most.
And now, we're adding three of the most
highly-requested features to Messages.
First, have you ever sent a Message
only to immediately realize
you didn't quite say what you intended?
Well, no worries.
Because now you can edit
any message you just sent
so embarrassing typos
can be a thing of the past.
Second, have you ever wished
you'd never sent that message at all?
Well, good news–now you have undo send,
so you can immediately recall
a recent misfire.
And finally, you can now mark
any thread as unread,
a perfect tool if you don't have time
to respond in the moment
and want to be sure
to come back to a message later.
These three features are going to make
a big difference
in how you use Messages every single day.
Messages makes texting easy and efficient,
and it's also a great way to share.
Last year, we introduced Shared with You,
which takes things like photos, links,
and music that your friends share
with you in Messages and highlights them
right in the app
where you'd like to enjoy them later.
And for developers, we're really excited
to make Shared with You
available with a new API.
So when someone sends you a funny video,
a worthwhile article,
or a recipe that you don't have time
to check out in the moment,
it'll be there waiting for you
the next time you open that app.
And when it comes to sharing in real time
with others, people are loving SharePlay.
It's stellar for enjoying
shared experiences
while connecting over FaceTime.
Like watching TV shows,
listening to music,
or breaking a sweat
to a synced up workout.
So many of your favorite apps
are using SharePlay
to create shared experiences,
like listening to bedtime stories together
with Better Sleep
or playing a rowdy game of Heads Up,
no matter how far apart you are.
And this year,
we're making it easier to discover
all of these awesome SharePlay experiences
from within your FaceTime call.
With just a tap, you can jump
into SharePlay-supported apps
that you already have on your phone,
or discover new experiences
that you can share with your friends.
And to give you more opportunities
to enjoy shared experiences,
we're extending SharePlay beyond FaceTime
and bringing it to Messages.
This was the number one request
from developers.
Now when you find something
you want to share,
like a movie on Disney+,
you can kick off SharePlay right there
and enjoy it together
while chatting in Messages.
You can watch in sync,
and you've got the same instantaneous
shared playback controls
that make SharePlay magical.
So whether you're using SharePlay
for your weekly movie night
or marking a message unread
so you can respond later,
Messages has everything you need
to connect with ease.
And we're making it that much easier
to compose Messages
with some updates to Dictation.
To tell you more, here's Robby.
Robby Walker:
Dictation lets you type just by speaking
and can be much faster
than typing with the Keyboard.
This is why it's so popular for taking
notes, sending messages, and more.
In fact, Dictation is used
over 18 billion times each month.
And it's designed to protect your privacy.
Thanks to the Neural Engine,
Dictation can happen entirely on-device.
Today, we're excited to introduce
an all-new on-device Dictation experience
that lets you fluidly move
between voice and touch.
Let's take a look.
We'll use our new dictation experience
to send an email.
Now, when I start dictating,
the keyboard stays open,
so I can switch
between using voice and touch.
I can even select text using touch
and replace it with my voice.
Just by speaking.
Are you sending a longer message?
Dictation automatically adds
punctuation to the text.
"That's so cool! Mind blown emoji!"
Automatic punctuation
and emoji dictation also work
when you send messages with Siri.
And this year, we're making it easier
to use Siri with apps.
There are over 15,000 apps
that work with Siri
using SiriKit and Siri Shortcuts.
And today, these require manual setup.
So we're introducing a new developer API
built using the Swift programming language
called App Intents.
Now shortcuts work with zero setup
so you can use Siri to get things done
with supported apps.
Now let's talk about another feature
powered by intelligence: Live Text.
Live Text is so useful
because it's deeply integrated
across the entire OS,
letting you interact with text
in images across the system,
from Camera and Safari
to Notes and Screenshots.
And this year, we're excited
to take this integration further
by bringing Live Text to video.
Now you can pause a video
on any frame and interact with text
just like you can today with photos.
It's great for copying code samples.
We're also accelerating the things you do
with Live Text with quick actions.
So now you're just a tap away
from converting currency
and translating a foreign language.
And for an even richer
translation experience,
you'll be able to use Live Text
while in the Translate app,
with our new camera view.
This will be great for when you have
lots of text to translate.
And for developers, we're also excited
to announce a Live Text API.
Soon you will be able to grab text
straight from photos
and videos in apps like Vimeo.
And photos are about more than just text.
That's why last year
we introduced Visual Look Up,
a feature that recognizes objects like
pets, landmarks, plants, and more,
and gives you rich information
about what's in your images.
And this year we have a new feature
that takes image understanding further.
Now when you touch and hold
on the subject of an image,
you can lift it away from the background
and place it in apps like Messages.
It feels like magic.
It's actually the product
of an advanced machine learning model
which is accelerated by CoreML
and the Neural Engine to perform
40 billion operations
in just milliseconds.
Together, Live Text and Visual Look Up
continue to unlock
rich and useful information
from your photos and videos
across iOS, iPadOS, and macOS.
Back to you, Craig.
Craig: These intelligence features
help you get things done with ease.
And another app that makes life easier
is Wallet.
To tell you about what's new in Wallet,
I'll hand it over to Corey.
Corey Fugman:
With Apple Wallet, we're working hard
on our goal to replace
your physical wallet.
Take what we're doing
with driver's licenses and ID cards.
We're excited to have launched
Maryland and Arizona,
with 11 additional states
actively working on deployments.
And the first locations
now accepting Wallet IDs
are select TSA security checkpoints.
You'll also be able
to securely present your ID
to apps requiring identity
and age verification.
To protect your privacy, only the
necessary information will be shared.
So rather than providing
your exact birthday,
you can simply share that you are over 21.
Now, let's talk about Keys.
Our growing suite of keys in Wallet
makes it easy to access everyday places
like your home, car, hotel, and office,
all with just your iPhone.
And now we're making sharing keys
even easier
with your favorite messaging apps
like Mail, Messages, or WhatsApp.
When your friend receives the key,
they can add it to their Wallet
with a single tap.
And to let you share keys with people
who don't have an iPhone,
we're working with the IETF to make
sharing keys an industry standard
that is free for others to adopt.
We are seeing tremendous enthusiasm
from our partners,
with more of them signing on to support
keys for all of the places you visit.
Now let's talk about Apple Pay,
one of the most important areas of Wallet.
We've made a lot of progress
with Apple Pay acceptance
in stores and online,
and now we're expanding even further.
Starting this month
with Tap to Pay on iPhone,
millions of merchants across the U.S.
can accept contactless payments
directly on iPhone with no additional
hardware or payment terminal needed.
Beginning with apps
from these payment providers,
Tap to Pay on iPhone enables
small merchants and large retailers
to use iPhone to securely accept payments.
In addition to expanded acceptance,
we're also enhancing Apple Pay
to support new types of payments.
So we are thrilled to announce
Apple Pay Later.
Apple Pay Later lets you split the cost
of an Apple Pay purchase
into four equal payments
spread over six weeks
with zero interest
and no fees of any kind.
And Apple Pay Later is available
everywhere Apple Pay is accepted
in apps and online.
You can now get that espresso machine
you've wanted
and pay for it over time
with no additional cost.
For developers and merchants,
Apple Pay Later requires no integration.
It just works using their
standard Apple Pay implementation.
Upcoming payments are managed
through Wallet,
making it easy to keep track
of what's due when
and to stay within a budget.
And after you've placed your order,
we have another brand-new feature
that helps you track it.
Apple Pay Order Tracking enables merchants
to deliver detailed receipt and tracking
information directly to Wallet,
making it easy to get
the latest information
on all of your Apple Pay orders delivered
securely and privately to your device.
Apple Pay Order Tracking will be
offered at millions of merchants
through eCommerce platforms
starting with Shopify.
So that's our Wallet update.
Back to you, Craig.
Craig: With ID cards available
in more locations,
new ways to use and share keys,
Apple Pay Later,
and Apple Pay Order Tracking,
Wallet makes life so much easier,
no matter where you go.
And the best way to get wherever
you're going is with Maps.
So let's get out of here
to talk about what's new.
♪ ♪
We're building the best map to help you
navigate and explore the world.
We've launched our redesigned map
in ten countries and regions,
and we're excited to announce
that later this year,
we'll bring the new map to 11 more,
including France,
Switzerland, and New Zealand.
Our new map includes great features like
cycling, Look Around, and so many more.
And with the new city experience,
we pushed it even further
with unprecedented detail for landcover,
roads, and elevation,
as well as improved driving
and transit navigation.
And we're adding Las Vegas,
which looks stunning.
And before the end of the year,
we'll add six more cities
including Miami, Chicago, and Sydney.
To tell you more about what's new in Maps,
here's Meg.
Meg Frost: With iOS 16,
we're introducing great updates
for Maps users and developers.
Let's start with one of our most
requested features:
multistop routing.
You can now plan
up to 15 stops in advance.
Maps will now store previous routes
in Recents so they're easy to get back to
and you can plan multi-stop routes
on the Mac
and send them to iPhone
when you're ready to go.
And, of course,
when you're driving,
you can ask Siri to add additional stops
to your route
while safely keeping your eyes
on the road.
Next, let's talk about
getting around with transit.
We're making it easy
for riders to see fares
for how much their journey will cost
along with the ability
to add transit cards to Wallet.
And if a transit card balance is
running low
, you'll receive an alert
so you can reload it
without having to leave Maps.
And for developers,
we're making big improvements to MapKit,
starting with our
revolutionary new city experience
which includes rich details for landcover,
roads, landmarks, and more.
Developers like Bird can now integrate
this detailed map
so users can more easily locate bikes
and scooters to get around town.
And it looks stunning
in both Light and Dark Mode.
And there's more.
We're also bringing Look Around to MapKit,
making it easy to integrate
high resolution imagery from Maps
into apps like Zillow,
helping users get an immersive
ground-level view while browsing homes.
And finally, we're excited to announce
that later this year,
developers will have faster
and more flexible ways
to build incredible Maps experiences
with brand-new server-side APIs.
And that's a quick look at Maps.
Back to you, Craig!
Craig: Now, let's talk about sports.
Sports can bring people together
in meaningful ways,
whether a heated rivalry among friends
or a whole town rooting for their team.
And at Apple, we want to create great
experiences for sports fans everywhere.
To tell you more, here's Rubie.
♪ ♪
Rubie Edmondson: Today, there are many
ways to keep up with your favorite sports,
like being able to ask Siri
about players or teams
or see live games,
no matter where they're streaming.
And now with Live Activities,
the Apple TV app brings you scores
and play-by-play action
right on your Lock Screen.
We also recently premiered
Friday Night Baseball on Apple TV+
where you can stream
two great games every Friday.
And today, we have another major update
for sports in Apple News.
Apple News is the number one news app
everywhere it's available,
and it's about to become amazing
for sports fans.
You can now follow your favorite teams
and leagues to get stories
from hundreds of the best publishers
in an all-new section called My Sports.
You'll also find scores, schedules,
and standings for the top professional
and college sports leagues,
and highlights too.
Now you can catch the best plays from your
favorite teams right in your news feed.
And your favorites are seamlessly synced
with the Apple TV app
and across all your Apple devices.
This new sports experience is free.
It'll be available in the U.S.,
UK, Canada, and Australia.
And when you subscribe to Apple News+,
you'll get premium sports coverage
from many local newspapers.
That's Sports.
Back to you, Craig.
Craig: iOS and the entire Apple ecosystem
are amazing for families,
and we have some great new features
to talk about,
starting with some updates
to Family Sharing.
With Family Sharing,
you can share your favorite purchases
and subscriptions with up to five
of your family members,
including Apple Music, iCloud+,
Apple One, and much more.
Everyone gets personalized access
to their favorite content
without having to buy their own
subscriptions or share an account.
And for households with kids,
you can create accounts just for them
with built-in parental controls
to help you monitor their screen time
or approve their purchases.
And this year, we're making it even easier
to create accounts for kids
and make sure the right parental controls
are in place right from the start.
We're adding a new, easy way
to set age-appropriate restrictions
for apps, movies, books, and music.
Along with quick setup
of other important parental controls.
We're also making setting up
a new device for your child–
like an iPad–really simple.
Just turn on the device they'll be using,
bring your iPhone nearby,
and choose to set up with Quick Start.
With just a few taps, the new device
will be set up for their use
with all the parental controls
you've selected already configured.
And when your child asks
for more screen time,
you won't have to navigate to Settings
to approve or deny their request.
You can now respond right in Messages.
Finally, we've added a new
Family Checklist with helpful tips
like updating a child's settings
as they get older,
turning on location sharing,
or just reminding you that you can share
your iCloud+ subscription with everyone.
So those are some of the helpful updates
to Family Sharing this year.
Now, as we all know, one of the things
everyone enjoys sharing
with their family is photos.
So this year, we're introducing a better
way to share photos with your family.
Our precious memories are
often captured by several people
and in between personal photos of hobbies,
house projects, and homework,
we have photos on our device that
everyone in the family would like to have.
But no one has all of them,
so the family's memories
are never complete.
Until now.
We're introducing
iCloud Shared Photo Library
to help you share photos seamlessly
and even automatically.
It's easy to set up.
It's a separate iCloud library
that everyone can contribute to,
collaborate on, and enjoy.
You can participate in one shared library
that's shared
with up to five other people.
We've made it simple to share just
the photos you want from your library.
You can share everything
already in your library,
or choose what to include based on
a start date or the people in the photos.
For example, you can choose
to include just the photos
where you were together with your partner
and the kids.
Once the Shared Library is set up,
you can manually move over new photos
after you take them.
But we wanted to make it even easier
with a new switch right in Camera
that sends shots straight to
the Shared Library as you take them.
This is great when you're on a vacation
and you want to make sure
the photos are shared right away.
And if you take a photo
of something personal, like a gift,
you can easily turn it off.
You can also choose to have
the sharing switch enabled automatically
whenever you take shots with other
members of the Shared Library nearby.
So if you take photos on a camping trip,
you don't have to remember
to share them later.
You'll also receive intelligent
sharing suggestions in the For You tab.
Everyone has equal permissions
for adding, editing,
and deleting photos in the Shared Library.
So if one member of the group
is a talented photo editor,
everyone gets to enjoy their edits
to the shared photos.
Deletions, captions,
and keywords sync too.
Content in the Shared Library
will appear in everyone's Memories,
Featured Photos, and in the Photos widget.
So you can relive your family's adventures
that include all the photos.
That's iCloud Shared Photo Library:
the best way to share photos
with your family.
And last, let's talk about privacy.
We're always working hard to protect
our users and their privacy,
with features like App Privacy Report,
Mail Privacy Protection,
App Tracking Transparency,
Privacy Nutrition Labels,
and so many more.
Another critically important area
is protecting our users' personal safety.
One way we're doing that
is by adding a new tool
to help people quickly turn off
others' access,
for example, disabling location sharing if
they're escaping an abusive relationship.
It's called Safety Check.
To tell you about it, here's Katie.
Katie Skinner:
Many people share passwords
and access to their devices
with their partner.
However, in abusive relationships,
this can threaten personal safety
and make it harder for victims
to get help.
We've been working closely
with organizations
that support victims of domestic
and intimate partner violence.
And the result of those conversations
is Safety Check,
a new section in Settings where you can
quickly review and reset the access
you've granted others.
This lets people in abusive situations
quickly revoke an abuser's access
to their data and location,
enabling them to cut ties
and get to safety.
Safety Check stops sharing your location
with others via FindMy
and resets the system privacy
permissions for all apps.
It also protects access to your messages
by helping you sign out of iCloud
on all your other devices
and restricts Messages and FaceTime
to the device in your hand.
Safety Check also helps you manage
who you've given access to.
And you can audit which permissions
you've granted to certain apps.
We've received some really positive
feedback on our approach,
including from
the National Center for Victims of Crime
who said: "In times of crisis,
for many survivors,
"it's important to know
who has their information and location.
Safety Check helps
give control back to survivors."
This is important work,
expanding the ways
iOS helps you stay safe.
Now, back to you, Craig.
Craig: Protecting you and your privacy
is and will always be
at the center of what we do.
iOS 16 offers so many updates that will
change the way you experience iPhone.
iOS also extends that experience
beyond the phone,
to enhance how you interact
with the world around you.
Whether helping you through
your morning routine
or keeping you connected
on your next road trip,
iOS has you covered.
This year we're bringing exciting updates
to your home and your car.
To tell you what's new in the home,
here's Corey.
♪ ♪
Corey Wang: Our home is perhaps
the most important place in our lives,
and there's a lot to manage.
Smart home accessories can make it easier
and more convenient to control your home
right from your iPhone.
You can do things like see who's
at the door while working at your desk,
or turn off the lights downstairs
without getting out of bed.
And when you're away from home,
you can double-check
if the front door is locked
or adjust the temperature
so it's just right when you get back.
And your smart home
is all the more powerful
when your accessories work together,
reacting to changes automatically.
Now, the smart home is still
in its early days,
and we want to help bring
these powerful experiences
to as many homes as possible.
In order to build a connected
ecosystem at home,
it's important that you have
the most choice
so you don't have to worry
about what works with what.
With that in mind, we joined forces
with other industry leaders
to create a new smart home
connectivity standard.
It's called Matter.
Matter enables smart home accessories
to work together across platforms.
And to ensure we stayed true
to our values,
we contributed HomeKit,
our smart home framework,
as a foundation of this new standard,
so it's built on the same core principles
and maintains
the highest level of security.
Industry-leading brands have
already committed to supporting Matter,
with over 130 products in the pipeline,
and that's just the beginning.
The Matter standard provides
the underlying foundation
to connect smart home accessories,
and it allows us to innovate on top of it.
We take privacy further,
ensuring that data about how you use
your accessories is processed
and stored by default in a way
that even Apple can't see.
With Matter, we can continue to create
amazing experiences in the Home app
while also making sure
all your different accessories
are consistently simple to set up
and easy to use.
And now that you’ll have more
accessory options to choose from,
let's check out how we made
the experience even better
with an all-new Home app.
We reimagined it from the ground up
starting with the underlying architecture
so it's more efficient and reliable,
especially for homes
with many accessories.
We also completely redesigned
how you navigate, organize,
and view accessories to make it easier
to control your smart home.
We've integrated your rooms and favorites
into the main tab of the app.
So you can see your entire home
in a single view.
And we made sure it looks great,
whether you're just getting started
or have built out
an advanced connected home.
We added new categories for climate,
lights, security, and more
and an overview of what's happening
in each category
right at the top of the screen.
And categories are a great way
to navigate within the app.
When you tap on a specific category,
you see all the relevant accessories
organized by room
and more detailed status information.
A multi-camera view displays up to
four cameras at once front and center,
and you can scroll to the right
to see any additional cameras.
We also redesigned tiles
so that different accessories
are more visually recognizable
through shape and color.
And with the new widgets
on the Lock Screen, it's easier than ever
to see how your home is doing.
So that's the all-new Home app,
and it's coming to iPhone, iPad, and Mac.
Now that you have what you need
to keep tabs on your home,
you're ready to hit the road.
Let's hand it off to Emily
to talk about CarPlay.
Emily Schubert: CarPlay is the smarter,
safer way to use your iPhone in the car
and has fundamentally changed the way
people interact with their vehicles.
It's available
on over 98% of cars in the U.S.
What's more, 79% of U.S. buyers
would only consider a car
that works with CarPlay.
It's a must-have feature
when shopping for a new vehicle.
Our users love CarPlay.
It gives them an easy way
to use apps in the car,
using the familiar UI from their iPhone.
But cars have changed a lot,
with larger-sized screens
and more of them throughout the car.
There's an opportunity for iPhone
to play an even more important role.
We've been working with automakers
to reinvent the in-car experience
across all of the driver's screens.
Let's take a sneak peek
at this next generation of CarPlay.
♪ ♪
There's so much to explore here.
Let's take a closer look.
This next generation of CarPlay provides
content for all the driver's screens,
giving an experience
that is unified and consistent.
It's the very best
of both your car and your iPhone.
And it goes beyond what you can do
with CarPlay today.
Deep integration with the car's hardware
lets you tune your car's radio
or change your temperature without ever
leaving the CarPlay experience.
It also includes widgets,
powered by your iPhone,
that fit your screens perfectly.
They can live front and center
in the gauge cluster as well,
giving you information at a glance.
In fact, this next generation of CarPlay
powers your entire instrument cluster.
To do this, your iPhone communicates
with your vehicle's real-time systems
in an on-device, privacy-friendly way,
showing all of your driving information
like speed, RPMs,
fuel level, temperature, and more.
And no matter what type of unique
screen shapes or layouts you may have,
this next generation of CarPlay feels like
it was made specifically for your car.
We're also excited to give you the ability
to make the core of the driving experience
unique to you.
We carefully crafted
instrument cluster options
ranging from the modern
to the traditional,
that use different colors,
dial treatments, backgrounds, and layouts
to provide various looks and feels.
You can choose different curated themes
and styles for your gauges.
And automakers
from around the world are excited
to bring this new vision of CarPlay
to customers.
This is just a taste of what
the next generation of CarPlay will bring.
Vehicles will start to be announced
late next year,
and we can't wait to show you more
further down the road.
And now, I'll hand it back to Craig.
Craig: And that's iOS 16,
a mighty release that gives you
entirely new ways to make iOS your own.
It also helps you stay in touch with ease,
engage with the world around you,
and seamlessly share experiences
and memories with your family and friends.
And that's just the beginning.
We've also made a big advancement
in Spatial Audio with AirPods.
Now, Spatial Audio works by understanding
how sound interacts
with the geometry of your head and ears.
And now, in iOS 16, you can use
the True Depth camera on iPhone
to create a personalized
Spatial Audio profile,
enabling an even more precise
and immersive listening experience,
tuned just for you.
Plus, Quick Note is coming to iOS
so you can capture ideas instantly.
A new rapid security response mechanism
gets important improvements
to iPhone faster,
and you've got more Memoji customizations
to choose from.
And there's so many more features to meet
your needs no matter where you are.
Now, I’ll hand it over to Kevin
to tell you about the big new advancements
coming to Apple Watch.
♪ ♪
Kevin Lynch: Let's talk about watchOS.
Apple Watch continues to be
the most loved watch in the world,
because it helps you stay connected,
active, and healthy.
In watchOS 9 we're bringing great
new features to each of these three areas.
First, you can stay connected
to what matters to you most
just by glancing at your wrist,
whether you use
the popular Photos watch face,
or a face with rich complications.
And we're adding four new watch faces
for you to choose from.
The Astronomy face has been remastered to
take advantage of the expansive display,
and shows current cloud coverage
around the world.
The Lunar calendar is used
to observe traditional holidays
and special events in many cultures.
The Lunar watch face celebrates
this thousand-year-old practice
with support for Chinese,
Islamic, and Hebrew calendars.
Play Time, designed by artist Joi Fulton,
features whimsical animated numbers.
You can tap the display
to send them bouncing around,
and when you lower your wrist,
they take a nap.
Finally, Metropolitan highlights
watch typography with a new font
that dynamically stretches
when you rotate the digital crown,
and features
many lovely color combinations.
Rich complications enable you to see
more information in a small space,
and we're bringing these
to more of our watch faces.
watchOS 9 also introduces a refreshed
Siri UI and new banner notifications.
And active apps will be pinned
to the top of the Dock for quick access.
Another way to stay connected
is by listening to the latest stories,
or sharing your favorite content.
With watchOS 9,
the Podcast app allows you to discover
and follow new podcasts
using Search and Listen Now.
And the app is now available to kids
using Family Setup.
For developers, sharing content and
selected images from apps like Outcast
and WeChat is easier with the new
Share Sheet and Photos Picker APIs.
And with CallKit, you can start,
end, or mute VoIP calls from apps
like Webex directly on Apple Watch.
That's some of what's coming
in watchOS 9 to keep you connected.
And now to Craig to tell you
what's coming to keep you active.
Craig Bolton: The Workout app
is one of the most popular apps,
so in watchOS 9,
we're bringing new easy-to-use metrics,
views, and training experiences
inspired by high-performing athletes,
starting with running.
It's a sport that,
no matter what your level,
you can use metrics to better understand
your performance.
And switching up your training
can reduce the chance of getting injured.
The first thing we're doing is adding
three new running form metrics
to track how efficiently you run.
Measuring these from the wrist isn't easy.
Take vertical oscillation for example,
which is a measure of how much
you move up and down.
If it's too high, your energy
might be wasted going up
versus propelling you forward.
In order to capture this from the wrist,
we need to extrapolate your torso movement
from the distinctive style
of your arm swing.
We use machine learning
and sensor fusion–
a combination of accelerometer
and gyroscope–
to isolate your torso movement,
and then measure how much
vertical oscillation is produced.
We use a similar approach to measure
the two other Running Form metrics–
stride length and ground contact time.
These metrics can be added
to new easy-to-read Workout views.
Each Workout view
lets you see more at a glance.
Scroll the digital crown to see new views
for familiar metrics like segments,
splits, and elevation.
And we're introducing heart rate zones
so you can quickly see
what zone you're in
and get a sense of your intensity level
at any point during your workout.
There's also a new custom workout
that you can use
to add structure into your run.
For example, if you are trying
to improve your speed or endurance,
you can create a workout
using distance and time intervals
that include sets of work and recovery
which you can repeat as needed.
You can also add one of the new alerts
to a specific part of your workout–
like one to monitor which heart rate zone
you want to train in
to help keep you on track.
During your run,
these alerts will guide you
with both haptics and voice feedback,
letting you know when to switch
between work and recovery
and when to pick up the pace
if your heart rate falls below
the target zone that you set.
During your run,
you can use the Digital Crown
for additional workout views
like this new power metric.
Running with a power target
can help you go the distance
by keeping your effort in a range
that you can reasonably sustain.
You can even see how this workout
is contributing to your Activity rings.
And if it's a route you do often,
it will be automatically saved
in the Workout app for you to race
against your last or best time.
That way, you can see if all the training
you're doing is paying off.
You can use many of these new features
not just when you're running,
but for many workout types like Hiking,
HIIT, and Functional Strength Training.
And for our triathletes,
there's a new multi-sport workout type
that uses sensor fusion to detect
when you finish one leg of your race
and are transitioning to the next.
So it can automatically switch
between swimming, cycling, and running.
That's just some of what's coming
to the Workout app in watchOS 9.
Since the first Apple Watch,
we've been inspired by the stories
we hear from users who stay motivated
by closing their Activity rings each day.
We also know there are many
iPhone users who want to meet
their fitness goals
but don't yet have an Apple Watch.
So in iOS 16, the Fitness app
will be available to all iPhone users.
Using the iPhone motion sensors,
you can track steps, distance,
flights climbed,
and workouts from your favorite apps,
which can be converted to
an estimation of your active calories
to contribute to your daily Move goal.
You'll also be able to share
your Move ring with friends
and receive coaching tips.
While Apple Watch gives you a picture
of your all-day activity,
we're excited to bring some of
the Fitness app benefits to iPhone users
to get them started
on their fitness journey.
Now, I'll hand it off to Sumbul
to tell you what's coming in watchOS 9
to help keep you healthy.
Sumbul Ahmad Desai:
The Sleep app has helped millions of you
by providing insights
into how much sleep you're getting
along with metrics like heart rate,
respiratory rate, and blood oxygen.
In watchOS 9, you'll be able to learn more
about your sleep with Sleep Stages.
Apple Watch uses signals from
the accelerometer and heart rate sensor
to detect which stage of sleep you're in.
Machine learning models
were trained and validated
against the clinical gold standard
of polysomnography with the largest
and most diverse population
ever studied for a wearable.
You can see how much time
you spent in each stage,
as well as when you might have woken up.
You'll see more details in the Health app
where you'll learn
that each sleep stage–
REM, Core, and Deep–
perform an essential function.
And as you sleep, you're likely to cycle
through these stages multiple times.
Researchers are still looking
into what happens during sleep
and how it impacts your health.
We want to help push forward
the science of sleep,
so Apple Heart and Movement Study
participants will now be able
to contribute sleep stage data
through the Research app.
With the large scale of this study, we are
excited about the potential discoveries.
That's what's new with sleep.
Another area where Apple Watch
has an impact is heart health.
We hear from so many of you who have
received an Atrial Fibrillation alert
and sought potentially-life saving care.
So we also wanted to offer support
once you've been diagnosed.
When living with this condition,
it's important to understand
the time you spend in AFib
because it may relate
to your risk of serious complications,
such as stroke.
watchOS 9 can now track the amount of time
your heart shows signs of this rhythm
with AFib History.
And in the Health app,
you can manage lifestyle factors
that may influence the amount of time
you spend in AFib
like exercise, sleep, and weight.
AFib History even helps you identify
the time of the day or week
when your AFib is most frequent.
You can also share a PDF with your doctor
to facilitate richer conversations.
AFib History
is a first-of-its-kind feature
that uniquely provides insights
into your AFib over the long term.
We expect to receive FDA clearance
for AFib History soon.
Apple Watch makes some
of the more complicated aspects
of your health more intuitive.
And this year, we're tackling
another integral aspect of health
for so many of us–Medications.
Over 50% of people
take prescription medications,
and we wanted to help make it
easier to track, manage,
and understand
the medications that you take.
So in watchOS 9, the Medications app
makes it easy for you to discreetly
and conveniently track your medications,
vitamins, and supplements anytime.
You can log medications
that you might take occasionally
like Cetirizine for allergies.
And you can receive notifications
for medications
that you need to take regularly.
Rich complications on your watch face
can help you stay on top of your schedule.
And of course you can track and manage
your medications in the Health app,
even if you don't have an Apple Watch.
To build your medications list,
start typing the name,
and you'll see suggestions.
We wanted to make
creating the list easier,
especially if you take
multiple medications.
So you can just use your iPhone camera
to scan the label of your medication.
You can create a schedule
to receive reminders
and add custom visuals
to make it easier to remember.
Another important aspect of medications
is drug-drug interactions,
which can make them less effective
or cause side effects.
In the U.S. alone,
drug interactions cause nearly
a quarter of a million
hospitalizations each year.
To help you with this, you'll receive
an alert when you add a new medication
if there is a critical interaction.
We've partnered with Elsevier,
a leading medical publisher,
to provide clinically accurate
and evidence-based information
across the Medications experience.
You'll be able to review critical,
serious, and moderate interactions
as well as interaction factors
like alcohol.
Medications also works
with Health Sharing,
which is updated in iOS 16.
You can now send a family member
an invitation
to share their health data with you.
This is another way that you can support
a loved one on their health journey
and have peace of mind, too.
Now back to Kevin.
Kevin: Your health data is some of
your most personal information,
and privacy is central to how we build
and design features for Apple Watch.
Health data is encrypted on device
and is not shared without
your explicit permission.
You'll also now be periodically reminded
of what health data you're sharing
and who you're sharing it with.
There's so much more in watchOS 9,
including support for six
new keyboard languages,
a new way for developers to connect
their watchOS apps to Apple TV,
and with Family Setup,
kids can now control home devices
right from their wrist.
watchOS is the world's most advanced
wearable operating system,
and watchOS 9 takes it further
with new features
to help you stay connected,
active, and healthy.
Back to Craig.
Craig: I'm so excited for watchOS 9
and can't wait to get it
into the hands of our users.
Next, to show you what's new with Mac,
here's John.
♪ ♪
John Ternus: We couldn't be more excited
by how well the Mac transition
to Apple Silicon is going.
It all started with the launch of M1,
which brought a whole new level
of performance, capabilities,
and battery life to the Mac.
We've already transitioned
nearly the entire Mac product line.
Users have been blown away
by the phenomenal capabilities
of these new systems
powered by the M1 family of chips.
And the Mac business
has never been stronger.
Well, today we're excited to start
the next generation
of Apple Silicon for the Mac.
Introducing...
M2.
It takes the breakthrough performance
and capabilities of M1 even further.
To tell you more,
I'll pass it over to Johny.
Johny Srouji: Today we begin our second
generation of Apple Silicon
designed specifically for the Mac.
The M-Series chips deliver a scalable
range of performance and capabilities.
It began with M1's
breakthrough set of features
that transformed our most popular systems.
M2 starts the second generation
of M-Series chips,
and goes beyond the remarkable features
of M1.
Unlike others in the industry
who significantly increase power
to gain performance,
our approach is different.
We continue to have a relentless focus
on power efficient performance.
In other words, maximizing performance
while minimizing power consumption.
Combined with our unified memory
architecture and custom technologies,
this focus on power efficiency
allows M2 to bring even more performance
and new capabilities
to our most popular Macs.
M2 is built using an enhanced,
second-generation
five nanometer technology,
and features over 20 billion transistors:
that's 25% more than M1.
We use those transistors to enhance
every feature of the chip,
starting with the memory controller
which delivers
100GB/s of unified memory bandwidth,
which is 50% more than M1
for even greater performance.
And because M1 is so capable,
users run all sorts of demanding tasks.
So for M2, we've enabled
up to 24GB of unified memory
to handle even larger
and more complex workloads.
M2 features our next-generation CPU,
with advancements in both
the performance and efficiency cores.
The performance cores are faster
and feature a larger cache,
and the efficiency cores
have been significantly enhanced
for even greater performance gains.
Together, they rip through CPU-intensive
tasks using very little power.
When we look at the multi-core
CPU performance of M2 compared to M1,
it delivers 18% greater performance.
And compared to the latest
10-core PC laptop chip,
the CPU in M2 delivers nearly
two times faster performance
at the same power level.
And M2 delivers the peak performance
of the PC chip
while using a quarter of the power.
Now let's compare M2 to the latest 12-core
PC laptop chip,
which needs dramatically more power
to deliver an increase in performance.
So it's in a thicker, hotter,
more noisy system
with less battery life.
M2 delivers nearly 90% of the peak
performance of the 12-core chip
while using just a quarter of the power.
This is what we mean
by the power efficient performance
of Apple Silicon.
M2 also features our next generation GPU,
which now has up to 10 cores–
that's two more than M1.
Combined with a larger cache
and higher memory bandwidth,
the 10-core GPU delivers a big boost
in graphics performance.
M2 delivers up to 25% higher
graphics performance
at the same power level as M1
and up to 35% higher performance
at its max.
And compared to the integrated graphics
in the latest PC laptop chip,
the GPU in M2 delivers 2.3 times faster
performance at the same power level.
And M2 delivers the peak performance
of the PC chip
using just one-fifth of the power.
This much higher performance
per watt from M2
enables systems to run cool and quiet
with exceptional battery life.
Now, one of the advantages
of making our own silicon
is that we can quickly bring
our newest custom technologies
across our SoCs.
So M2 also features our next-generation
Secure Enclave and Neural Engine.
The Neural Engine in M2 can process
up to 15.8 trillion operations per second.
That's over 40% more than M1.
It also has
our next generation media engine,
including a higher-bandwidth video decoder
that supports 8K H.264 and HEVC video.
And M2 features our powerful
ProRes video engine
for hardware accelerated
encode and decode.
So systems with M2 will be able to play
back multiple streams of 4K and 8K video.
So that's M2.
It starts our next generation
of M-Series chips, with an 18% faster CPU,
35% faster GPU,
40% faster Neural Engine,
and 50% more memory bandwidth.
It takes the amazing performance,
capabilities,
and efficiency of M1 even further.
Now, back to John.
John: The fact that we're already starting
our next generation of Apple Silicon
for the Mac is remarkable.
So now let's talk about
the first Mac to get the M2 chip.
We're thrilled that it's
our most loved Mac–
the MacBook Air.
Users love MacBook Air
for its great performance,
portability, and battery life.
It defined the category
of thin and light notebooks.
And with M1, it redefined
what a thin and light notebook could do.
Today, it's more popular than ever.
In fact, MacBook Air is
the world's best-selling laptop.
Apple Silicon enables us to design
products we never could have imagined,
which is why we're so excited
to introduce an all-new MacBook Air,
completely redesigned around M2.
And here it is.
♪ ♪
John: This is the new MacBook Air,
powered by M2.
And to tell you all about it,
here's Kristin.
Kristin White: The new MacBook Air takes
everything our users love about the Air
to the next level.
The wedge shape of the previous Air
has evolved into a new design
that's strikingly thin from every angle.
The durable,
all-aluminum unibody enclosure
feels incredibly solid when you hold it
and is built to last.
And this remarkably thin design
integrates its components so efficiently
that it results in an astonishing 20%
reduction in volume over the previous Air.
The new Air is just 11.3mm thin,
or under half an inch,
and it's only 2.7 pounds.
MacBook Air now comes in four finishes:
Silver, Space Gray,
a gorgeous Starlight,
and a stunning Midnight.
And yes, MagSafe is back
for dedicated charging
and peace of mind when you're plugged in.
And it keeps
the two Thunderbolt ports free
for connecting
to a variety of accessories.
There's also an audio jack with support
for high-impedance headphones.
This all-new design
is incredibly portable,
and it's loaded with new features,
starting with a brilliant
Liquid Retina display.
We expanded the display closer
to the sides and up around the camera
to make room for the menu bar.
The result is a larger 13.6-inch display
with much thinner borders,
giving users more screen real estate
to view their content in brilliant detail.
At 500 nits,
it's also 25% brighter than before.
And MacBook Air now supports
1 billion colors,
so photos and movies
look incredibly vibrant.
Next, let's talk about the camera.
Having a great camera is more
important than ever these days.
So MacBook Air features a new
1080p camera with twice the resolution
and twice the low-light performance
of the previous Air.
Combined with the processing power
of M2's advanced image signal processor,
you'll look great on video calls.
Next up, audio.
To fit inside such a thin design,
the speakers and mics
are completely integrated
between the keyboard and display,
all while delivering
an even better audio experience.
A three-mic array captures clean audio
using advanced beam-forming algorithms.
And there's a four-speaker sound system
that produces amazing stereo separation
and vocal clarity.
There's also support
for immersive Spatial Audio
for music and movies with Dolby Atmos.
The Magic Keyboard features
a full-height function row with Touch ID.
And, of course,
the new Air has a spacious,
industry-leading Force Touch trackpad.
And when it comes to performance,
M2 takes it even further.
So applying filters and effects
in apps like Photoshop
is up to 20% faster than before
and a massive five times faster
for customers that haven't yet upgraded
to Apple Silicon.
And for intensive workloads like editing
complex timelines in Final Cut Pro,
performance is nearly 40% faster
than the previous Air.
Thanks to the power efficiency of M2,
all these capabilities are built into
a silent, fan-less design.
And even with a larger display
and increased performance,
the Air delivers the same great
all-day battery life
with up to 18 hours of video playback.
There's also some new charging options,
including a compact power adapter
with two USB-C ports
so you can charge two devices at once.
And for the first time,
the Air supports fast charge
with an available 67W adapter.
So you can charge
up to 50% in just 30 minutes.
So that's the all-new, amazingly portable
and powerful MacBook Air.
It's thinner, lighter, and faster
with a durable unibody design,
bigger display,
better camera, all-day battery life,
and four beautiful finishes.
It's everything you could want
in a new MacBook Air.
Now, before I hand it back to John,
let's see it in action.
♪ ♪
John: We're so excited
to bring M2 to MacBook Air,
the world's best-selling laptop.
Only with Apple Silicon can you build
such a thin and light notebook
with a fan-less design
and this combination
of performance and capabilities.
But that's not all we have for you today.
M2 is coming to another Mac,
which is actually the world's
second-best-selling laptop:
the 13-inch MacBook Pro.
It's our most portable pro notebook,
and users love the performance it delivers
in its compact design.
Now with M2,
you get even more capabilities
in the same great form factor.
With a faster 8-core CPU
and 10-core GPU,
working with RAW images
in apps like Affinity Photo
is nearly 40% faster
than the previous generation.
And over three times faster
if you're upgrading from a model
without Apple Silicon.
And playing graphics intensive games
like Baldur's Gate III
is also nearly 40% faster
than the previous 13-inch Pro.
With an active cooling system,
the MacBook Pro is designed
to sustain its pro performance.
And thanks to M2, it also supports
up to 24GB of unified memory.
Along with 50% more memory bandwidth,
multitasking and working with
large assets is super fluid.
With support for ProRes encode
and decode in M2's media engine,
you can convert
your video projects to ProRes
nearly three times faster than before.
MacBook Pro also delivers
phenomenal battery life,
with up to 20 hours of video playback.
So that's
the powerful 13-inch MacBook Pro.
With the incredible performance of M2,
ProRes acceleration,
up to 24GB of memory,
and up to 20 hours of battery life,
our most portable Pro notebook
gets even better.
Both the Air and the Pro also support
our environmental goals.
They use 100% recycled rare earth elements
in many components,
are free of numerous harmful substances,
and meet Apple's high standards
for energy efficiency.
The all-new MacBook Air starts
at $1199
and just $1099 for education.
The powerful 13-inch MacBook Pro
starts at $1299
and $1199 for education.
And they'll be available next month.
And the MacBook Air with M1
stays in the lineup at $999
and just $899 for education.
We're thrilled to bring M2
to the world's two most popular laptops,
the MacBook Air
and 13-inch MacBook Pro.
And they join the even more powerful
14 and 16-inch MacBook Pro
with M1 Pro and M1 Max
to round out the most amazing lineup
of Macs we've ever offered,
and continue our tremendous pace
of innovation for the Mac.
Now, back to Craig.
Craig: We're really excited
about these new Macs
with the next generation of Apple Silicon.
And the powerful software
that drives the experience is macOS.
So let's talk about what's new.
Kyle: Jump! Sit!
Craig?
Craig: Sorry, Kyle. Wrong door.
♪ ♪
macOS plays a critical role
in our lives
as we work, collaborate with colleagues,
family, and friends,
create and organize
what's important to us,
and so much more.
This year, we focused on making the
core things you do with macOS even better,
delivering new ways to be productive
and take advantage
of the capability of your
other devices with Continuity.
So what should we call it?
Well, that brings us
to the latest exploits
of Apple's crack product marketing team.
They've been absolutely riding high
since their naming coup on M1 and M2,
and needless to say, they were exhausted.
But after their requisite three-month
rejuvenation retreat in Monterey,
with their chakras now
in complete alignment,
the team once again piled
into their macOS naming microbus
and wove their way down Highway 1.
Chasing the vibrant display
of colorful California wildflowers,
they finally came to rest
where stunning surf meets lush
alluvial plains,
in beautiful Ventura.
macOS Ventura enriches so many
of the ways we use our Macs.
So let's jump in.
A key part of the Mac experience
is helping you be productive and creative,
which can often mean having
a lot of windows open at once.
And the more you do,
the more overwhelming this can become.
We all want the perfect mix–
to focus on our work without distractions
and to easily move between tasks.
This year, we have a new way
to automatically keep everything organized
and give you quick access to your windows.
It's called Stage Manager.
Let's see how it works.
When you're working on the Mac,
it's really easy
to find yourself
with lots of open windows.
Now, the Mac has great tools
like Mission Control
to help you find the window
that you're looking for,
but with so many open windows,
it can feel like you never really escape
all the clutter.
With Stage Manager,
you can focus on the app you're using
without the distractions,
and it's easy to get started.
Let's activate Stage Manager
from Control Center.
As you see, it automatically arranges
all my windows for me off to the side
and puts the app I'm currently
working with front and center.
When I bring forward a different app,
like clicking on Mail here in the Dock,
you'll see that it's brought to the stage
and Safari gracefully moves
over to the left
with my other recent apps.
When I click on Safari,
it retakes the stage,
and Mail moves back to the left.
You'll notice that for an app
with multiple open windows,
like Pages here, Stage Manager gathers
all the windows together
in a single pile.
When I click, I get the top one,
and if I want a different window,
I can cycle through them
just by clicking.
It's really convenient.
Of course,
just as you would expect on a Mac,
I can have overlapping windows and
multiple apps open at the same time too.
It's really easy to group apps together.
Here I'll just drag in Notes
and pair it with my Pages window.
This is so great
when I'm working on projects
that involve a specific group of windows
like planning a trip
with these three apps here.
And if I go back to my previous group,
Stage Manager keeps my windows arranged
just as I left them.
I love working this way.
Of course, like many Mac users,
I often want to get at files
on my desktop,
and with Stage Manager,
we've made that easier than ever.
I'm working on this Final Cut project,
and I want to pull in a couple of files.
With just a click on my desktop,
my windows clear the stage
and my files are revealed.
Now I can grab these title graphics
and drag them over
to my Final Cut window.
I'll just drop them in right here,
and boom.
So that's a quick look at multitasking
with Stage Manager,
Another part of the Mac experience
that helps you do more is Spotlight.
This year we have a big update
that delivers a more consistent
and powerful experience
across our platforms.
Spotlight is great
for doing all kinds of things,
like quickly launching an app
or starting a search.
And now you can peek at a result
in Quick Look
with a tap on the space bar.
Spotlight can now also find images
from your photo library,
across the system, and on the web.
And using Live Text,
you can search the text inside the image.
You can also take actions
like starting a timer
or running a shortcut
right from Spotlight.
It's also a great way to get information,
now leveraging the full window
for richer results.
For musicians, you'll see their albums,
key facts, news, and more.
It's also great for movies, TV shows,
and actors,
businesses, and sports.
Rich results and the ability
to take actions right from Spotlight
are also coming to iOS and iPadOS.
Now, speaking of iOS,
we wanted to make Spotlight even easier
to discover and access,
so we added it right
to the bottom of the Home Screen.
With just a tap, you can use Spotlight
to launch an app,
find a contact, or start a search.
These updates
make Spotlight more productive,
helping you find
what you're looking for faster.
Next, let's turn to an app that many of us
use to communicate every day.
To take you through it,
here's Darin.
Darin Adler:
Of course, we're talking about Mail.
Mail is central to how
so many of us communicate.
This year, we have great updates
that will help you be more productive,
starting with some
highly-requested features.
Undo send lets you pull an email back
a few moments after hitting Send.
Scheduled send, so your emails arrive
at the perfect moment.
Follow-up suggestions will automatically
remind you to follow up
if you haven't received a response.
And Remind Me makes it easy
to come back to a message
at a particular date and time.
Next, let's talk Search.
This is the biggest overhaul
of Search in Mail we've done in years,
leveraging the latest
state-of-the-art techniques
to deliver more accurate
and complete results.
When you click Search,
you'll see recently shared documents,
links, and more.
The moment you start typing,
with each letter,
you instantly see suggestions.
If you make a typo,
Search is one step ahead,
only showing results
for the correct spelling.
And if Search knows a synonym,
it'll look for that too.
And all these new features are also coming
to iPadOS and iOS.
And that's Mail.
Next up is another app most of us spend
a ton of time in every day:
Safari.
With macOS Ventura,
Safari is the world's fastest browser,
rendering the most complex websites
with incredible speed.
Safari is the most power-efficient
browser on Mac,
letting you do more on a single charge
than any other browser.
And of course, Safari is a trailblazer
in protecting your privacy on the web,
with features like
Intelligent Tracking Protection
and Privacy Report.
Safari has a legacy of introducing
key web technologies
that elevate the web experience
for everyone.
Safari's pioneering support for HTML5
transformed the video experience
on the web, resulting in higher-quality
playback and increased battery life.
And Safari continues to deliver support
for the latest web technologies
and standards for web developers,
including all of these
added in just the last year,
like more fluid web animations,
new browser extension types,
and support for
the push notifications standards.
These enable more immersive
and engaging web content for our users.
And now Safari has a new way to share
your favorite content with others
with Shared Tab Groups.
Whether you're planning a trip
with friends or shopping for a couch
with your partner,
you can share all the tabs in one place.
And when they find something great,
they can add tabs too.
You can see which tabs your friends
are looking at live,
and using built-in collaboration,
you can easily connect in real time
over Messages or FaceTime.
It's so easy to discover the web together.
And next, we have a new way
to make the web a safer place.
We rely on passwords
to protect our most private accounts.
While Safari helps users create
the strongest passwords possible,
there are still ways
accounts can be compromised.
Hackers can use social engineering
techniques like phishing
to trick users into giving up passwords.
They can also breach a website directly
to get access to all the passwords
stored on its server.
That's why we've helped create
a next generation credential
that's more secure, easier to use,
and aims to replace passwords for good.
We call them passkeys.
Passkeys use powerful
cryptographic techniques
and the biometrics built into your device
to keep accounts safe.
To create a passkey, just use TouchID
or FaceID to authenticate,
and you're done.
When users create a passkey,
a unique digital key is created
that only works
for the site it was created for.
Passkeys can't be phished.
Since the passkey never leaves
your devices,
hackers can't trick you into sharing it
on a fake website.
And passkeys can't be leaked because
nothing secret is kept on a web server.
We've designed passkeys to work in apps
as easily as they do on the web.
Passkeys are securely synced across
Apple devices using iCloud Keychain
and are instantly available on Mac,
iPhone, iPad, and Apple TV.
We've been working with industry leaders
in the FIDO alliance
including Google and Microsoft,
to ensure that passkeys work seamlessly
cross-platform.
With a passkey, you'll be able to walk up
to a non-Apple device
and sign in to a website or app
using just your iPhone.
The transition away from passwords
will be a journey,
and we look forward to working with
developers on the password-less future.
And that's Safari.
Now back over to you, Craig.
Craig: We think these updates
to Mail and Safari
will help you be productive
and browse the web
in new and safer ways.
Next, let's have some fun
and talk about gaming.
We're at a point where two things
are really coming together.
First, Apple Silicon
has changed everything.
It's taking the graphics performance
of every new Mac to new heights,
giving Macs the power to run
the most demanding games, with ease.
Second,
the Mac is more popular than ever,
and it's a huge and fast-growing
opportunity for game developers.
And since we have a unified silicon
architecture spanning from iPhone and iPad
all the way up to M1 Ultra,
game developers can scale the quality
and performance of their titles
across the entire line.
Another key part of a great gaming
experience is the software that powers it.
To tell you what's new, here's Jeremy.
Jeremy Sandmel:
We continue to improve Metal.
It's the software that powers
hardware-accelerated graphics
on all our platforms.
And now, Metal 3 brings
new features that will unleash
the full potential of Apple Silicon
for years to come.
Gaming at maximum resolution
and quality looks awesome.
And to help game developers
increase the performance of realistic
and immersive graphics,
we're introducing MetalFX Upscaling,
which enables developers to render rich,
visually complex scenes even faster.
It works by rendering smaller,
less compute-intensive frames
and then applies high-quality spatial
upscaling and temporal anti-aliasing.
And it's so cool.
No Man's Sky,
coming to Mac later this year,
will be one of the first games
to use MetalFX Upscaling.
The frame rate increases, giving you that
responsive feel, and it looks beautiful.
Another area we're improving
is game loading.
Games continue to push the boundaries
and appear more realistic than ever before
by using richer textures
and more geometric detail,
which can take a while to load.
So Metal 3 adds a new fast
resource loading API
that minimizes wait time
by providing a more direct path
from storage to the unified memory system
so the GPU can more quickly access
high-quality textures
and buffers without waiting.
Metal 3 and Apple Silicon enable
even more immersive visuals,
faster performance, and quicker loading.
This really is a new day
for gaming on the Mac.
But don't take our word for it.
Let's hear from the team that has created
the acclaimed Resident Evil Village.
We are so excited it's coming to the Mac.
To tell you more, we are delighted
to introduce Ijuin-san,
manager of Capcom's
Advanced Technical Research Division.
♪ ♪
Craig: Thank you, Ijuin-san.
Next, let's talk about Continuity.
Continuity is all about giving you
a seamless experience across devices.
Features like Universal Control,
AirPlay, and Handoff
allow you to always use
the right device for the moment.
And today,
we're extending Handoff to FaceTime.
Now picture this: you answer
a FaceTime call on your iPhone
while you're away from your desk.
When you get home and bring
your iPhone up close to your Mac,
your Mac automatically recognizes
the call on your iPhone,
and you can move it
to your Mac seamlessly,
giving you a bigger view
to continue the conversation.
You can handoff calls in any direction
between your devices,
so you'll always be able to join the call
from the right one.
We also have exciting news
about another Continuity feature,
which pairs the best camera you own
with the large displays on Mac.
We spend a lot of time in front
of our Macs with our cameras on.
Our webcams have become an integral part
of work, school, and play.
And now, with Continuity Camera,
you can use iPhone as your webcam.
It's powered by the advanced capabilities
of the iPhone camera system,
letting you do things that were never
before possible with a webcam.
Let me show you how it works.
Now, I'm just gonna pop this stand
on my iPhone,
and attach it to my display.
Let's launch FaceTime.
You can see my Mac
automatically detects my iPhone
and uses it as the camera.
I don't even have to wake up my iPhone.
This all works wirelessly
so there's nothing to plug in.
So to try this out, let's call a friend
in the design studio.
Johnnie Manzari: Hi, Craig!
Craig: Hey, Johnnie!
Are you up for helping me give a demo
of Continuity Camera?
Johnnie: Sure, I'm using it right now.
with my iPhone and Pro Display XDR.
You know, one thing I love about
Continuity Camera is Center Stage.
I can move around and Center Stage
will keep me in the frame.
I'll frequently pair that
with Portrait Mode
to blur the background
with that beautiful boca.
Craig: Yeah, I've loved
having these features on my iPad,
and it's great that we can now
use them with any Mac.
Johnnie: For sure.
A new one people are gonna love
is Studio Light.
Check this out.
It brightens my face
and darkens the background.
Craig: Hey, that looks great.
It's almost like you have a ring-light.
Johnnie: It is perfect
for tough lighting conditions,
like if I'm ever sitting in front
of a window.
Okay, now I wanna show
my favorite new feature, Desk View.
You can see the work that's on my desk,
and it keeps me in the picture.
It is amazing.
Take a look.
It looks like I have
a dedicated overhead camera,
but this is Desk View
creating both of these views
from the one ultra-wide camera
on my iPhone
using some very powerful image processing.
I didn't even need to adjust my phone.
Desk View's gonna be great
for sharing new designs with my team.
I can even use it
to show my nephew a new card trick.
Craig: This is gonna be so cool.
Well, hey, Johnnie, thanks for helping us
give the quick demo.
Johnnie: No problem.
I'll talk to you later.
Craig: In addition to FaceTime,
you can use Continuity Camera
with any macOS videoconferencing app
like Zoom, Teams, Webex, and more.
And we're working with Belkin
to offer beautiful stands
to hold your iPhone
at the perfect height and angle.
These will be available later this year.
And since so many of you with a Mac
already have an iPhone,
these great capabilities come
with the devices you already own.
That's the magic of Continuity.
And that's macOS Ventura,
a feature-packed release that brings
new tools for managing windows,
smart new features for Mail, Safari,
and games,
and magical new Continuity features.
Now let's turn to iPadOS.
♪ ♪
Our vision for iPadOS
is to create a distinct experience
that's built on the best of iOS,
like security, mobility,
and an intuitive touch-first interface,
with powerful capabilities from macOS,
like multitasking and trackpad support,
combined with features like Apple Pencil
that are uniquely iPad.
All of this comes together
to deliver our most versatile device.
This year in iPadOS 16,
we have a big release
that's going to take this versatility
even further.
Starting with a host of features that
you heard about earlier in iOS and macOS
that are going to be great on iPad,
like Shared Photo Library,
Shared Tab Groups
and Passkeys in Safari,
and a big update to Mail.
We're also bringing Weather to iPad,
taking full advantage of the stunning
display with beautiful animations
like these gently moving clouds,
heavy snowfall, and driving rain.
And all of these modules are tappable
to access detailed information.
And for developers,
we're announcing WeatherKit
so they can build weather into their apps.
iPadOS 16 also includes new ways
to collaborate with others,
more capable apps,
and new features for Pro users
that take advantage
of the power of the M1 chip.
So let's start with collaboration,
which often begins in Messages
when you're asked
to pass along a document.
Of course, you could send a copy,
but now you can also instantly kick off
a collaboration
when you send something
with the Share Sheet.
This makes initiating collaboration
across the system
as easy as sending a link,
and means a conversation with your
collaborators is always just a tap away.
Let me show you how it works.
So let's tap in to Messages.
I've been talking to the team
about an upcoming offsite,
and we've been using this conversation
to figure out the details.
Now, it looks like a message just came in
from Lopp,
and he wants to catch up on the latest.
Over here in Pages,
I've been collecting our ideas.
I want to share this with the group.
In the past, when I'd tap Share,
I'd end up sharing a copy.
But now, you'll notice I can start
collaboration right here.
And what's great is, I don't need
to type in a bunch of names
or email addresses.
When I select a Messages group,
everyone gets added automatically.
Let's go ahead and send it.
This makes it way easier
to collaborate with people
you're already communicating with.
Everyone can immediately join
and start making edits,
like the ones you see here.
And back in the Messages conversation,
I even get a notice of any changes
I might have missed.
When you collaborate this way,
your document is connected
to the conversation.
The group appears in the toolbar,
and I can kick off communication
right from here.
I can get back
to the messages conversation
or initiate a FaceTime call.
Let's go ahead and call the group.
Hey, everyone!
Michael Lopp: Hey, Craig.
Craig: Hey, I saw that a few of you
were in the document.
Does anyone have any other ideas
for the offsite?
Lopp: Yeah, I've been thinking about it,
and I've been collecting a few tabs.
I'm gonna share them right now with you
in Safari.
Craig: Thanks, Lopp.
This year, you can start collaborating
with the group right in FaceTime.
You can see that Lopp just invited me
to collaborate on a set of tabs in Safari.
I'm gonna go ahead and accept his invite,
and now, I can get to them in Safari.
Just like with the Pages document,
everyone in the group
automatically has access.
I can see Anne and Mindy
joining the tab group,
and I can even see which tabs people are
looking at right in the tab bar.
Looks like Mindy is checking out kayaking.
Lopp: Found a few more.
Check these out.
Craig: When Lopp adds tabs,
they instantly appear
so we can all check them out.
Let's see, we already did this last year,
but ziplining looks cool!
All right, team, let's wrap this up
and update our document
with the latest ideas.
Looks like Anne is updating the text,
and Mindy just dropped in an image,
so we're all set.
So that's a quick look
at some of the new ways
you can work together with collaboration
with iPadOS 16.
In addition to Pages and Safari,
these new collaboration features
will work with a variety of apps,
like Notes and Keynote.
And for developers, there's a new API
to integrate collaboration in their apps,
and these features will also be coming
to iOS and macOS.
Of course,
when you're collaborating live,
sometimes you want a space
where you can brainstorm
and capture ideas as they strike.
So today, we're giving you a sneak peek
at a brand-new app called Freeform
coming later this year.
To tell you all about it,
here's Elizabeth.
Elizabeth Reid: We have so many
great ways to collaborate,
but up until now,
you didn't have a space to work in,
a place for group sessions,
project planning,
home renovations, or school projects.
Now, you can be on a FaceTime call,
and with a tap, you're all collaborating
live on a Freeform board.
You can add almost anything to a board.
It's perfect for brainstorming sessions,
jotting down notes,
sharing files,
or even creating diagrams with others.
It's flexible,
limited only by your imagination.
As others begin adding their thoughts,
you can see their live cursors
showing you right where they're working.
And if someone is in
another part of Freeform,
you can just tap to jump straight
to where they are on the board.
And any time you need more space,
move around simply using touch,
or focus on what's really important
with a pinch.
Of course, with a full complement
of drawing tools,
you can sketch or write a note
anywhere you'd like with Apple Pencil.
And with all the powerful tools
to create content on iPad,
Freeform is a great place
to pull it all together,
including photos, video, audio,
documents, PDFs, web links,
pretty much anything you need to work with
can be brought onto your board.
And you can preview right in line,
including multipage documents
and high-resolution videos,
giving you everything you need
to bring your ideas to life
right at your fingertips.
And that's a sneak peek at Freeform.
Back to you, Craig.
Craig: Freeform is going to be
a great way
to brainstorm your ideas with others,
and we're building it right into iPadOS,
macOS, and iOS later this year.
Of course, the versatility of iPad
means you can seamlessly move
from being productive to gaming.
With its stunning display,
built-in sensors,
and support for your
favorite game controller,
iPad provides a great gaming experience.
And the M1 chip
delivers high-performance graphics,
enabling immersive games
like Divinity: Original Sin 2.
In iPadOS 16,
we have some great updates to gaming,
starting with Metal 3,
which brings the same MetalFX upscaling
and fast resource loading API to iPad
that we talked about earlier with macOS.
There's also a new API
that lets games download
large assets in the background,
enabling you to multitask
while the download completes.
Another important aspect to gaming on iPad
is how it brings us together.
Tens of thousands of games
use Game Center to help us
play with our friends
or compete against each other.
It's easy to jump right in and play
without creating a new account,
using your Game Center profile.
You can find friends to play with,
compare scores on leaderboards,
and track progress through achievements.
And now, we're bringing Activity
to the Game Center dashboard.
You can see what your friends are playing,
highlights of their achievements,
and even find out
when they beat your high score,
so you know when it's time
to take your game to the next level
and get back on top.
And all of this activity appears
on your Game Center profile.
Game Center has always supported
playing together in real time.
Now, SharePlay makes it simple
to join and play.
In a multiplayer game using Game Center,
just start a SharePlay session
and bring your friends right in.
These new Game Center features
will be coming to an update
to iPadOS 16 later this year,
and we're also bringing them
to iOS and macOS.
The versatility of iPad
makes it great for so many things,
and a big part of that is apps.
This year, we're continuing our work
to make iPad apps more capable
with desktop-class apps.
While many iPad apps
have their origins in iOS,
over the years, they've taken on
their own unique capabilities,
optimized for the iPad's larger display.
In iPadOS 16,
we scoured the entire system,
adding enhancements across the board,
from system elements and interactions
to new features you use on Mac
and want on iPad.
Let me highlight a few of them.
Undo/redo across the system,
availability view in Calendar,
find and merge cards
and create lists in Contacts,
and we have a big update to Files,
with some of the most requested features,
such as the ability to change
file extensions,
view folder size, and more.
We've also added system-wide features
that deliver improvements across apps,
starting with a redesigned
find and replace experience
that works in-line.
A document menu in apps
like Files, Pages, and Keynote
that reveals common actions
you may want to take,
such as duplicate,
rename, export, and print.
And for the first time ever,
customizable toolbars in iPadOS
so you can add the tools
that matter to you most.
And for developers,
we've created new APIs,
so they can build these capabilities
right into their own apps.
These features will help you
be more productive.
And we have another feature
for Mac that will be great
for creative pros on iPad.
And that is reference color.
The Liquid Retina XDR display
in our latest 12.9-inch iPad Pro
is great for professional color workflows.
And with iPadOS 16,
we're introducing Reference Mode,
which meets the color requirements
in workflows like review and approve,
color grading, and compositing,
where accurate colors
and consistent image quality are critical.
So whether you prefer using iPad Pro
as a standalone device
or as a second display with Sidecar,
Reference Mode provides
a consistent reference workflow
across your pro devices,
making iPad Pro an indispensable tool
for creative professionals.
Now, I want to turn our attention
to a set of features
enabled by the performance of the M1 chip
in our latest iPad Pro and iPad Air.
Features for people who push
the versatility of iPad to the limit.
Pros are always wanting
more space to work with,
so we're adding
a new display scaling setting,
which allows you to increase
the pixel density of the display
so you can view more in your apps,
which is particularly helpful
when using Split View.
We also want to enable you
to do more in apps.
Our latest iPad Air and iPad Pro
come with a ton of ultra-fast memory
and storage.
iPadOS 16 adds support
for virtual memory swap,
meaning your iPad storage can be used
to expand the available memory
for all apps
and delivers up to 16 GB of memory
to the most demanding apps.
With technologies like display scaling
and virtual memory swap,
we have the foundation for a big leap
forward in user experience,
one that can change how our Pro users
get work done on iPad.
So we're bringing Stage Manager,
our latest windowing system
that you just saw in macOS, to iPadOS.
Stage Manager takes multitasking
on iPad to a whole new level
by making it more nimble and unlocking
full external display support.
I'd like to show it to you now.
Today on iPad, when you use apps,
you get the full screen experience
that we're all familiar with,
like in Photos here.
With Stage Manager activated,
I can now resize windows,
exposing a powerful new way
to work with apps on iPad.
And the Dock is visible,
so I can easily get to all my apps.
Let's open Music.
You'll notice that all my recently used
apps appear on the left,
so switching between them is really fast.
And Stage Manager gives me
powerful new layout capabilities
to create my ideal workspace.
For the first time on iPad,
I can work with overlapping windows.
I'm gonna drag Messages
alongside Calendar here,
and Stage Manager automatically moves
Calendar gently off to the side
as I bring it to the stage.
And if I move Messages to the left,
Stage Manager repositions Calendar for me
automatically.
And like you saw earlier,
I can resize windows
and arrange everything
just the way I want.
And it gets even better
when I plug my iPad
into an external display.
My wallpaper beautifully fills
the entire display,
and I can move my cursor to it
from my iPad.
I have the Dock here too,
so let's go ahead and launch Keynote.
When I do,
I once again enter Stage Manager,
now on an even bigger canvas.
All of that additional screen real estate
is so useful
when working on a presentation in Keynote.
And it's amazing when you're working
with a set of apps.
I can create groups of three
and even four windows.
This is just incredibly powerful.
Between my iPad and my external display,
I can have up to eight apps
running onscreen simultaneously.
And I can take advantage of the unique
capabilities of each of these displays.
For instance,
I'm working on this Keynote document,
and I want to add a drawing from Procreate
here on my iPad.
I can use Apple Pencil
to add a finishing touch
to my drawing.
And now I can jump back into the gallery
and then drag and drop across displays
and into my deck.
And that's a quick look at Stage Manager.
It's an entirely new way to multitask
with multiple overlapping windows,
flexible window sets,
fast app switching,
and full external display support.
And that's iPadOS 16,
a big release with exciting updates
to many of the built-in apps;
Weather app comes to iPad,
new ways to collaborate
and be productive,
great features for pro users,
including Stage Manager,
and so much more.
Now, back to Tim.
Tim: Thank you, Craig.
And thanks to all of our presenters.
What an exciting day of announcements!
We introduced the all-new,
redesigned MacBook Air,
with its super-thin enclosure,
Liquid Retina display,
MagSafe, beautiful new finishes,
and supercharged by M2,
our next generation of Apple Silicon.
Along with a powerful new
13-inch MacBook Pro,
also supercharged by M2.
And we pushed our software platforms
forward in some incredible new ways.
Introducing features and capabilities
that will enable our developers
to do amazing work and provide our users
with exciting new experiences.
Our OS releases will be available
as developer betas today,
and each of them will have a public beta
next month.
All of these OS releases
will be available to our users this fall.
I'm confident that our incredible products
and innovative platforms
will inspire developers
to do the very best work of their lives,
enabling all of us to do
even more amazing things.
We hope you enjoyed today's event,
and we have a huge week ahead.
We will be offering
a comprehensive online experience,
starting with
a Platform State of the Union
for those developers who want take
a deeper dive into our announcements.
And there will be more than 175 sessions,
as well as one-on-one labs
with Apple engineers
and digital lounges.
All of this is available for free
to all our developers
to help them get the most
out of the conference.
Thank you for joining us,
and let's have a great WWDC!
♪ ♪
.