♪ ♪
Tim Cook: Good morning.
We're so glad you could join us.
At Apple, we're fortunate
to be surrounded by people
who strive to innovate together
to create products and experiences
that enrich people's lives,
products that are intuitive
and easy to use,
that have a unique integration
of hardware and software,
and that are incredibly personal.
Today, we're here to talk
about three products
that have become essential in our lives:
iPhone, AirPods, and Apple Watch.
They're always with you,
useful whenever and wherever
you need them,
and are designed
to work seamlessly together.
On their own, each is industry leading.
Together, they provide
a magical experience.
With one tap,
AirPods are instantly set up
and ready to work
with your iPhone and Apple Watch,
and automatic switching allows sound
to move seamlessly
between any of your Apple devices.
There's also incredible integration
between iPhone and Apple Watch.
Together they provide the convenience
of having your notifications
and messages on your wrist
and available with just a glance.
You can seamlessly hand off phone calls
between your iPhone and Apple Watch,
and you can set your destination
on your iPhone
and your Apple Watch will help guide you
along the way.
Users can even get their health
and fitness data from Apple Watch
and see it on the Health app
on their iPhone.
These are just a few examples
of the unique and powerful ways
our hardware and software
are designed to work together,
enhancing and enriching the experiences
you have with these products.
This type of integration is something
only Apple can do.
And today we're going to make
these products and these experiences
even better.
Let's get started
by talking about Apple Watch.
Apple Watch has become
an essential companion.
It's always with you, allowing you
to do so much right from your wrist.
It keeps you connected to the things
you care about most,
encourages you to stay active,
and monitors your health
and gets help when you need it.
And I've received thousands of letters
from customers
writing about their personal experiences
using Apple Watch.
I'd like to share just a few of
those stories with you now.
Dear, Mr. Cook...
Dear, Tim...
Hello, Mr. Cook...
I'm writing to you
from Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
I'm writing you from Atlanta, Georgia.
I am a 27-year-old high school teacher.
I'm a senior in high school.
I only had the watch
for two or three weeks.
I was viewing a movie with my wife
in our family room...
I was having lunch at one of the spiciest
restaurants in San Diego...
It was a typical summer night.
I looked around the corner,
and a bear was staring right at me.
I was doing what we call
a dump and return
when I slipped headfirst
into the compactor.
I was skating on a frozen river
when the ice gave out.
The door closed, and everything went dark.
My longtime friend
started grasping his chest.
I was fighting to catch my breath.
I used the watch to study my pulse,
and it was wildly erratic.
Things escalated quickly from there.
I was getting tired, and I could tell
hypothermia was setting in.
I go to grab my phone,
but my pockets were empty.
I didn't have my phone on me.
As I was trying to figure out what to do,
I looked down and saw my watch.
I placed my Apple Watch on his wrist,
and I couldn't believe my eyes.
An atrial fibrillation notification
popped up.
Holy cow.
Holy moly.
I looked down at my Apple Watch,
and my heart rate was
187 beats per minute.
I drove him to the hospital
where he was treated for a heart condition
he wasn't aware he had.
Dear, Apple,
my dad was flying our small plane
to Vermont.
I was asleep in the backseat.
I woke up when we were crashing
into the tops of the trees.
The plane broke into six pieces,
and we were miles away from civilization
in the freezing cold.
Then, all of a sudden,
my Apple Watch started ringing.
I forgot I was wearing it.
I told my grandma
that I'd have to call her back,
and I immediately called 911.
I whispered to my co-teacher,
"I need to go to the emergency room
right now."
We were advised to head directly
to the emergency room.
I held down the button and whispered,
"Siri, call 911."
I dialed 911,
and that sucker started ringing,
and I was smiling like a brand-new baby.
Rescuers arrived in minutes.
If I hadn't had the Apple Watch,
things could have been much worse.
I'm so grateful.
From now on,
I'll never leave the house without it.
My doctor said, "It was your watch
that saved your life."
Thanks for helping save my friend's life.
Since the heart event was without
other symptoms,
clearly,
the watch was my only call to action
and my only link to the fine medical care
that saved my life.
With deep gratitude, Erik.
Thank you, Hannah.
Sinceramente, Marcos.
Bill.
Taryn.
Sincerely, Dr. Korn.
All the best, Shaae.
There are so many ways Apple Watch
improves peoples' lives.
These are the reasons we do what we do.
And this year we're introducing
our best Apple Watch lineup yet,
by far!
To tell you more, here's Jeff.
♪ ♪
Jeff Williams:
Each year, Apple Watch sets a new standard
for what a smartwatch should be.
And this continuous innovation has made it
the number-one-selling smartwatch
in the world for seven years running.
And we're so excited about what's next.
♪ ♪
This is the new Apple Watch Series 8.
It has all of the things you love
about Apple Watch plus even more.
Series 8 is beautifully designed
and packed with the most advanced sensors
and technology.
It features a big, brilliant,
Always-On display with narrow borders
that push the screen right to the edge.
Detailed watch faces
like the new Lunar, Astronomy,
Metropolitan, and Modular look stunning.
And it's so bright that text
and complications are easy to read
even when your wrist is down.
And Series 8 is durable.
It's swim proof,
dust proof, and crack resistant.
To tell you more about Series 8,
here's Deidre.
♪ ♪
Deidre Caldbeck: Series 8 is designed
to keep you connected
to the people and things
that you care about most.
It motivates you to stay active and fit.
With Workouts and Fitness+ there are so
many ways to exercise using Apple Watch.
Series 8 helps keep you safe
with fall detection,
emergency SOS, and Medical ID.
It has sleep tracking,
Cycle Tracking, and Mindfulness
to give you insights into your body
and help you maintain healthy habits.
With best-in-class health sensors
that enable ECG,
irregular rhythm notifications,
and blood oxygen,
it is the ultimate device
for a healthy life.
And now, Series 8 brings
even more features
for health, safety, and connectivity,
starting with an innovative
new temperature sensor
that takes our commitment
to women's health even further.
And here's Sumbul to tell you about it.
♪ ♪
Dr. Sumbul Ahmad Desai: Women's health
impacts more than just women.
It also impacts their families
and communities.
And menstrual cycles are key
to a woman's health,
so much so that many physicians
regard them as a vital sign.
We added Cycle Tracking three years ago,
and it has helped tens of millions
gain deeper insights
into their cycles and overall health.
This year, we're introducing a suite
of advanced Cycle Tracking features,
including valuable information about
a critical aspect of women's health:
ovulation.
As always, we build our health features
with two fundamental principles.
First, they're developed
using scientifically validated insights,
and second, privacy is at the core,
designed to keep your data
secure and private.
Utilizing the new temperature sensor
in Apple Watch Series 8,
you can now receive a retrospective
estimate of when you ovulated.
Series 8 has a unique two-sensor design.
There's one temperature sensor
on the back crystal, near your skin,
and another just under the display.
This design improves accuracy
by reducing bias
from the outside environment.
Nighttime wrist temperature
can be a good indicator
of overall body temperature
because while you sleep,
your blood vessels dilate,
increasing blood flow to your limbs.
Overnight, Series 8 samples
your wrist temperature every 5 seconds
and it can detect changes
as small as 0.1° Celsius.
In the Health app,
you'll be able to see nightly shifts
from your baseline temperature,
which can be caused
by things like exercise, jet lag,
alcohol, or illness.
But tracking temperature changes
is even more useful for those who ovulate,
because cyclical patterns can reveal
the biphasic shift.
The biphasic shift is an increase in
body temperature that occurs in response
to changing hormones,
and it can indicate ovulation.
If you're trying to conceive,
knowing if and when you ovulated
can inform your family planning
and conversations
with your health care provider.
Today, the most common way
to track the biphasic shift
is manually with a thermometer
and a journal.
Series 8 makes this much easier
and more convenient
by providing new, automatic
retrospective ovulation estimates.
Further advancing Cycle Tracking,
all users on iOS 16 and watchOS 9
can be now notified
of possible cycle deviations
based on logged cycle data.
You may not realize that common
cycle deviations, like persistent spotting
or prolonged periods, can be symptoms
of serious health conditions
like fibroids, thyroid disorders, or PCOS.
That's why it's so important
to know when they occur.
The temperature sensing capability
on Series 8, plus heart rate,
and logged cycle data come together
to give you a detailed view of your cycle,
all of which can be easily shared
with your healthcare provider
to facilitate more informed conversations.
We believe privacy
is a fundamental human right
and that your health data
is yours and yours alone.
Your Cycle Tracking data is encrypted
on your device
and only accessible with your passcode,
Touch ID, or Face ID.
When using iOS and watchOS
with the default two-factor authentication
and a passcode,
Health app data synced to iCloud
is encrypted end-to-end,
meaning that Apple does not have the key
to decrypt the data
and therefore cannot read it.
Only with your explicit permission
can your health data be shared.
And you have granular control
over the types of data you share
and who you share it with.
Women's health is critically important,
and we're proud to bring these new
advanced cycle tracking capabilities
to Apple Watch Series 8.
Now back to Deidre.
Deidre: Safety features on Apple Watch,
like fall detection and emergency SOS,
have helped save lives.
There's another emergency situation
you never want to find yourself in,
and that's a car crash.
According to the US Department
of Transportation,
almost half of the worst crashes
occur in rural areas,
and the majority involve
only a single vehicle.
So we built an innovative new feature
to help in situations like this.
Introducing Crash Detection.
Apple Watch Series 8 can detect
if you were in a severe car crash.
When a crash is detected,
it will automatically connect you
with emergency services,
provide your location,
and notify your emergency contacts.
And to tell you more, here's Ron.
♪ ♪
Ron Huang: In order to detect
the unique forces of a car crash,
we developed two new motion sensors
for Series 8:
an improved 3-axis gyroscope
and a high-g-force accelerometer.
The new accelerometer is capable
of measuring up to 256 g's,
allowing it to detect
the extreme impacts of a crash.
And it samples motion four times faster–
at over 3,000 times a second–
so it can sense
the precise moment of impact.
With these new technologies,
we built an advanced
sensor fusion algorithm
to deliver accurate Crash Detection.
We started by spending years
studying vehicle impacts
at state-of-the-art crash test labs.
We focused on four main types
of severe crashes:
front impact, side impact,
rear-end collision, and rollovers.
In each crash test, we captured data
from the new gyroscope
and accelerometer
as well as from other sensors in Series 8
including the barometer,
microphone, and GPS.
And then we used machine learning
to incorporate all of these signals
into the algorithm,
which was trained on over 1 million hours
of real-world driving and crash data.
Series 8 can detect crashes
in the most popular types of vehicles
like passenger cars,
SUVs, and pickup trucks.
Crash Detection runs only
when you're driving
and processes data only
around the time of a possible crash,
entirely on your device.
That's Crash Detection
on Apple Watch Series 8.
We truly hope you never need it,
but that you will feel a little bit safer
every time you get in the car.
Now, back to Deidre.
Deidre: Even with the new temperature and
motion sensors working in the background,
Apple Watch Series 8 still has all-day,
18-hour battery life.
But sometimes,
like if you're on a long flight
or without a charger for the night,
you need to preserve battery life.
To help with that,
we're introducing Low Power Mode,
which can give you up to 36 hours
of battery life on a full charge.
Low Power Mode maintains many
of the core features of Apple Watch–
like activity tracking
and fall detection–
while temporarily disabling
other features,
like Always-On display
and auto workout detection,
providing maximum battery savings with
the least impact to the user experience.
Low Power Mode is available on Series 4
and later running watchOS 9.
Cellular models of Series 8
will also support international roaming.
Apple Watch will now be able
to stay connected to your cellular network
while you're traveling abroad.
Simply add your Apple Watch to your iPhone
roaming plan at little or no cost.
By the end of the year,
international roaming will be available
on more than 30 carriers worldwide.
It will be supported on all
cellular models of Apple Watch
from Series 5 onward running watchOS 9.
Apple Watch Series 8 will be available
in four colors of 100% recycled aluminum:
Midnight, Starlight,
Silver, and Product(RED),
and in three stainless steel finishes:
Silver, Gold, and Graphite.
There are also great new colors
across our most popular band styles.
We also have exciting updates
to both Nike bands,
including fresh colors
for the Nike Sport Band
and a new Nike Sport Loop
"Just Do It" woven
right into the textile.
And with watchOS 9,
you can use all Nike watch faces
with any Apple Watch.
There are also two stylish new bands
for Apple Watch Hermès.
"H Diagonal" uses hundreds
of micro-perforations
to create a sporty pattern
of the iconic Hermès H.
And "Gourmette Metal"
features a polished silver chain
wrapping twice around the wrist
for a bold look.
There's also a new
"Hermès Lucky Horse" watch face
that celebrates their equestrian roots.
That's the incredible
new Apple Watch Series 8
with temperature sensing,
retrospective ovulation estimates,
Crash Detection,
and international roaming,
on top of best-in-class health features
like Blood Oxygen,
ECG, and sleep tracking.
It has the latest design that users love
with an edge-to-edge display,
great durability, and fast charging,
and all the new features of watchOS 9.
Apple Watch Series 8 will start
at $399 for GPS
and $499 for cellular.
And with the purchase
of any new Apple Watch,
you'll also get 3 months of Fitness+ free.
You can order today,
and it will be available September 16th.
And that's Apple Watch Series 8.
Now back to Jeff.
Jeff:
I am so incredibly excited about Series 8.
Let's take one more look
at this amazing watch.
So you've taken up running.
Apple Watch has taken up
a few new things as well.
First, it tracked your distance.
Now, it's tracking your stride length.
It learns your favorite route,
then lets you race against yourself.
You're behind.
Yeah, you're behind.
When you're swimming,
it can tell a breaststroke
from a backstroke
from a kickboard.
And when you're done,
it dries itself off.
This isn't a dream.
Your watch can take an ECG.
But if it was a dream,
that watch would track your REM sleep
down to the minute.
It checks your heart rate.
It checks for temperature changes
to estimate when you've ovulated.
It checks out
when you're buying spaghetti.
It could already detect if you fell.
Now the microphone detects
impact noise,
the accelerometer senses
rapid deceleration,
and the barometer measures
a shift in pressure
consistent with an air bag going off.
So it can check if you need help
after a car crash.
And hey, it also shows
your ground contact time.
Amazing.
Have a nice run.
Jeff:
Next, let's talk about Apple Watch SE.
SE has been a huge hit,
and for more than 80% of SE customers
it's their very first Apple Watch.
They love how SE delivers
the core Apple Watch experience
at a more affordable price.
SE is a fantastic way
to get started with Apple Watch.
And this year, it gets even better.
The new SE will be available
in Silver, Midnight, and Starlight–
all in 100% recycled aluminum.
And we've completely redesigned
the back case.
It's now made of nylon
composite materials
that match perfectly
with the three case finishes.
And there's a new production process
that reduces its carbon footprint
by over 80%.
Now, back to Deidre to tell you more.
Deidre: The second generation SE
continues to deliver the core benefits
of Apple Watch that users love,
like workout and activity tracking.
It's swim-proof.
It has high and low heart rate
notifications,
emergency SOS,
and fall detection.
SE also includes the same motion sensors
as Series 8
to support Crash Detection.
And with AirPods, you can listen
to your music anywhere.
The SE display is 30% larger
than that of Series 3.
And SE features the same
S8 System in Package that's in Series 8,
making it up to 20% faster than before.
SE continues to be the perfect Apple Watch
for Family Setup.
With Family Setup, you can use your iPhone
to pair watches for your children
who don't yet have their own iPhones.
Kids can make phone calls and send
messages to contacts that you specify,
connect to emergency services,
and share their location.
And with new features coming soon
like the Home app and home keys in Wallet,
Family Setup allows even more independence
for kids
and more peace of mind for parents.
SE offers everyone
the core features of Apple Watch,
and now includes the faster S8 SiP,
Crash Detection,
new case colors with matching back cases,
and all the new capabilities of watchOS 9,
all at a more affordable price
starting at $249 for GPS
and $299 for cellular.
You can order it today and it will
be available on September 16th.
We are so excited about the great
new features coming to Series 8
and Apple Watch SE, and can't wait
for people to start using them.
But we're not done yet.
Here's Jeff to tell you even more.
♪ ♪
Jeff: We've been working
on something completely new.
Over the years,
we've spoken to acclaimed explorers,
accomplished adventurers,
and elite athletes
who are drawn
to some of the most extreme environments–
like Ray Zahab, an extreme explorer
who's crossed some
of the harshest environments on foot,
including the length of the Sahara Desert,
and expeditions across Antarctica
and the Arctic,
and Nadia Aly–
an accomplished diver,
expedition leader
and renowned underwater photographer,
and Scott Jurek–one of the most dominant
ultra-marathon runners in history
and a seven-time winner
of the Western States 100-miler.
Inspired by their stories,
we set out to create an Apple Watch
designed specifically for exploration,
adventure, and endurance,
and it's extraordinary.
This has been years in the making,
and we can't wait to show it to you.
♪ ♪
Wanted for hazardous journey...
long months of complete darkness...
Bitter cold,
constant danger,
safe return... doubtful.
Honor and recognition
in case of success.
♪ ♪
Jeff: This is Apple Watch Ultra,
a completely new design reimagined
with extraordinary new capabilities
that expand the ways
you can use Apple Watch.
Every detail has been engineered
to create the most rugged
and capable Apple Watch ever.
It starts with the case,
made from aerospace grade titanium
that strikes the perfect balance
of weight,
durability, and corrosion resistance.
The titanium case extends up to surround
the flat sapphire front crystal,
protecting it from edge impacts
that can occur during extreme activities.
And at the center of the 49mm case
is our biggest, brightest display
ever in Apple Watch,
making it easier to read
in the harshest sunlight.
We also added a new button–
the Action button–
in high-contrast "international orange".
It's customizable and gives users quick
physical control for a range of functions.
The Digital Crown has a larger diameter
and coarser grooves,
and the side button stands proud
of the case,
both designed to be used
while wearing gloves.
And the audio system excels
when you're out in the elements.
We added a second speaker
for increased volume.
Three strategically placed microphones
and advanced software
help ensure voice clarity on calls,
even in windy conditions.
And for maximum connectivity
and communication,
cellular is built
into every Apple Watch Ultra.
Ultra has the biggest battery
of any Apple Watch yet.
It gets up to 36 hours
of battery life on a single charge.
And Apple Watch Ultra can even get
up to 60 hours of battery life
for a multi-day adventure
using a new battery optimization setting
coming later this fall.
And to complement
the rugged utility of the hardware,
we created our most technical face yet:
Wayfinder.
With a host of critical information,
it includes a compass in the dial
and can be customized for the mountain,
ocean, or trail.
And to optimize for evening conditions,
there's Night mode.
Just rotate the Crown,
and the UI turns red
for better visibility in the dark.
Apple Watch Ultra
is designed to push boundaries.
It's a versatile tool for anyone
who appreciates outdoor adventure,
water sports, and endurance training.
And for each of these,
we created a special band
as meticulously crafted
as the watch itself.
With explorers in mind,
we developed the Alpine Loop.
The titanium G-hook securely fastens
through the reinforced top loops.
The band is woven using
an innovative process
that integrates the two layers
without any stitching.
The Ocean Band is molded
in a high-performance elastomer
with a tubular geometry,
allowing it to stretch for a perfect fit,
even over a wetsuit.
The titanium buckle
and adjustable loops
secure the band
during high-speed water sports.
For endurance athletes,
we created the Trail Loop.
The lightweight textile
has increased elasticity
for a comfortable, snug fit.
It's our thinnest band yet,
with a convenient tab
for making quick adjustments.
Ultra is a totally new expression
of Apple Watch.
Whether you're an accomplished athlete
or explorer
or aspire to try exciting new activities,
we think you're gonna love it.
Here's Julz to tell you more.
♪ ♪
Julz Arney:
We set out to make Apple Watch Ultra
the best sport watch out there,
with features for every athlete.
GPS performance is critical
for serious runners and athletes
who want the most accurate metrics.
A typical GPS solution works well
most of the time,
but some environments are really tricky–
like when tall buildings
or dense trees block satellites,
making accurate GPS readings nearly
impossible when training and competing.
The famed Chicago Marathon
is a great example.
It's a notoriously challenging environment
for GPS
because a big portion is run
between skyscrapers.
So we designed a new, precision
dual-frequency GPS solution
that, in addition to L1,
also includes the latest frequency: L5,
plus new, custom positioning algorithms.
In dense urban conditions like this,
Apple Watch Ultra provides
the most accurate GPS
of any sport watch in the market.
We also brought some great workout updates
to watchOS 9
inspired by high-performance athletes,
with new metrics,
views, and experiences
like vertical oscillation,
heart rate zones, and custom workouts.
And now, with the addition
of the Action button on Apple Watch Ultra,
you can make the workout experience
more powerful and more precise.
Press the Action button
for the most accurate start
to your workout.
For triathletes and duathletes, the Action
button lets you instantly transition
from one leg of your race to the next.
And later this year,
we're enabling a new feature
which automatically detects
when you arrive at a running track,
ensuring the most accurate pace
and distance.
The Action button lets you
conveniently mark a segment
with a single press
for the ultimate track-running experience.
For endurance athletes, the bigger
battery makes a big difference.
Of course, you can easily complete
a marathon with battery life to spare.
Using the new low-power workout setting,
most athletes can do a 2.4-mile swim,
plus a 112-mile bike ride,
and then run a marathon
to complete a long-distance triathlon
with full precision GPS and heart rate.
But Ultra is so much more.
It's designed to help you explore
the most extreme and remote locations,
from freezing-cold mountains
at minutes 20° Celsius
to the blazing desert heat
at 55° Celsius,
or 130° Fahrenheit.
When navigating in the backcountry,
a compass is an essential tool.
So we completely redesigned
the Compass app
with new precision views
and added capabilities.
The orienteering view includes
Compass Waypoints to mark a position–
like the location of the trailhead
or your tent–
and they can be quickly added
using the Action button.
And if you get lost or disoriented,
Backtrack uses GPS data
to create a path of where you've been,
so you can easily retrace your steps.
And it turns on automatically in the
background when you go off the grid,
just in case.
Getting help when you need it is critical,
especially in the backcountry.
That's why Apple Watch Ultra has
a built-in 86 decibel siren
that you can activate
using the Action button.
It has a unique sound pattern
that alerts others to your location
up to 600 feet, or 180 meters, away.
Finally, Apple Watch Ultra
has been designed for water sports.
It can withstand the intense
dynamic forces of activities
like kitesurfing and wakeboarding,
and it can go deep below the waves
because we engineered it
to twice the water resistance, WR100.
Using its new built-in depth gauge,
Ultra automatically launches
a new Depth app when submerged
to show current depth, underwater time,
and water temperature.
We also want Ultra to be a great tool
for recreational scuba divers.
So it's been certified to EN 13319,
the internationally recognized standard
for dive computers and gauges.
And we're partnering
with Huish Outdoors
to create an exclusive app
that turns Apple Watch Ultra
into a capable dive computer
for recreational scuba diving
to the depth of 40 meters, or 130 feet.
To tell you more
about this incredible app,
here's Mike Huish, CEO of Huish Outdoors.
♪ ♪
Mike Huish: Our company is world-renowned
for powering every aspect
of the underwater experience.
And Oceanic has been a leading innovator
in scuba diving for over 50 years,
introducing
some of the very first dive computers.
We're thrilled to announce our new
Oceanic+ app for Apple Watch Ultra.
This is so exciting for anyone
interested in scuba diving
because now the same watch you wear
every day is also your dive computer.
We've designed Oceanic+
with all the key features
for recreational scuba divers
and free divers.
And it works seamlessly
with our iPhone app to plan your dives.
Our dive planner
calculates depth and time,
and integrates dive conditions like tides,
water temperature, and even up-to-date
information from the community,
like visibility and currents.
The best way to experience this
is on a real dive,
so let's get in the water.
Your dive metrics
are all simple and easy to read
on the large, bright display.
Our app runs
the Bühlmann decompression algorithm,
which constantly calculates
and monitors dive parameters.
So from the moment you start a dive,
all critical information
is just a glance away.
And unlike most dive computers,
which require you to perform
a complex sequence of button presses
to find the information you need,
our app uses simple gestures.
Rotate the Digital Crown
to access additional screens
or press the Action button
to set a compass heading.
Oceanic+ provides all of
the safety warnings that you would expect
from the most advanced
dive computers today,
like decompression limits,
excessive ascent rate,
and at the end of your dive,
safety stop guidance
all smartly color-coded
to help make complex information
easy to understand.
Right after the dive, your data–including
your GPS entry and exit location–
automatically syncs to your iPhone
and the cloud,
where you can see
a summary of your dive profile.
And in your logbook,
you can sort and search past dives,
and instantly share your adventures
with family and friends,
as well as the community.
We can't wait for you to try it out
later this fall.
The Oceanic+ app and Apple Watch Ultra
together create a powerful
and easy-to-use dive computer
that will inspire more people
to discover and explore
the underwater world.
Now back to Jeff.
So that's Apple Watch Ultra,
the most rugged
and capable Apple Watch ever.
With a 49mm titanium case,
precision dual-frequency GPS,
a customizable Action button,
long battery life,
a built-in depth gauge,
the biggest and brightest display–
up to 2000 nits–
and all the other great features
of Series 8,
it's designed
to help you run your longest race,
explore the back country,
and dive the world's oceans.
And Apple Watch Ultra,
as well as our entire watch lineup,
was designed with the environment
in mind–
from the use of recycled materials
to suppliers' use of clean energy
during manufacturing.
We're already carbon neutral
for our corporate operations,
and these efforts move us even closer
toward our goal
to become carbon neutral
for our entire product footprint by 2030.
All models of Apple Watch Ultra
will be $799.
You can order it today,
and it will be available starting
on September 23rd.
Here's another look
at the all-new Apple Watch Ultra.
♪ ♪
Every explorer has a packing list–
the essential tools
for heading out into the unknown.
We put as many of those tools
on your wrist as we could.
The result...
was the new Apple Watch Ultra.
Ultra's design pushes the boundaries
so you can do the same.
The rugged, yet lightweight, titanium case
extends
to protect the flat sapphire crystal
and can endure temperatures
that fall below zero
or climb 130° above it.
Into the unknown,
you'll want the battery to last for days.
That's why Ultra was built
with a larger battery
for multi-day use on a single charge.
You'll also need a map.
Or better yet, a dual-frequency GPS
with pinpoint accuracy.
The Compass has been redesigned
and now has waypoint marking
and Backtrack,
dropping points along your route
to keep you found
when the conditions leave you lost.
A turn of the Crown engages Night mode,
which removes retina-altering blue light
to ease the strain on your eyes
in the dark.
Beside the bigger, brighter screen
is its most versatile tool–
a customizable Action button.
One push lets you track race segments,
find a way out,
or start up a dive computer,
which is now strapped to your arm,
tracking everything from depth
to water temperature.
The micro-polished sapphire surface
and sealed case
result in an Apple Watch twice
as water resistant
as any Apple Watch to come before it.
And the audio system's three microphones
triangulate
so you can be heard
even in extreme weather.
Of course, none of this matters
if it falls off your wrist.
Which is why we've designed
three new bands–
Alpine, Trail, and Ocean–
for specific environments
and maximum comfort,
to endure long runs,
hard falls, and ripping currents.
Apple Watch Ultra is an essential tool
for essentially anything.
So what will your anything be?
♪ ♪
Jeff: And that's the Apple Watch lineup
for the fall,
with Apple Watch SE providing core
features at an even more affordable price,
Apple Watch Series 8 with Crash Detection,
and a temperature sensor
that enables new women's health features
in a design users love.
And finally, Apple Watch Ultra,
our most rugged, capable Apple Watch yet.
This is our best lineup ever,
and we can't wait
for users to experience them.
And now, back to Tim.
Tim:
I'm so excited about Apple Watch Ultra.
It's a great addition
to our fantastic Apple Watch lineup,
which just keeps getting
better and better.
Now, let's turn to AirPods.
Just like Apple Watch,
AirPods have become essential
for so many people.
Whether listening to music on a run
or watching your favorite movie,
AirPods work seamlessly
with Apple Watch and iPhone,
and they provide an incredible audio
and cinematic experience
with the simplicity and convenience
our users love.
In fact, AirPods are the best
and most popular headphones in the world,
and AirPods Pro
have become our most popular model,
featuring exceptional
Active Noise Cancellation
and unrivaled sound quality.
We're excited to introduce
the next generation of AirPods Pro,
our most advanced AirPods yet.
♪ ♪
To tell you more about the new
AirPods Pro, here's Mary-Ann.
♪ ♪
Mary-Ann Rau: At the heart of AirPods Pro
is our brand-new H2 chip,
providing an incredible upgrade
to performance from H1
with high bandwidth connectivity
to unlock breakthrough audio experiences
that only Apple silicon can deliver.
The exceptional sound quality of
AirPods Pro is also now transformed
with a new low distortion audio driver
and a custom amplifier to power it.
So whether you are dancing to J Balvin
or relaxing to SZA,
you will hear even more detail and clarity
across a wider range of sound frequencies.
These advances come together
in a magical way with Spatial Audio,
which takes the listening experience
to the next level
by making sound feel like you are on stage
with your favorite band
performing around you.
♪ ♪
We are taking this experience even further
with Personalized Spatial Audio.
With iOS 16, you can use
the TrueDepth camera on iPhone
to create a personal profile
for Spatial Audio,
because the way we all perceive sound
is unique
based on the size
and shape of our head and ears.
Personalized Spatial Audio will deliver
the most immersive listening experience
by precisely placing sounds in space
that are tuned just for you.
Another feature our users love
is Active Noise Cancellation,
which has been a game changer.
It reduces unwanted noise,
so you can better hear your favorite song
while on the go.
To create a next-generation experience,
H2 delivers advanced computational audio
previously unable to run
on a device of this size.
This, combined with optimizing
the placement of the acoustic vent
and microphones, now enables
up to double the amount of noise cancelled
over the original AirPods Pro,
delivering even greater focus when you
want to be immersed in the moment.
A great in-ear fit also helps
to provide passive noise reduction.
With a new, extra small ear tip,
even more people can enjoy
and comfortably wear AirPods Pro
throughout the day.
♪ ♪
When you want to be connected
to the world around you,
there's Transparency mode.
With the power of H2, we're taking
this experience to the next level
with Adaptive Transparency,
which dynamically reduces
the volume of harsh environmental noise
like heavy construction.
This is made possible because it
processes at 48,000 times per second
to react instantaneously to any
high-decibel noise you are exposed to.
♪ ♪
Next, let's talk about how you control
all of these great experiences.
The force sensor on AirPods Pro
brought the capability to play
or pause media
and answer calls
to keep you in the moment.
Today, we're taking that convenience
even further by introducing touch control,
which adds a capacitive sensing layer
so you can adjust volume
with a light swipe up or down.
The new AirPods Pro with H2
are not only more powerful,
they are far more power efficient,
delivering even longer battery life.
Now, you will have up to 6 hours
of listening time from a single charge,
which is a 33% increase
over the original AirPods Pro.
And with the charging case,
you will have up to 30 hours
of total listening time,
which is an increase of 6 hours.
The charging case is also core
to the convenience of AirPods Pro.
Today, Find My can help you
locate AirPods Pro
because each headphone
can individually play a sound.
With the new AirPods Pro,
if you happen to misplace
the charging case,
precision finding will help you
navigate directly to it
with U1 technology.
We have also added a speaker
to the bottom of the case
to help you find it
by playing louder tones.
And the speaker will indicate
pairing, low battery,
and when charging has started.
To make charging easier,
in addition to the Lightning cable,
you can now use your Apple Watch charger
as well as MagSafe
or other Qi-compatible chargers.
And with the addition of a lanyard
loop to the side of the case,
your AirPods Pro
will always be within reach.
These are the breakthrough
2nd generation AirPods Pro
powered by H2,
making our most popular AirPods
even better.
We've built AirPods Pro
with the environment in mind.
All magnets are made
with 100% recycled rare earth elements,
and all outer plastic wrap
from the packaging is removed.
And you can recycle all AirPods models.
Just bring them to your nearest store
or mail them in.
The new AirPods Pro
are available for $249,
and you can order on September 9th.
They're available on September 23rd
with free engraving, including Memoji.
We can't wait for you to experience
the future of AirPods.
Now, back to Tim.
♪ ♪
Tim: The new AirPods Pro and Apple Watch
models are incredible products.
They bring more capability
wherever you go.
And they're designed to work seamlessly
with the most essential product of all:
iPhone.
People love iPhone and it's
an important part of our daily lives.
We're constantly challenging ourselves
to raise the bar
to make it better and even more loved.
So let's take a look at the new iPhone.
♪ ♪
As you can see,
we're going big with iPhone 14,
and even bigger with iPhone 14 Plus.
Here's Kaiann to tell you all about it.
♪ ♪
Kaiann Drance:
The popular 6.1" size of iPhone 14
is joined by the new,
larger 6.7" size of iPhone 14 Plus.
With a larger display,
you can enjoy more content
when browsing the web.
You can see more text or larger text.
It looks great
with the incredible features of iOS 16,
like the new Lock Screen
and iCloud shared Photo Library.
You can even get more workout details
in the Fitness app
with the new Enhanced Workout Summary.
With a larger display,
you have more area
to watch your favorite show
or play your most intense game.
iPhone 14 also has an updated
internal design
that improves thermal performance, which
is great for staying in the action longer.
Both models have the gorgeous
Super Retina XDR display
with OLED technology that supports
1200 nits peak HDR brightness,
two million-to-one contrast ratio,
and Dolby Vision.
iPhone 14 is designed to last,
so you can count on it to be there
for you.
Both models have Ceramic Shield–
tougher than any smartphone glass–
aerospace grade aluminum,
and water and dust resistance.
They come in five gorgeous colors:
Midnight, Starlight,
a great new shade of blue,
a strikingly elegant purple,
and a truly eye-catching PRODUCT(RED).
Users depend on their iPhone
for so many things,
which is why iPhone 14 delivers
all-day battery life.
iPhone 14 Plus lasts even longer
throughout your day
with the best battery life ever
in an iPhone.
The larger display and best battery life
were previously only available
in our Pro Max models,
and now we're bringing it
to even more people.
Now, let's talk about performance.
iPhone 13 Pro introduced an amazing chip:
the A15 Bionic with a 5-core GPU.
It's a powerhouse that unlocks
extraordinary features
and delivers great power efficiency,
privacy, and security.
Now we are bringing this proven,
Pro-level performance to iPhone 14.
The 5-core GPU is 18% faster,
enabling even smoother graphics
in computationally heavy workloads
like complex gaming.
It has a powerful 6-core CPU
with two high-performance
and four efficiency cores,
and a 16-core Neural Engine
that pushes the limits
of machine learning.
Since its introduction,
A15 continues to be faster
than all the competition
at any price.
A15 is essential to iPhone 14.
And with a custom image signal processor,
A15 also powers innovative features
in the amazing new camera system.
Here's Caron to tell you more.
♪ ♪
Caron Thor: iPhone is always with you
and ready to quickly and effortlessly
capture your life's moments.
Last year, over three trillion photos
were taken with iPhone!
We develop unique,
state-of-the-art camera technology
while staying true
to the craft of photography.
Lighting is a fundamental part
of getting the best shot possible.
It plays such an important role
in capturing everyday memories
and jaw-dropping moments.
iPhone enables gorgeous photo capture
across the entire range of light–
from bright light,
where colors come alive,
to low light, like indoors,
to nighttime scenes.
And iPhone 14 again sets
the standard for photo
and video capture
regardless of where you are.
It has a new 12MP Main camera
with a larger sensor,
and larger pixels at 1.9 microns.
It has a larger f/1.5 aperture
and sensor-shift OIS
for a powerful Main camera upgrade
and takes stunning shots everywhere.
The faster aperture
allows better motion freezing,
showing off vibrant colors
that bring the scene to life
with great texture and detail.
It delivers a 49% improvement
in low light capture,
for more vibrant color and better results
in challenging lighting environments,
while making Night mode exposure
twice as fast.
And the Ultra Wide camera takes
incredible-looking photos and video,
which is great for wider shots
and unique perspectives.
The front camera enables
great-looking selfies,
high quality video during FaceTime,
and so much more.
iPhone 14 has a new TrueDepth camera.
It has a faster f/1.9 aperture
for a 38% improvement in low light capture
for photos and video.
The new front camera has autofocus
for the first time,
so it can focus clearly
at multiple distances.
Together with TrueDepth capabilities,
the front camera now has a hybrid system
that can focus faster, even in low light.
So you'll get better selfies, group shots
can be in focus from farther away,
and you'll be able to show off
great detail up close.
Low light environments can be
a unique challenge with photography.
We've made incredible progress
in capturing in low light over the years
with increasingly larger sensors
and faster apertures,
more advanced lenses–
all paired with intelligent software
and our powerful Apple silicon that result
in incredible capabilities for low light.
Deep Fusion is a great example.
It's a huge achievement
in computational photography
and uses the powerful Neural Engine
to combine multiple frames
into a single image.
This delivers extraordinary detail
and preserves even the subtlest textures
in these mid- to lower-light environments.
Now, we are taking
our image pipeline further
by applying Deep Fusion much earlier in
the process on uncompressed images.
This retains much more information
and detail,
and enables rendering of more colors
and brighter colors.
This new process unlocks our biggest step
forward yet for low light performance.
We call it Photonic Engine.
This is our enhanced image pipeline
that dramatically improves
low-light photos.
It goes beyond what hardware alone
can provide.
The best part is that it benefits
every camera.
When compared to iPhone 13,
it enables photo low light improvement
up to two times on the front camera,
two times on the Ultra Wide camera,
and two-and-a-half times
on the new Main camera.
You'll get photos
with much better detail and color,
helping you remember
the moment the way you lived it.
There's also a big improvement
to video this year.
iPhone leads the industry
with the highest quality video
and has great stabilization.
It now has a new,
even more advanced stabilization mode
that gives users a powerful tool
when capturing moments on the move.
This is Action mode.
It uses the full sensor with more overscan
and advanced roll correction
to make video look incredibly stable
when you're in middle of the action.
Simply toggle it on
for great-looking, smooth video,
without having to carry extra gear
like a gimbal.
It also supports and Dolby Vision HDR.
The new iPhone 14 camera system
is a huge upgrade,
enabling incredible-looking shots across
the entire range of shooting conditions.
Back to you, Kaiann.
♪ ♪
Kaiann: Now let's talk about connectivity.
iPhone has powerful capabilities
that help our users stay in touch
on the go.
This is especially true for 5G,
enabling super fast downloads,
better streaming,
and real-time connectivity.
And momentum for 5G is stronger than ever,
with over 250 carriers around the world
on 5G.
We've also made big improvements
to cellular technologies like eSIM,
making it even easier to connect.
An eSIM is a digital SIM that eliminates
the need for a physical SIM card.
With eSIM, you can quickly transfer
an existing cellular plan
or get a new cellular plan,
all digitally.
You can even store multiple eSIMs
on the same device,
meaning multiple cellular plans
and phone numbers.
And it's more secure.
Someone can't remove
the physical SIM card
if your iPhone is lost or stolen.
eSIM setup is easy.
In just a few simple steps,
users are ready to make calls,
send messages, and browse the web.
You can even do this
without a Wi-Fi connection.
Extensive planning and testing
with carriers
helped enable the iPhone eSIM experience.
This includes the US,
where eSIM support has skyrocketed,
thanks to AT&T,
T-Mobile, Verizon, and many more.
Now, for the first time, all US models
no longer have the SIM tray,
so you don't have to deal
with a physical SIM card anymore.
eSIM provides a simpler way
to activate and use iPhone.
Next, let's talk about some features
that make iPhone even more essential.
iPhone is there when you need it most.
That confidence is especially important
in moments where your safety is at risk.
With iPhone 14,
we have two critical new safety features.
It has Crash Detection–
the same feature you just heard about
on new Apple Watch models.
iPhone 14 has a new,
high dynamic range gyroscope
and a new dual-core accelerometer
that is able to detect up to 256 g's,
and it can automatically notify
emergency services
and emergency contacts
if you are in a severe car crash.
If you have both Apple Watch
and iPhone,
they seamlessly work together
to get you help efficiently.
Now here's Ashley to tell you
about another new safety service
coming to iPhone.
♪ ♪
Ashley Williams: Emergencies don't always
happen when it's convenient.
When you need help,
you need it wherever you are,
even if you don't have Wi-Fi
or cell service.
Now, your iPhone can connect you
with the help you need
when you're off the grid, like this.
Rescue 07, Command.
Please be advised,
a storm is headed your way
two miles southeast.
♪ ♪
Today, we are announcing
a groundbreaking new service for iPhone:
Emergency SOS via satellite.
While iPhone is designed
for a best-in-class cellular experience,
connecting to a satellite presents
an entirely new set of challenges.
Smartphones connect to cell towers
that are a few miles away.
Over the last several decades,
carriers have built
more and more cell towers
to improve the strength and speed
of their network service.
However, there are some places–
like winding back roads
and mountain ridges–
that cell towers don't reach.
Connectivity in these areas can
be provided by communication satellites.
Unlike stationary cell towers,
communication satellites
are hundreds of miles above the Earth,
and flying at over 15,000 miles per hour.
To connect to these satellites,
you need to be outside,
with a clear view of the sky.
And the bandwidth is so limited
that even sending a text message
is a technical challenge.
Typically, the only way to tap
into such a network
is with an expensive device
that uses a bulky external antenna.
We knew that approach
just wouldn't work for iPhone.
So we invented another way.
We designed and built custom components
and specific software
so that iPhone 14 antennas can connect
to satellites' unique frequencies.
That connection is only possible
when the phone is pointing
directly at a satellite.
However, satellites fly too high
to be seen by the human eye.
So we created a unique user experience
that shows you where to point your phone
to establish a connection,
and stay connected as the satellite moves.
This way, no bulky antenna is needed.
Once connected,
you need to send and receive
enough information to get emergency help.
Standard messaging protocols
are not designed
for a satellite's limited bandwidth.
So we created a custom
short text compression algorithm
to reduce the average size of messages
by a factor of three.
Thanks to this algorithm,
it can take less than 15 seconds
to send a message
if you have a clear view of the sky.
In other conditions,
such as light foliage,
it may take a few minutes.
And since each message can take some time,
we knew a standard back-and-forth
conversation
would take far too long
for an emergency situation.
We worked with emergency experts
to surface the questions
they're most likely to ask,
and we provided the most common responses
for you to choose from
with just a few taps.
With fewer messages to write and send,
you can get help quicker.
After your message
is relayed to a ground station,
it needs to reach
the right emergency service provider.
If that emergency service provider
accepts text messages,
we will connect you to them directly.
If they only accept voice calls,
we have set up Relay Centers,
staffed with highly-trained
emergency specialists
ready to get your text and call an
emergency service provider on your behalf.
It took years
to make this vision a reality
through game-changing hardware, software,
and infrastructure innovation.
This breakthrough service can also be used
in more casual, less dire circumstances.
So if you're out on a long hike,
you can use the Find My app
to share your location manually
via satellite.
This lets your loved ones know
where you are,
without you even sending a message.
Now, back to Kaiann.
Kaiann: We believe that this service
is such an essential part
of the iPhone experience
that we'll include it free for two years
with iPhone 14.
It launches in November,
and we're starting with the US and Canada.
Now, let's talk about the environment.
Since 2020, Apple's corporate operations
have been carbon neutral.
To reach our goal
of carbon neutral products by 2030,
we're looking at our environmental impact
across our supply chain
and the entire product lifecycle.
Over 200 of our suppliers have committed
to 100% renewable energy
for Apple production.
Our suppliers work to create less waste
and then reuse, recycle, or compost.
In fiscal year 2021 alone,
iPhone suppliers kept
over 250,000 metric tons of waste
from ending up in a landfill–
that's about one year's worth of waste
from 730,000 households.
We build our products to last.
This durability enabled millions of
trade-ins to find new owners in 2021.
And when it is time to recycle an iPhone,
that has environmental benefits too.
In fact, one metric ton of recovered
main logic boards and cameras
has the same amount of gold and copper
as over 2,000 metric tons of mined rock.
So don't throw away your old iPhone
or leave it sitting in a drawer–
bring it to your nearest store
or mail it in.
Together, we can reduce our impact
on the planet one step at a time.
And that's iPhone 14,
with powerful new cameras,
Photonic Engine,
Action mode,
A15 Bionic with a 5-core GPU,
Emergency SOS via satellite,
Crash Detection,
and the larger 6.7" display size
with the best battery life in an iPhone,
and so much more.
And later this fall, Apple Fitness+
will be available to all iPhone users,
even if they don't yet have
an Apple Watch.
iPhone 14 will start at just $799.
This is the same starting price
as last year's iPhone 13,
but with so much more capability
that sets a new standard for iPhone.
And iPhone 14 Plus starts at just $899,
bringing the larger 6.7" display
and the best battery life
to more people than ever.
We also have incredible offers
from Apple and our partners,
including up to $800 off in the US
when you trade in a qualifying iPhone.
iPhone 14 and iPhone 14 Plus
are available for pre-order
starting on September 9th.
iPhone 14 will be available
on September 16th,
and iPhone 14 Plus will be available
on October 7th.
We're thrilled about iPhone 14.
Let's take a look.
♪ ♪
There's simply nothing like iPhone 14.
Now, back to Tim.
♪ ♪
Tim: iPhone 14 and iPhone 14 Plus
have incredible new features
that will help our users
in meaningful ways.
And that's just the first part
of our iPhone story today.
With our Pro models we've introduced
some of our most important technologies
like Face ID, Super Retina display,
and our most advanced camera features
like sensor shift stabilization.
I'm excited to share
our most innovative Pro lineup yet.
♪ ♪
To tell you more
about the new iPhone 14 Pro, here's Joz.
♪ ♪
Greg "Joz" Joswiak:
Our Pro models feature beautiful
and strong surgical-grade stainless steel,
together with
our industry-leading durability features,
including Ceramic Shield
and water resistance.
They come in four gorgeous colors:
a new Space Black, Silver,
Gold, and this all new Deep Purple.
iPhone 14 Pro introduces
a new front design
that is sure to become iconic.
It starts with the new TrueDepth camera.
We redesigned all components
to fit into a smaller size,
using 30% less area.
We put the proximity sensor
behind the display for the first time.
With this change, we reconsidered
how you interact with your iPhone.
Throughout the day,
you experience different types
of alerts and notifications,
and these are often happening
while you're doing other things
on your iPhone.
So we developed a new experience
that's even better.
Here's Alan to tell you more.
Alan Dye: Our goal was to design a space
that clearly and consistently
surfaces alerts and background activity
in a rich and delightful way,
the result being an entirely new
and intuitive way to interact with iPhone,
one that truly blurs the line
between hardware and software.
We're calling it the Dynamic Island.
We've designed this new space
to be highly adaptive
so it can fluidly expand
into different shapes
using uniquely crafted animations
and transitions.
So now, when you receive an alert,
the Dynamic Island expands to notify you.
Our ambition is to clearly convey
the information
and present content and controls
without distracting from the app
you're in.
This works across the entire system
for things like
confirming your AirPods are connected,
muting, or starting a charge.
Each alert has its own personality,
and it's been designed
with its own unique character,
making it easy to identify at a glance,
like when you're using FaceID,
or tapping your iPhone
in transit locations.
The Dynamic Island also displays
ongoing background activity,
like when you're playing music.
When you swipe to go home,
the Music app gracefully morphs
into the Dynamic Island,
always staying active and visible.
And we've even designed it
to show the current album art.
It's also completely interactive.
You can tap and hold
to expose more options,
or tap to go back to the app.
So now, when you're on a call,
you have easy access to controls
without leaving the app you're using.
We've designed all these animations
to feel fluid, lively,
and highly responsive.
The Dynamic Island is always live
and active,
heightening the sense of vitality
by adapting in real time
to show you important information,
like your next direction from Maps.
And it's always visible
for ongoing activities,
like when you're using the timer.
We've designed Live Activities–
a new feature on the iOS 16 Lock Screen–
to work seamlessly
with the Dynamic Island,
including support for third-party apps,
so you can keep track of what's happening
from anywhere on iPhone,
like following a baseball game
without needing to leave the app you're in
or not missing the Lyft ride
while texting friends.
We've also created a robust design system
for developers,
so every alert looks and feels consistent,
no matter which app it comes from.
And when you have
more than one background activity,
the Dynamic Island playfully adapts,
bubbling out into two elements.
At Apple, we're focused on creating
extraordinary products,
products born from designing
hardware and software together,
so you don't know where one ends
and the other begins.
The Dynamic Island does this
in a truly magical way
and enables
an entirely new iPhone experience.
Back to Joz.
Joz: iPhone 14 Pro has a stunning
new display with Pro features.
This is the most advanced display
we have ever shipped.
iPhone 14 Pro and iPhone 14 Pro Max
come in two great sizes,
now with even thinner borders,
more active area,
and the Dynamic Island.
It is also brighter.
The new display provides
peak HDR brightness of 1600 nits,
bringing iPhone to the same level
as the Pro Display XDR.
So photos and HDR movies
are gonna look amazing–
including those you shoot on your iPhone.
And for those bright, sunny days,
iPhone can now push brightness even higher
for a peak of 2000 nits.
That's twice as bright as before,
and the highest peak brightness
of any smartphone.
The new Lock Screen in iOS 16
introduces more personalization
with widgets and Live Activities,
so this is the perfect time to introduce
Always-On display.
It's easy to see the time
and other important information
without raising your iPhone
or tapping the display.
This keeps essential information available
for the moments
where all you need is just a glance.
This is made possible
by a number of new technologies
that make the display
incredibly power efficient.
This display can operate
at a refresh rate as low as 1Hz
with a new low power mode,
and we further improved
our LTPO technology,
allowing the display to intelligently dim
the entire Lock Screen.
We also take advantage
of multiple coprocessors in our chip
to refresh the display
using minimal power,
so the time, widgets, and Live Activities
are always available.
And we use our photographic expertise
and powerful image segmentation
to dim wallpaper photos
while preserving skin tones,
so they continue to look great.
And you can keep an eye
on your Live Activities
without even touching your iPhone.
With all these incredible features,
the new Super Retina XDR
is the most advanced display
ever in a smartphone.
iPhone 14 Pro is powered
by our new A16 Bionic chip.
Our newest generation of Apple Silicon
powers every experience on iPhone.
With A16, we focused
on three important areas:
power efficiency, display, and camera.
Delivering incredible performance
with leading power efficiency
is a hallmark of Apple silicon.
A16 has nearly 16 billion transistors,
the most ever in an iPhone.
This is our first chip built
on a state-of-the-art 4-nanometer process,
enabling greater efficiency
while delivering even more performance.
In fact, A16 Bionic is the fastest chip
ever in a smartphone.
The competition is still working
to catch up with the performance of A13
which we first introduced with iPhone 11
three years ago.
The new 6-core CPU of A16
is generations ahead.
It's up to a whopping 40% faster
than the competition.
The CPU uses
our best-in-class fusion architecture
which delivers both leading performance
and leading efficiency.
Our two high-performance cores are faster
and use 20% lower power
compared to A15 Bionic.
And most daily tasks can be handled
by our high-efficiency cores.
At the same performance level,
these new efficiency cores
use one-third the power
of even the best of the efficiency cores
from the competition.
This allows iPhone to deliver
amazing battery life
while still being extremely responsive.
The new 16-core Neural Engine
is capable of nearly 17 trillion
operations per second,
which helps power iPhone's
advanced computational photography.
And the 5-core GPU
has 50% more memory bandwidth–
great for graphic-intensive games.
There's also
an entirely new display engine in A16.
This engine enables the 1Hz refresh rate,
Always-On capability,
higher peak brightness,
and the advanced anti-aliasing
that makes Dynamic Island animations
so incredibly smooth.
A16 also flexes every muscle
for the iPhone 14 Pro camera system.
It uses the CPU, GPU,
Neural Engine, and ISP
to perform up to 4 trillion operations
per photo.
And the image signal processor
was designed to support a new generation
of technology that provides
our most powerful Pro camera system ever.
This empowers every user
to take their best photos and videos–
from the casual user to the professional.
We're excited for iPhone 14 Pro to push
the boundaries for what's possible
and usher in a new era
for iPhone photography.
To tell you more, here's Vitor.
♪ ♪
Vitor Silva: iPhone 14 Pro introduces
a brand-new class of camera to iPhone:
a 48MP camera
with a quad-pixel sensor.
It is our largest sensor yet–
65% larger than the one on iPhone 13 Pro–
features our 2nd-generation
sensor-shift OIS,
and 100% focus pixels.
It also features a new 24mm focal length,
popular in photography
for its versatility
to shoot great landscapes,
group portraits, even single subjects.
The quad-pixel sensor enables
a new flexible approach
which adapts to the photo you're shooting.
For most photos,
we want to optimize for light capture.
So the new sensor groups every four pixels
into one large quad-pixel,
with four times more light.
This further improves light capture
while maintaining
the practical 12MP photo size.
Combined with the new Photonic Engine,
the new Main camera has up to
two times low-light improvement
for photos
compared to iPhone 13 Pro.
Let's take a look at what
the Main camera can do.
You can capture stunning photos
across all lighting conditions.
In this brighter shot,
the Main camera captured
the beautiful, rich color of her skin,
the detail of the fiber in the blanket,
and even a little of her joy.
For this photo, we locked exposure
on the woman's face.
As the vibrant feathers fell,
iPhone kept her in sharp focus
while creating a colorful texture
around her.
In this low-light example,
the Photonic Engine captures
incredible dynamic range,
from the warm glow of her skin,
the color of her eyes,
to every little crease, fold,
and texture in the garment.
The new sensor can optimize for detail
using each pixel individually,
providing more creative options
for shooting and editing in pro workflows.
With this approach we can go beyond
the three fixed lenses
of the Pro camera system,
adding a new 2x Telephoto option
for our users.
We use the middle 12 megapixels
of the new sensor
to deliver a full-resolution photo
and 4K video with optical quality.
This Telephoto has larger pixels
and a faster aperture
than any previous 2x Telephoto camera
on iPhone,
delivering incredible photos and videos.
And it has a familiar focal length
that is great for Portrait mode,
capturing stunning detail
with beautiful bokeh.
We're also using the new sensor
to optimize for detail in ProRAW.
ProRAW merges the best of our
intelligent computational photography
with the benefits of the RAW format,
giving Pro photographers
full creative control
over things like sharpening,
white balance,
and our advanced tone mapping
with more bit depth and dynamic range.
You can now shoot ProRAW
at 48MP resolution,
taking advantage of every pixel
in the Main camera
and unlocking incredible
editing flexibility.
The new sensor has
a different pixel pattern,
so we designed
a new machine learning model
that further enhances detail
and reduces noise.
This leverages the full power
of A16 Bionic
and results in an unprecedented level
of detail.
It's unbelievable how much we can zoom in,
like in this ethereal photo in Hawaii,
revealing each individual rock
on the beach,
and even dry branches from the trees.
With more pixels,
Pro photographers can reframe their photos
while still retaining great resolution.
We are able to keep the sharpness
and warmth of her eyes
as the focal point
of this high-resolution image.
This makes the 48MP Main camera
even more versatile,
further empowering the creativity
of the most Pro users.
iPhone 14 Pro also has
a new Ultra Wide camera,
with a larger sensor, more focus pixels
and–together with the Photonic Engine–
delivers a massive,
up to three times, improvement
in light capture for photos.
The new lens is sharper, with more detail,
so macro gets even better,
like this katydid bug
captured in a split second
to reveal more
than was visible to the naked eye.
The flash was completely redesigned
for a new adaptive behavior
based on the focal length of the photo.
With a new array of nine LEDs,
we control the pattern and intensity.
So it's up to twice as bright,
with up to three times better uniformity
compared to our previous generation.
And with the new Photonic Engine,
all cameras of iPhone 14 Pro
get a dramatic improvement
in low-light performance,
including up to two times better
for the Telephoto camera.
Together with higher-resolution photos
and more creative options,
this is our most powerful Pro camera
system ever.
Now, back to Joz.
♪ ♪
iPhone is already the choice
for filmmakers
because of its versatility
and cinema-grade video.
iPhone is the only smartphone
to shoot in ProRes,
and the only device in the world
with an end-to-end workflow
in Dolby Vision HDR.
iPhone 14 Pro also has our new Action mode
for shooting videos
with our best stabilization.
And Cinematic mode gets a great update,
now supporting up to 4K resolution
and 30 frames per second
for even more detail.
Pro filmmakers can also choose to record
in 4K at 24 frames per second–
the cinematic standard.
This is the biggest leap ever
for iPhone camera,
and we are continuing to raise the bar
for our industry-leading video quality.
People count on iPhone throughout the day.
So long battery life
is incredibly important to our users.
Even with industry-leading performance,
new Pro camera system,
and Always-On display,
iPhone 14 Pro delivers
all-day battery life.
So that's iPhone 14 Pro
and iPhone 14 Pro Max.
The Dynamic Island and Always-On display
introduce new ways to experience iPhone.
Powered by the A16 chip
with the new 48MP Main camera,
beautiful new finishes,
Crash Detection
and Emergency SOS via satellite,
this is the best iPhone
we've ever created.
Like iPhone 14,
our Pro models are designed
with features to reduce
their environmental impact.
They use recycled materials,
like gold and rare earth elements,
and meet our high standards
for energy efficiency.
Let's see iPhone 14 Pro in action.
♪ ♪
All right, lock it up.
Roll sound, please.
-Lock it up.
It is time to go beyond
what a smartphone can do...
All right, roll camera.
With a massive camera upgrade,
the A16 Bionic chip...
And action.
An entirely new category
of safety innovations,
and never-before-seen
display technology,
this is iPhone 14 Pro.
Cut!
The Always-On display
artfully dims your wallpaper
to create a unique,
low-powered Lock Screen,
making go-to information
available at just a glance.
And introducing
a remarkable innovation,
that is both hardware and software
and something in between:
the Dynamic Island.
An interactive place
that bubbles up alerts,
notifications, and activities,
fluidly transforming itself as needed.
♪ ♪
It's an entirely new way
to experience iPhone.
♪ ♪
Chin up a little bit.
You are now looking
at the most impressive
iPhone camera system yet.
In a major leap,
the iPhone Pro's Main camera
has a 48MP quad-pixel sensor.
It captures breathtaking detail,
depth, and color,
and now gives you the equivalent
of four pro lenses at the ready.
With every photo,
the quad-pixel sensor captures
four times more information
than ever before.
Then the A16 Bionic,
powering the new Photonic Engine,
analyzes and perfects every pixel
with up to 4 trillion operations
achieving an astonishing new level
of sharpness and detail.
♪ ♪
And now, Pro photographers
will now be able to capture
an uncompressed,
48MP ProRAW image,
giving you even more resolution
to rescale, retouch,
and reimagine your photos.
That was perfect.
Let's go again.
Building off iPhone's leap ahead in ProRes
and Dolby Vision video technology...
And action.
iPhone 14 Pro now includes
new Action mode,
allowing gimbal-like stabilization
for all your action scenes.
And Cinematic mode
will be even more powerful
for Pro filmmakers,
with 4K resolution
and 24 frames per second recording.
iPhone 14 Pro is capable of shots
that for most film cameras
are simply impossible.
You can rely on your iPhone every day,
and now it can even help
in emergency situations.
For the first time,
iPhone 14 Pro will be able
to communicate with satellites
with Emergency SOS...
Allowing you to deliver
critical information
to emergency services
in places where Wi-Fi
and cell service are unavailable.
And a feature we hope
you never have to use...
Commencing test.
♪ ♪
Crash Detection.
Using a high g-force accelerometer
gyroscope, sensors,
and machine learning algorithms,
iPhone 14 Pro can detect
when there has been a severe car crash
and automatically call
emergency services.
♪ ♪
Supercharged
by nearly 16 billion transistors,
the A16 Bionic is the fastest chip
in a smartphone
and powers the most impressive range
of Pro innovations yet.
911. What's your emergency?
The iPhone 14 Pro goes above and beyond,
redefining what a smartphone can be...
Again.
♪ ♪
Even with these groundbreaking features,
iPhone 14 Pro still starts at $999,
and iPhone 14 Pro Max at $1099,
with storage options up to 1TB.
We also have fantastic offers from Apple
and our carrier partners,
including up to $1000 off in the US
when you trade in a qualifying iPhone.
You can pre-order both models
on September 9th
and they will be available
on September 16th.
This is our most incredible
iPhone lineup ever,
including iPhone 13, iPhone 12,
and iPhone SE,
starting at just $429.
Now, back to Tim.
♪ ♪
Tim: Thank you, Joz,
and thanks to all of our presenters.
What an incredible day of announcements
about products
that are truly essential
to our daily lives.
Apple Watch Series 8, equipped
with best-in-class health features
and Crash Detection
continue to make Apple Watch
the gold standard for smart watches.
The new Apple Watch SE brings
all the core features of Apple Watch
to even more users.
And the remarkable Apple Watch Ultra–
an entirely new category of Apple Watch
with its rugged design,
long battery life,
and breakthrough technologies–
is the most capable watch ever.
The new AirPods Pro deliver
an even better audio experience,
including improved
Active Noise Cancellation,
Personalized Spatial Audio,
and longer battery life.
iPhone 14 and iPhone 14 Plus,
with a larger 6.7" display,
are full of innovations,
including a fantastic new camera system
and a new front camera with auto-focus.
iPhone 14 Pro
and iPhone 14 Pro Max:
the best iPhones we've ever created,
with a new way to experience iPhone,
as well as the industry-leading
A16 Bionic,
Always-On display, and powerful
new camera technologies.
And we're continuing to build
more safety features into iPhone
with Crash Detection
and, for the first time,
the ability to communicate via satellite,
delivering the Emergency SOS service.
These incredible products each offer
so many great capabilities
and work seamlessly together
in a way that only Apple can deliver.
Making products that are so personal
and indispensable
is what drives us to continue innovating,
improving on what are already
best-in-class experiences.
I'm proud of all the teams
and hard work
that went into making today's
announcements possible.
And I'm excited to see all of the amazing
things you'll do with these new products.
Thank you for joining us.
Have a great day.
♪ ♪
.