（实验性）挖空六级高频词汇
Odin, the king of Asgard,
was plagued by nightmares.
Three fearsome _______ haunted his dreams:
a massive, writhing shadow;
a shambling, rotting corpse;
and _____ of all,
a monstrous beast with a ______ bite.
Night after night, the creatures
besieged the king.
And although their true forms
were _______ to him,
he could tell they were _______
to Asgard’s most __________ problem:
Loki.
Despite having _______ down
with his wife and sons,
Loki had been ________ off to visit
the giantess Angrboda.
And when the king learned this affair
had ________ three children,
he was filled with unease.
Odin summoned Thor and Tyr,
two of his bravest warriors,
to travel to Jotunheim to _______
Loki’s ______ children.
Upon arriving at Angrboda’s home,
the pair were immediately accosted
by Loki's first child,
a serpent named J?rmungandr.
The God of Thunder ______
the snake’s venom
and swiftly _____ him to a pine tree.
The second child, Hel, appeared as
a glowing young woman from the right
and a moldering corpse from the left.
Her flesh flaked onto the ______
as she silently _________ to her captors.
Finally, the third child _____ at Tyr.
The small wolf was ______ but harmless.
Tyr playfully cuffed its claws
and stowed the cub in his pocket.
Back in Asgard, the warriors
presented their prisoners
and _______ recognition
seized Odin's heart.
Though these three were meager reflections
of his dark dreams,
the king was __________ to dispose
of them before his _______ came true.
First, he banished J?rmungandr
to the sea at the edge of the world.
Then he sent Hel deep below the earth
to join her ______ corpses.
But the wolf, named Fenrir,
presented a challenge.
He’d already grown strong
enough to ________ the gods,
so Odin took a more patient approach.
For months, he supervised the creature,
watching Fenrir grow
from a cub to a wolf to a beast
who spoke with the voice of a God.
Tyr visited __________ and found Fenrir
to be strong and clever.
But as their ____ deepened,
Odin's fear only grew.
One day, Odin forged his heaviest chains
and ______ them to Fenrir
with a challenge.
He would ____ the wolf
to test his growing strength.
Fenrir _______ accepted the _________
and splintered the _____ like old wood.
Odin returned to the forge, crafting
shackles that no man could lift alone.
These ______ ______ gave Fenrir pause.
But with an encouraging wink from Tyr,
he accepted the challenge.
The beast ________ for a moment
and then _________ his restraints
into a thousand pieces.
Desperate, Odin ______ help
from the most _______ ______ of all:
the Dwarves.
Rather than metal, they ______
the ______ ingredients;
from feline _________ and fish breath
to the sinews of mountains
and ______ bears.
With these, the Dwarves _______ Gleipnir,
an unbreakable _____ in the guise
of fine thread.
When Odin __________ Fenrir a third time,
the wolf laughed.
But as he examined the thread
more closely,
Fenrir sensed Odin’s trickery
and began to feel some fear himself.
Fenrir ______ a deal.
He would accept the challenge,
but only if a god kept their hand
in his mouth throughout.
With a heavy heart, Tyr volunteered.
The gods _____ the wolf and as he strained
Gleipnir only grew tighter.
Fenrir felt the _____ of betrayal—
not only from Odin,
but from his _________ friend.
With a howl of fury,
he ___ through Tyr’s wrist
and _____ to _______ Odin
for ________ him.
Watching his _________ come to life,
Odin thrust Tyr’s blade
between Fenrir jaws,
releasing a torrent of saliva
that became a _______ river.
While the beast was not dead,
he was bound,
and Odin __________ his _______ over fate.
But in truth, his actions had
only ______ his doom.
Beneath the waves,
J?rmungandr grew to encircle the world.
Hel ____ to rule the dead
as queen of the Underworld.
And every day, Fenrir ________
a little more against his chains,
inching ever closer to his bloody revenge.