（实验性）挖空六级高频词汇
Imagine that you’ve been unemployed
and _______ work for months.
Government _______ ________ have helped
you cover rent, utilities, and food,
but you're ______ getting by.
Finally, you hear back
about a job application.
You receive your first paycheck in months,
and things seem to be turning around.
But there’s a catch.
Your new job pays just enough to
disqualify you from the _______ programs,
and not enough
to cover the same costs.
To make things worse, you have
to pay for ______________ to work,
and _________ while you’re at the office.
Somehow, you have less money now
than when you were unemployed.
Economists call this demoralizing
situation the _______ trap—
one of the many _________ _______ traps
affecting ________ of people
around the world.
Poverty _____ are ________
and _____________ circumstances
that _________ themselves,
perpetuating _______ for generations.
Some _______ _____ are ____
to an individual’s circumstances,
like a ____ of ______ to healthy food
or education.
Others can ______ ______ nations,
such as ______ of _______ government
or _______ change.
But the _____ _____ of _______ traps
in particular
is that they ____ from the very policies
designed to ______ poverty.
Most _________ __________ _______ employed
some strategies
to help people in _______
meet basic needs.
Before the 20th century,
religious groups and _______ charities
often led such initiatives.
Today, these are called _______ programs,
and they usually take the form
of government-provided subsidies
for housing, food, energy, and healthcare.
Typically, these programs
are means-tested,
meaning that only people who fall
below a certain ______ level
are ________ for benefits.
This policy is ________ to ______ ___
goes to those who need it most.
But it also means people lose access
as soon as they ____ more
than the qualification threshold,
regardless of whether or not they're
financially ______ enough to stay there.
This _______ _____ is _______ to both
those in _______ and those outside of it.
Mainstream ________ models ______ people
are ________ actors
who weigh the cost and ________
of their options
and choose the most advantageous
path forward.
If those in _______ know they'll gain
no net _______ from working,
they're incentivized to remain
in government assistance.
Of course, people work for many reasons,
including ________ norms
and ________ values.
But ______ is a _____ incentive
to ________ employment.
And when less people take on new jobs,
the _______ slows down,
keeping people in poverty
and ___________ pushing people
on the cusp of _______ over the edge.
Some have suggested this ________ loop
could be removed
by ___________ government __________
programs altogether.
But most agree the ________
is neither _________ nor humane.
So how can we ________ ________ in a way
that doesn't penalize people for working?
Many countries have tried different
ways to circumvent this problem.
Some allow people to continue receiving
benefits for a given period
after _______ a job,
while others _____ out benefits
gradually as ______ increases.
These policies still ______ some
financial _________ to work,
but the risk of a _______ ____ is lower.
Other governments _______ ________ like
education, childcare, or _______ care
equally across all their citizens.
One ________ ________ takes this idea
of _________ ________ even further.
A _________ basic ______ would _______
a fixed _______ to all members of society,
regardless of wealth or __________ status.
This is the only known policy that could
entirely ______ _______ traps,
since any ______ _____ would __________
the _______ rather than _______ it.
In fact, by creating a ______ ______ floor
below which no one can fall,
basic ______ might _______ people from
falling into _______ in the first place.
Numerous __________ and thinkers
have __________ this idea
since the 18th century.
But for now, _________ basic ______
remains largely hypothetical.
Although it's been tried in some
places on a _______ scale,
these _____ experiments don’t tell us
much about how the policy
would play out across an ______ nation—
or a planet.
Whatever ________ governments pursue,
solving the _______ ____ requires
respecting people’s ______ and autonomy.
Only by empowering ___________
to create _________ change
in their lives and communities
can we begin to break the _____
of poverty.