（实验性）挖空六级高频词汇
Peering into the eyes
of _________ animals,
you’ll see some extraordinarily
shaped pupils.
But why?
It turns out that _____ shape
is a ________ indicator
of what ____ an animal plays
in its ecosystem.
Pupils mark the hollow opening
in the iris,
the eye’s ____ of pigmented muscle.
They’re the portholes through which
light enters the eye,
where it then _______ the retina
and _________ light-sensitive cells,
setting the _______ of ______ in motion.
Pupils are black because most of the
light that enters them is absorbed.
Their size changes in response
to brightness,
as well as certain drugs
and _________ and ______ states—
but their basic form ______ greatly
among species.
House cats, for one, are twilight _______
with vertically elongated pupils.
In the dark, these structures
expand dramatically,
taking in the _________ light.
When it’s bright, they ______ into slits.
In fact, cat ______ are so ________ that
their _______ area is 135 times greater
than their _______ area—
whereas our ______ only shrink
and ______ 15-fold.
And because of how the slit _____
takes in light,
it creates sharp, vertical contours.
When the cat’s brain _________
the _______ from each eye,
the small but _____ differences
between them
help the cat _____
the _______ ________ of its target.
In fact, many other ambush _______ also
have vertically elongated pupils—
but mainly those whose eyes are
located closer to the ground.
This may be because these ______ are
especially useful in __________ objects
at the ________ short distances
these animals ____ to hunt.
The world looks very _________ from behind
the horizontally elongated pupils
of many grazing and ________ animals,
like goats.
These pupils, situated
on either side of the head,
let horizontal _____ of light in that
give the goat a near-360-degree view
and _______ it with sharp,
horizontal images.
This helps goats ______ any
disruption to the horizon—
alerting them to _________ predators—
while still ________ them to see ahead
and ______ _________
as they make their escape.
In fact, goats always keep their pupils
aligned with the horizon,
rotating their eyeballs in their sockets
as they move their heads up and down.
Meanwhile, nocturnal geckos have pupils
that ______ into slits
studded with pinholes
in higher light conditions.
Each pinhole ________ a separate, sharp
image onto the geckos retina.
Scientists think that comparing
these _________ inputs
might help the gecko _____ distance
without having to move.
And while they might have fooled you,
mantises and other _______ and crustaceans
have “pseudopupils.”
These aren’t _______ structures;
they’re _______ illusions
experienced by the observer.
Mantises have ________ eyes composed
of thousands of light-sensing units.
When some are _____ at you,
they appear black
because they’re _________ most wavelengths
of ________ light—
but there’s no ______ opening.
So, why do we have round pupils?
Elongated ______ help _______ certain
dimensions of an animal's vision.
But scientists think that, for animals
like us with circular pupils,
this is a lower priority.
Instead of seeing some ________
of a _____ in _______ focus,
we see a larger picture
in ________ detail,
which _______ more _______ skills
of observation.
This may be especially helpful
for foragers looking for food,
hunters eyeballing and chasing
their prey,
and ______ animals ___________
other faces.
As we ____ at _________ pupils,
patterns emerge.
And yet there are exceptions.
For example, Pallas’s cats and mongooses
are both small ambush predators,
but the Pallas’s cat has round pupils
and mongooses have goat-like pupils.
And we’ve only explored
a few _____ shapes.
Other animals have crescent-
or heart-shaped pupils.
And the cuttlefish has perhaps
some of the most bizarre:
their ______ are circular in the dark,
but W-shaped in the light.
So, what’s going on here?
Well, wouldn’t we all like to know?