（实验性）挖空六级高频词汇
As the sun sets on a plantation
in Jamaica,
children _____ to Mr. Kwaku for a story.
They all know he’s full of _____
from Ghana, the land of their ancestors.
But what they don’t know, Kwaku winks,
is how their ancestors got those stories
in the first place.
Long ago, all stories ________ to Nyame,
the all-seeing Sky God.
People on Earth were _____
and knew nothing about their history.
But one ________ decided
enough was enough.
Anansi, the tricky, shapeshifting spider,
resolved to bring the stories
down to Earth.
He ____ a web that _________
into the clouds
and climbed up to ________ the Sky God.
Crouching at Nyame’s feet,
Anansi _______ at the top of his lungs
that he had come to take _________
of the world’s stories.
Looking down from his golden stool,
Nyame hooted with ________
at the spider’s absurd request.
Nyame told Anansi that he could have
all the stories he wished—
but only if he could complete
an __________ task.
If Anansi brought him
Osebo the Leopard, Onini the Python,
Mmoboro the Hornet,
and Mmoatia the Forest Spirit,
then he could take the stories.
Anansi ______ accepted.
Nyame didn’t see him grinning
as he scuttled away.
Back on Earth, Anansi _______
his magic bag and set to work.
Anansi found Onini the Python
bathing in the sun.
Anansi scoffed that Onini
couldn’t be the longest animal,
saying he looked no longer
than a _____ of bamboo cane.
Enraged, Onini _________ himself across
the bamboo to _____ his lengthiness.
Anansi quickly _____ him tight-tight
to each end and placed him in his bag.
Next, Anansi ___ a _____ pit
in the middle of the path
Osebo the Leopard usually prowled,
and covered it with banana leaves.
Sure enough, ______ Osebo soon fell in.
Anansi scolded Osebo for his carelessness,
but offered to ______ him.
As he helped Osebo out of the pit,
Anansi swiftly jabbed him with his knife.
Osebo fell back to the ground
where Anansi wound him up
tight-tight in ______ thread.
Then, Anansi heard Mmoboro
and his hornets buzzing.
He __________ __________ them.
This would be tricky— their ______
could make someone swell up and die—
but Anansi knew they hated rain.
He filled his mouth with water
and ____ it at the swarm.
As they panicked, Anansi _____ the hornets
to _______ in his gourd,
where they found themselves trapped.
Anansi had one more task:
to _______ Mmoatia
the elusive and mischievous Forest Spirit.
She usually hid herself deep in the woods,
but Anansi knew she was lonely.
So, he made a little doll covered in sap
and left it in her path.
When she came upon it,
Mmoatia spoke to the doll
but became enraged when it didn’t answer.
She hit the disrespectful doll
and her small fists _____
to its ______ surface.
Anansi _______ Mmoatia up tight-tight
and _______ her into his bag
along with the other creatures.
Triumphantly, he climbed his web
back into the clouds.
When the Sky God saw that Anansi
had completed the __________ task,
he was amazed.
Nyame told Anansi
that he had ______ the world’s stories.
Dancing for joy, Anansi ________ them up,
stuffed the stories into his bag,
and descended to Earth.
There, he _________ the stories
throughout the world for people to share.
And they did, Kwaku tells the children.
Generations have continued
telling and reimagining Anansi’s stories
even after being stolen from Africa
and enslaved.
Anansi may be small, but “cunning’s
better than strong,” Kwaku says,
and tells the children to take Anansi’s
stories with them wherever they go.
Looking at his audience, Kwaku knows
that Anansi will persist
as a ______ of _______________
and __________ in the face of oppression,
and a testament to the ________ power
of storytelling.